<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cms on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/cms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cms on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/cms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual Composer Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/visual-composer-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/visual-composer-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visual Composer is a drag-and-drop WordPress website builder that makes it easy for anyone to create beautiful layouts without touching any code. It&amp;rsquo;s perfect for people who want to design their own websites and don&amp;rsquo;t have the time, knowledge, or patience to learn how to use complicated website building tools. You can customize your site with Visual Composer in a few clicks or by choosing from one of its prebuilt templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Wordpress Plugins You Probably Didn&#39;t Know About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/useful-wordpress-plugins-you-probably-didnt-know-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/useful-wordpress-plugins-you-probably-didnt-know-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wordpress is one of the most popular, efficient ways to develop a fully-functional, beautiful website. Wordpress add-on products and services are also highly decentralized. Developers are constantly producing plugins, or stand-alone software that can be easily incorporated into a Wordpress website and provide it with a specific functionality. Adding new plugins to your Wordpress website can significantly increase your site&amp;rsquo;s value to visitors and help you market your brand. Below are 12 new and exciting Wordpress plugins you didn&amp;rsquo;t know about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themeisle Hestia Pro review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themeisle-hestia-pro-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themeisle-hestia-pro-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hestia Pro is a powerful material design based WP template with which you can launch websites of various types without writing a single line of code. It is one of the best multi-purpose WordPress themes. According to Themeisle, the developer of Hesita Pro, HP is idle for business, blog, e-commerce sites based on the WordPress content management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the Hestia Pro theme SEO friendly and fast? Should you replace your current theme with it? Here&amp;rsquo;s my review of this premium WP template:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revive Old Post WordPress plugin review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/revive-old-post-wordpress-plugin-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/revive-old-post-wordpress-plugin-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike search engines that rank pages on the basis of various factors, Social networking portals display posts in groups and on pages in first-in-last-out order. If the page is old, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to scroll down the group until you find it. If the title of the post is interesting, people will share the post on their profiles or in groups they&amp;rsquo;ve joined. Such pages are called viral posts. They have the potential of bringing a large amount of traffic to a website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress News Pro theme review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-news-pro-theme-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-news-pro-theme-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;News Pro is one of the flagship StudioPress themes. It is also one of the most widely used WP magazine templates. Powered by the HTML5 markup, StudioPress NP is based on minimal flat responsive design. It is ideal for magazine sites that cover a variety of topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NP is built on Genesis Framework which powers 100K+ sites. Is the News Pro theme suitable for your site? Is it easy to use and SEO friendly? Let&amp;rsquo;s find it out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Options for Hosting Multiple Drupal Sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/infrastructure-options-for-hosting-multiple-drupal-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/infrastructure-options-for-hosting-multiple-drupal-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A project I was recently working on had in place a cloud-based infrastructure that was designed to support a single installation of the Drupal CMS running in Amazon Web Services (AWS). This infrastructure included an auto-scaling setup with load balancers hosting a &amp;lsquo;cache&amp;rsquo; layer and an &amp;lsquo;application&amp;rsquo; layer that hosted the Drupal CMS. On the backend tier, an AWS Relational Database Service (RDS) provided the MySQL database needed for the application. There were other components of the infrastructure such as our shared services for continuous integration, monitoring and development tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academy Pro review: Great theme for educational and membership sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/academy-pro-review-great-theme-for-educational-and-membership-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/academy-pro-review-great-theme-for-educational-and-membership-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academy Pro is a premium WordPress theme developed by StudioPress. It has a brilliant design and many features. It is ideal for membership and educational websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academy Pro is powered by Genesis framework and it looks great on all types of computing devices. Here&amp;rsquo;s my review of this theme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academy-pro-review&#34;&gt;Academy Pro review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other StudioPress templates, AP is easy to install. Once you download the theme, use the WordPress Content Management System&amp;rsquo;s theme installer tool to get started with Academy Pro. Here are the various features of this theme:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things you should do after Installing WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/things-you-should-do-after-installing-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/things-you-should-do-after-installing-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is the most powerful content management system. According to analytics tools, WP powers 30% of websites running on the internet. WP is a popular and user-friendly CMS. It is written in PHP and uses MySQL to save data. Unlike scripting languages such as JAVA EE, ASP, PHP is easy to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shared hosting companies offer a 1-click WP installer tool. If you use this tool, you can launch a new website within few minutes. Configuring DNS server and the web server isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. To make sure that your new website is found by search engines and internet users, you must do the below things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Velocity Minify: Plugin that combines CSS and JS files without breaking the site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fast-velocity-minify-plugin-that-combines-css-and-js-files-without-breaking-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fast-velocity-minify-plugin-that-combines-css-and-js-files-without-breaking-the-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress repository is the home to 100s of minification plugins. Some plugins may break the site and some will do their job. Fast Velocity Minify is a free plugin that improves the loading speed of your site. The plugin has 20000 active users and it is easy to use. It is a great alternative to Autoptimize and WP Better Minify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVM supports Nginx gzip_static module and it is compatible with 100s of popular plugins. You can use it with other popular caching plugins i.e. WP Rocket, Super Cache, W3TC, WP Fastest Cache, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to exclude pages or posts from sitemap in WordPress?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-exclude-pages-or-posts-from-sitemap-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-exclude-pages-or-posts-from-sitemap-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wordpress logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-to-exclude-pages-or-posts-from-sitemap-in-wordpress/images/wordpress-logo.jpg&#34;&gt;A blogger or webmaster may add the robots meta noindex or nofollow tag to irrelevant or thin pages or posts. When you add the attribute to pages, search engines will remove the pages from their index. If you don&amp;rsquo;t remove the no-indexed posts from the sitemap, search engines might crawl the posts even though they&amp;rsquo;re not relevant to your site. If you want Googlebot or Bingbot to crawl only the important pages on your site, follow the below two steps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monstroid2 review: A great multipurpose WordPress bootstrap theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/monstroid2-review-a-great-multipurpose-wordpress-bootstrap-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/monstroid2-review-a-great-multipurpose-wordpress-bootstrap-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monstroid2 is a premium multipurpose WordPress theme powered by Twitter Bootstrap and Cherry Framework, a secure modular open-source framework for developing themes and plugins. It is the successor to the Monstroid theme which had become a talk of the town within few months of its launch. Monstroid2 has new and powerful features. It also includes a powerful live theme customizer and page builder tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme has been developed by a firm called Jetimpex. Like StudioPress, Elegant Themes, Jetimpex is one of the top WP development companies. JI has launched 100+ templates for WordPress, Joomla, Prestashop on TemplateMonster, a marketplace for webmasters and developers. It has also published several plain HTML templates. Monstroid is Jetimpex&amp;rsquo;s best-selling WP theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to test WordPress plugins online without installing?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-test-wordpress-plugins-online-without-installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-test-wordpress-plugins-online-without-installing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your site is getting good traffic, and if a new version of the plugin you&amp;rsquo;re using has been launched, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the following two questions in the mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the plugin break your site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the plugin worth installing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the plugins are thoroughly tested before launch, it may have some bugs. If you install the update, your site may crash or it may add HTML code which may affect your site&amp;rsquo;s ranking in Google or Bing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to disable or noindex WordPress attachment pages?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-disable-or-noindex-wordpress-attachment-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-disable-or-noindex-wordpress-attachment-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attachment page is the built-in feature of WordPress. When these pages are not handled correctly by the website owner, Google and other search engines will index them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress attachments are thin pages that don&amp;rsquo;t add any value to a blog. These pages should be used only on personal or photography blogs wherein you want the visitors to comment on the pictures, videos, and other media files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide an option to turn off or disable these pages. However, you can use third-party plugins to manage them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned using Drupal’s Domain Access Module</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons-learned-using-drupals-domain-access-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons-learned-using-drupals-domain-access-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months my team has been developing microsites to accompany our main website. The requirements for these sites included having their own domain, theme and separate content. After reviewing options in Drupal 7, I decided the best approach given our situation was to use the Domain Access Module. The Domain Access Module provides a very solid and powerful framework for developing additional sites within your existing Drupal CMS, but it can also be somewhat complicated to setup for any given use case. I have documented some of the lessons learned over the last few months as we implemented Domain Access in our own project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InstaShow Instagram feed plugin review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/instashow-instagram-feed-plugin-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/instashow-instagram-feed-plugin-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InstaShow is a premium WordPress plugin that allows you to integrate the Instagram feed on your website. It has registered 6000+ sales on the ThemeForest marketplace. It is a highly customizable plugin that has a rating of 4.87/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;InstaShow is cheap and it provides amazing features. If you own a photography, product review website or a food blog, you can get more Instagram followers by installing this plugin. The Instagram widget provided by InstaShow is a great alternative to a gallery or featured image widget because it saves server resources. Instead of uploading pictures on your server, you can share your images on Instagram and configure InstaShow to display the pictures in a nice interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Best free WordPress migration plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-4-best-free-wordpress-migration-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-4-best-free-wordpress-migration-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I have a technical background, I was not comfortable in moving my sites during my initial days of online career. At that time, 2 of my biggest worries were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorrect site configuration can lead to tons of soft 404 or 404 errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If DNS isn&amp;rsquo;t configured correctly, search bots and visitors would fail to access my sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my online journey in May 2013. I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my hosting platform and moved my websites several times in the last four years without losing website traffic. Right now, my websites are hosted on an unmanaged Linode cloud server. Before switching to Linode, I used Digital Ocean. To move my sites, I follow the below steps:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avada Theme review: Is it the best premium WordPress theme?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/avada-theme-review-is-it-the-best-premium-wordpress-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/avada-theme-review-is-it-the-best-premium-wordpress-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avada is a top-rated premium WP theme, which you can download from ThemeForest marketplace. There are plenty of free themes that haven&amp;rsquo;t surpassed 1000 downloads. Interestingly, Avada has 300K+ users. It is not only best-selling WordPress theme on the ThemeForest market place but also the most popular premium WP template. Themeforest is a marketplace where developers across from various parts of the world publish their products. As the ratings and reviews are not in control of theme and plugin developers, you can consider ThemeForest as a transparent marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulk move noindexed posts from All in One SEO to Yoast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bulk-move-noindexed-posts-from-all-in-one-seo-to-yoast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bulk-move-noindexed-posts-from-all-in-one-seo-to-yoast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Yoast SEO plugin includes an option to import meta description and title tags from other popular plugins. While using other plugins, you may have noindexed or nofollowed some or several posts. There are a couple of plugins that enable you to move settings from AIOSEO to Yoast. Unfortunately, none of the plugins provide an option to bulk move noindex posts. People noindex posts to recover from Google quality updates or prevent penalty during an algorithm update.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Best WordPress directory theme (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-5-best-wordpress-directory-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-5-best-wordpress-directory-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A directory site has a massive listing of businesses. If a site is successful, it will have a listing of 1000+ business. A small site may have fewer listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEO plays a key role in deciding the fate of a directory site. A well-optimized website will rank high in search engines. A good example of this is Yelp, a large restaurant directory site that ranks at number 1 position in Google SERPs for several 1000 keywords. We must not forget that Yelp has 100s of employees working 24 x 7.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best way to Auto Tag WordPress posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-auto-tag-wordpress-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-auto-tag-wordpress-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress tags are important, no matter how small or large a site is. Tags allow users to group posts. They make website navigation easier. They allow search engines to discover and index new posts quickly. WordPress Related posts plugins use tags to calculate post relevancy and display related articles below blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human beings make mistakes. Sometimes, a webmaster may delete an important tag unintentionally. Once a tag is removed, the structure of the related post on your site may change. If you have a small blog with 10 to 20 posts, readding tags manually shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. If you own a large site, readding tags to posts is an annoying task. The best way to add tags to blog posts is to use Automatic Post Tagger WordPress plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Twitter feed plugin and Widgets for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-twitter-feed-plugin-and-widgets-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-twitter-feed-plugin-and-widgets-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular microblogging site. Twitter has 200+ million users thereby making it one of the best platforms to promote your product. Like Facebook, this site enables webmasters and developers to integrate user activity feed on third-party websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Twitter feed aka Embedded Timelines widget displays a list of your recent tweets and retweets from users who have enjoyed reading your post, watching your video, or seeing the picture you&amp;rsquo;ve shared. The feed gets updated in real-time and it increases user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Best WordPress restaurant theme (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-10-best-wordpress-restaurant-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-10-best-wordpress-restaurant-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of free website builder tools with which you can launch a restaurant site within an hour. The site builders have limited features. Furthermore, they don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to add maps, reservation forms, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about your restaurant business, you must use the WordPress CMS. WP allows you to create an incredibly powerful restaurant website within 50 to 55 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To launch your restaurant site, you must download one of below top WordPress restaurant themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress Foodie Pro Theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-foodie-pro-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-foodie-pro-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike tech and WordPress niche, food blogging is not a competitive niche. Hence, if you share unique recipes on the food blog, you can make good money online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to start a food blog or you already own a food blog, your objective should be to get as many loyal visitors as you can and make money from the site without affecting the visitor experience. To get desired results, you must use a powerful and SEO friendly food blog theme. One of the best templates for the recipe sites is Foodie Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themify Ultra theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themify-ultra-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themify-ultra-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress theme development companies don&amp;rsquo;t run for a long time unless they offer quality support to the customers or launch products that are worth the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themify is one of the most successful WP theme development firms. It has introduced several themes till date. The themes launched by this firm are active on 50000+ sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular theme from Themify is the Ultra theme. I had purchased the WordPress Ultra theme a few months back and I&amp;rsquo;m using it on two sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Best WordPress Magazine themes (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-6-best-wordpress-magazine-themes-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-6-best-wordpress-magazine-themes-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magazine themes are used on WordPress News sites of all types of niches. A news website may have several categories and tags. To make sure that the visitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t get bored while browsing the site, your site should have attractive pages and powerful navigation system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the theme must allow users to customize pages with easy so that you can test the performance of various layouts. Frankly speaking, free themes have limited features and customizing them is a difficult task. Only the users with good knowledge of PHP and CSS can customize their sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegant Themes review 2018: Great themes for WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elegant-themes-review-2018-great-themes-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elegant-themes-review-2018-great-themes-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A theme is responsible for the success of a blogger. Many bloggers end up buying a theme which looks attractive but scores 0 when it comes to SEO. Despite publishing high-quality content on their sites, these bloggers don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy success and they quit blogging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newbie blogger, I had committed a huge mistake of trusting a third class theme developer. The developer rolled out an update which created the dreaded duplicate title, meta description problem on my site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus WordPress theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nexus-wordpress-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nexus-wordpress-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nexus is a powerful WordPress magazine theme developed by ElegantThemes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t aware, ET is one of the top WP theme and plugin development companies. Some of its most popular products are Divi theme, Monarch social sharing plugin, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nexus template has a beautiful layout and it provides a plethora of widgets. It is a customizable theme that supports full-width layout. It is ideal for news websites and blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the best WordPress permalink structure for SEO?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-best-wordpress-permalink-structure-for-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-best-wordpress-permalink-structure-for-seo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress saves the permalink of the page/post in a database table. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t generate them on the fly. Hence, you can change the structure of the post/page URL anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should avoid changing permalinks often because it complicates your site. When you change the URL structure, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to redirect the old URL to the newer URL with a proper HTTP status code. If you don&amp;rsquo;t implement the redirect correctly, your site&amp;rsquo;s traffic from search engines will decline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to show or hide widget in WordPress pages or posts?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-show-or-hide-widget-in-wordpress-pages-or-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-show-or-hide-widget-in-wordpress-pages-or-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may want to display widgets only on certain pages of a site. If you&amp;rsquo;ve knowledge of PHP, you can show/hide widgets with just 2 lines of codes. The 1st line will have the PHP if else condition to detect the current page or term. If the condition you&amp;rsquo;ve specified in the if statement is true, then the code inside the if block must be executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The block must have the shortcode or code to display the required widget. It is the 2nd line of our code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ark WordPress theme review 2018: Killer WP Business template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ark-wordpress-theme-review-2018-killer-wp-business-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ark-wordpress-theme-review-2018-killer-wp-business-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ark theme for WordPress was introduced on Themeforest marketplace in December 2016. Within a month of its launch, Ark has registered 1000+ downloads. It has an excellent rating of 5 from 50+ users. The theme has 200+ customizable elements and 1000+ customization options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ark was declared the top-selling WordPress theme last month. It has become a popular item on ThemeForest within a month of its launch is because FreshLance (developer) is selling the powerful feature rich Ark template for an unbelievable price of $29.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates Link Builder plugin for WordPress now available</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-link-builder-plugin-for-wordpress-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-link-builder-plugin-for-wordpress-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular affiliate program. Until December 2016, the user had to place affiliate URLs manually in the blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manual method of inserting affiliate URLs in the blog post is cumbersome. The user should first create affiliate link using the Amazon Site Stripe tool or with the AA dashboard. Then, they must use the WordPess post editor to insert the affiliate URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon, for the first time, has introduced a WordPress plugin that lets users find products on Amazon and create affiliate links for them from the WordPress dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress widgets for your blog (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-widgets-for-your-blog-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-widgets-for-your-blog-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Widgets are one of the most impressive and powerful features of the WordPress content management system. They make your website look attractive and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you install WordPress, the CMS will add up to 10 different widgets to your blog or website. These widgets have limited functionality. Furthermore, they&amp;rsquo;re not customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free themes may not add new widgets to your WP site. To add a new widget, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to install a new WP plugin. As a blogger, you should know that too many plugins may slow down your website. If the plugin is badly programmed, it will lead to high server resource consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best cheap WordPress hosting with great reviews (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-cheap-wordpress-hosting-with-great-reviews-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-cheap-wordpress-hosting-with-great-reviews-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is the best blogging software and free content management system. It performs well on a powerful server. If the server has a poor configuration, WordPress may not provide the best experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites hosted on an underpowered server suffers from heavy downtimes. The website takes ages to open on the visitor&amp;rsquo;s browser. This results in poor user experience. As the first impression is the best impression, visitors may not visit your site in the future. Search engines fuelled by Artifical Intelligence can distinguish between a user-friendly and a user-hostile website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magazine Pro Theme Review 2018 : SEO Friendly and Fast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/magazine-pro-theme-review-2018-seo-friendly-and-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/magazine-pro-theme-review-2018-seo-friendly-and-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magazine Pro Theme from StudioPress is a powerful WP template for news and technology websites. It is based on responsive and minimal design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme lacks lengthy CSS and JS codes and it looks great. It has clean SEO friendly HTML tags. The small assets and search engine friendly nature of the Magazine Pro make it one of the fastest loading WordPress themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M Pro Genesis Child theme comes with valid Schema markups that help search engines identify various elements on your site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right way to update a WordPress theme or plugin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-right-way-to-update-a-wordpress-theme-or-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-right-way-to-update-a-wordpress-theme-or-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Themes and plugins are the most important parts of a WordPress website. If the code of the theme is not SEO friendly, your site will not perform well in search engines. Likewise, if the plugin has an erroneous code, it can lead to poor user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In worst cases, the problematic theme or plugin may cause high server resource utilization. The search bots will begin to ignore your site. If you don&amp;rsquo;t fix the problem ASAP, the site&amp;rsquo;s rankings will tank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyThemeShop Authority theme review 2018 : Feature packed SEO optimized template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-authority-theme-review-2018-feature-packed-seo-optimized-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-authority-theme-review-2018-feature-packed-seo-optimized-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authority is one of the best-selling WordPress templates of MyThemeShop. It has a large number of users. It is inspired by design of the website of popular blogger Matthew Woodward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authority is a responsive WordPress theme that supports customization of almost every element you&amp;rsquo;ll find on it. It has amazing page speed. It is a premium template with great design and plenty of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mythemeshop-authority-wordpress-theme-review&#34;&gt;MyThemeShop Authority WordPress theme review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you buy the theme, download its ZIP file and upload it to the wp-content folder of your blog. Extract the zip file and activate the theme from your WordPress dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress cost per year and money saving tips for bloggers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-cost-per-year-and-money-saving-tips-for-bloggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-cost-per-year-and-money-saving-tips-for-bloggers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning to launch a self-hosted WordPress blog or site? Your decision is great. WordPress is the backbone of millions of websites. It is the most widely used free blogging software. Although WP is a free CMS, you cannot use it unless you deploy it on a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can run WordPress on your PC by installing the NGINX, PHP-FPM, MySQL stack on your PC. The website deployed on localhost is accessible through an IP address. If you want your WordPress blog to be accessible from computers or mobile devices across the world, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to buy a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress Review Plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-review-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-review-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people use the internet to read reviews of products before they buy them. You may have seen top search engines such as Google or Bing showing star ratings in the search results of its pages. Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the ratings for all websites. It shows ratings only for the portals having schema markups and in-depth content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing the content is up to the user, but one can easily add schema codes to their site by referring the official guidelines. Modern content management systems provide extensions to add review boxes to their site and add the Schema markup code for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Must have WordPress Plugins for 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/must-have-wordpress-plugins-for-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/must-have-wordpress-plugins-for-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress, being a versatile plugin allows you to launch all types of sites. It allows users to install plugins to make website search engine friendly, faster, highly rewarding, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress has millions of users. The WordPress repository hosts over 100k plugins of all types. An experienced blogger using WP platform may not difficulty in choosing the right plugin. But the newbie users may get confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;must have wordpress plugins 2016&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/must-have-wordpress-plugins-for-2018/images/wordpress-logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Viral WordPress themes 2018 : Responsive, fast &amp; feature packed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-feature-packed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-feature-packed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A viral theme is one which helps website owners in garnering tons of traffic from social networks such as Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, etc. It should have excellent layout and beautiful social network icons. The icons in a viral WordPress theme must be placed at the best position so as to increase the chances of a visitor sharing the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to launch a viral WordPress site and looking for a good theme which above mentioned features, consider using the following templates:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Viral WordPress themes 2018 : Responsive, fast &amp;amp; feature packed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-amp-feature-packed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-amp-feature-packed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A viral theme is one which helps website owners in garnering tons of traffic from social networks such as Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, etc. It should have excellent layout and beautiful social network icons. The icons in a viral WordPress theme must be placed at the best position so as to increase the chances of a visitor sharing the content. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to launch a viral WordPress site and looking for a good theme which above mentioned features, consider using the following templates:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Job Board Themes for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-job-board-themes-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-job-board-themes-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recruiting a right person is crucial to the success of a business firm. Creating a website that allows you to publish job listings and managing them is not a huge task for a website developer. The developer can take anything between 20 to 50 days to create a job board site and he&amp;rsquo;ll charge you over $500 as a fee. If you&amp;rsquo;re are looking for a cheaper option, consider using WordPress content management system and buy one of the best Job Board Themes for WordPress we have shared in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing WordPress HTTP error on media or image upload</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fixing-wordpress-http-error-on-media-or-image-upload/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fixing-wordpress-http-error-on-media-or-image-upload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I have addressed one major issue the WordPress users face i.e. HTTP error on uploading media or image files. I encountered this error yesterday while trying to upload a picture in my latest blog post. The picture uploader tool was repeatedly throwing cannot upload error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I logged into the server and checked PHP error log files generated by the website and PHP web server. The files were clean. I checked WP memory limit in the wp-config.php file. The memory allocated to my site was 64 megabytes and all my sites were using 15% of the allocated system memory. Hence, I ruled out the low memory issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WP AMP plugin : Accelerated Mobile Pages for WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wp-amp-plugin-accelerated-mobile-pages-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wp-amp-plugin-accelerated-mobile-pages-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People spend more time on mobile phones than computers. Google Engineers realized this a few years back and they made several changes to core Algorithm. They introduced a mobile-friendly testing tool for webmasters and launched page layout algorithm which affects rankings of ad-heavy desktop/mobile sites. In 2016, Google launched a new concept called Accelerated Mobile Pages. After testing AMP on a bunch of top news website, Google now allows all websites to use AMP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress BeTheme review (2018) : Super theme to Build any type of site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-betheme-review-2018-super-theme-to-build-any-type-of-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-betheme-review-2018-super-theme-to-build-any-type-of-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BeTheme is a responsive multipurpose WP Premium template compatible with BuddyPress, WooCommerce, Gravity forms, BBpress, and many other premium WordPress products. It works on IE9 to IE11 browsers and other top web browsers such as Google Chrome, Opera, Safari, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeTheme has over 45000 users. It is one of the best-selling paid WordPress themes of all time and the best product from top WP development firm Muffingroup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to buying a WordPress Theme which you can model into any type of website, then you should check out the BeTheme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPI Smart Passive Income Pro Theme Review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/spi-smart-passive-income-pro-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/spi-smart-passive-income-pro-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;StupdioPress has launched the new Smart Passive Income Pro theme which resembles the blog of famous blogger Patt Flynn. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Patt is one of the smartest affiliate marketing professionals who has been making over $100000 every month through his Smart Passive Income blog. Patt Flynn has earned over a 3 million dollars so far because of his great strategies and smart design of his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlighting feature of SPI Pro theme is its large fonts in the footer, sidebar, and header section. The big size immaculate fonts give a distinct look to the blog using the SPI Pro template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extra WordPress Theme Review 2018 : Superb Theme powered by Divi Builder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/extra-wordpress-theme-review-2018-superb-theme-powered-by-divi-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/extra-wordpress-theme-review-2018-superb-theme-powered-by-divi-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a searching for a multi-purpose WordPress theme which supports customization up to a great extent, then you&amp;rsquo;re at the right place. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared a detailed review of the ET Extra Theme. Extra is one of the best selling themes from ElegantThemes. It is also one of the most beautiful templates I&amp;rsquo;ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it is a multipurpose theme, you can easily create a WP based eCommerce, Portfolio, News, Magazine, Food blog with Extra. Below are the highlighting features of Xtra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix White Screen of Death Problem?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-white-screen-of-death-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-white-screen-of-death-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the Blue screen of death error, the WSOD is the most commonly reported error. The white screen problem occurs because of few lines of code crashing the entire application. Experienced programmers can fix the issue in a few minutes. If a novice user who hired a freelancer or uses a content management system sees the white screen, he should follow the below two methods to fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wsod-in-sites-other-than-cms&#34;&gt;WSOD in sites other than CMS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you see the white screen of death, the first thing you should do is check log files. Unless you change the path of log files in the server&amp;rsquo;s config file, the web and DB server creates log files in the /var/ directory in Linux. In most of the cases, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the root cause problem for the WSOD problem in these files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OptinMonster vs SumoMe plugin comparison (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-vs-sumome-plugin-comparison-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-vs-sumome-plugin-comparison-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of the best plugins for email marketing and having regular visitors are OptinMonster and SumeMe. SumoMe is an ideal tool for the users looking for an all-in-one plugin for improving traffic, adding new subscribers, etc. OptinMonster is a great plugin for creating Opt-ins of various types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two plugins are great for users who don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste time in customization. They provide predefined templates which you can use right away on your website. In case you&amp;rsquo;re finding it confusing to choose between OptinMonster and SumoMe, go through the below paragraphs where we have explained the similarities and differences between the 2 most popular plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to buy WordPress themes when free templates are available?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-to-buy-wordpress-themes-when-free-templates-are-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-to-buy-wordpress-themes-when-free-templates-are-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is a great content management system because it allows users to launch a new self-hosted blog or website within half an hour. Launching a site is easy but you&amp;rsquo;ll not make money with it if the site doesn&amp;rsquo;t get decent traffic from search engines. To make sure that the site is SEO friendly, you must write good quality content, buy a good hosting plan, and purchase a premium theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoast vs SEO framework vs AIO SEO plugins comparision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/yoast-vs-seo-framework-vs-aio-seo-plugins-comparision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/yoast-vs-seo-framework-vs-aio-seo-plugins-comparision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEO is not a child&amp;rsquo;s play. One wrong setting can impact search engine rankings dramatically. Although WordPress is a decade old CMS and powers millions of sites, it is still suffering from various SEO issues. To fix the problem, the must install one of the 100s of SEO plugins available in the WordPress repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not install plugins which have poor ratings and promise plenty of features. I did the same mistake in the past and I still regret it. In the year 2013, my site lost 90 to 95% organic traffic because of a bad WordPress SEO plugin. Today, the best SEO plugins provide plenty of useful features. They let users optimize their site for higher local search rankings, add breadcrumbs to the website, add XML sitemaps, etc. Moreover, they work great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the Acquia Certified Developer Exam Drupal 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/preparing-for-the-acquia-certified-developer-exam-drupal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/preparing-for-the-acquia-certified-developer-exam-drupal-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Acquia Certified Developer exam Drupal 8 just launched a couple of months ago. I was interested in studying for this exam as I have been working in Drupal 8 for the last six months and future projects look most likely to be Drupal 8 based. I had looked at the various Acquia certification tracks in the past, however I was never fully committed to the Drupal 7 track so I was happy when Acquia announced first the Foundations and then later the Certified Developer exams. I took the Foundations exam first and found that while I was weaker in my front-end Drupal 8 skills, I managed to pass. Later when I sat for the Certified Developer exam I realized there was a bit of cross over in terms of the questions, in fact I think a few of them were taken directly from the foundations exam. I would recommend anyone considering the Certified Developer exam to first take Foundations as it will give you a good idea of the type of questions to expect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection Service Container Example</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dependency-injection-service-container-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dependency-injection-service-container-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier post, I outlined the basics of dependency injection and talked a little bit about the Drupal 8 service container and how we can use this in our code. Day 16 of Drupal Activity Cards provides a task for us to implement dependency injection in one of the Drupal 8 Example modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples module is a great resource for developers getting started in Drupal coding. The modules included gives us basic functionality that provides easy to follow starting points for a number of different needs. For our dependency injection example we are going to look at page_example, a simple module for generating a Drupal 8 page via a controller. A function called simple() returns a basic page. We are going to extend this function to provide a log entry every time a use visits this page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logging in Drupal 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logging-in-drupal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logging-in-drupal-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Logging is very important in any production site because we don&amp;rsquo;t have the same ability to debug code that we have in our development environments. Drupal 7 had a very robust logging system called watchdog(), which has been replaced by logger in Drupal 8. This post summarizes a basic use case for logging in Drupal 8 continuing the Drupal 8 Activity Cards series on Day 13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amber Matz breaks down logging in Drupal 8 concisely in How to Log Messages in Drupal 8. In her article, she breaks down the code needed to implement logger and provides solid explanations. The examples provided involve procedural coding in the .module file as does the example I provide in this article. If you are writing controllers or forms that extend ControllerBase or FormBase then it would be better to use the service container to inject logger into your code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Drupal 8 Theming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-drupal-8-theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-drupal-8-theming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drupal 8 has a new theme engine, however many of the concepts we are familiar with in Drupal 7 are still in place in this new version. Themes still have the same ability to overwrite various templates within core, only now instead of modifying .tpl.php files, you will be creating Twig files in their place. Theme functions are still available to use, however they are now kept in the .theme file instead of template.php. Other changes worthy of exploring in more depth are briefly summarized below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Custom Content Entity Type</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/creating-a-custom-content-entity-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/creating-a-custom-content-entity-type/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drupal 8 has seen a lot of improvements for content entities and with the new Drupal console, setting up a content entity has been made a lot easier with the addition of boilerplate code generation. Day 11 of the Drupal 8 Activity Card set focuses on content entities, how they can be setup in Drupal 8, how we might add our own custom fields to the boilerplate code provided, and how this is managed within the Drupal 8 administration system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring your Local Drupal 8 Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/configuring-your-local-drupal-8-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/configuring-your-local-drupal-8-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have struggled with properly optimizing my local environment in terms of enabling debugging and disabling cache for a while. There isn&amp;rsquo;t that many steps you need to cover in order to have a proper working development environment. After reviewing Day 10 I completed setting up my environment the correct way and have outlined this in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-enable-settingslocalphp&#34;&gt;Step 1 Enable settings.local.php&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy and Rename /sites/settings.example.local.php -&amp;gt; /sites/default/settings.local.php&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncomment the following lines in your settings.php file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# if (file_exists(__DIR__ . &amp;#39;/settings.local.php&amp;#39;)) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#   include __DIR__ . &amp;#39;/settings.local.php&amp;#39;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-disable-cache-services&#34;&gt;Step 2 Disable Cache Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your sites/default/settings.local.php file, uncomment the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# $settings[&amp;#39;cache&amp;#39;][&amp;#39;bins&amp;#39;][&amp;#39;render&amp;#39;] = &amp;#39;cache.backend.null&amp;#39;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuild your site configuration by visiting yoursite.local/rebuild.php&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-disabletwig-cache-and-enable-debugging&#34;&gt;Step 3 Disable Twig Cache and Enable Debugging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the following lines to your /sites/development-services.yml (Refer to /sites/default/default-services.yml for all options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;parameters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;twig&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;auto_reload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;cache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear Cache and then verify Twig debugging has been enabled by refreshing your Drupal 8 homepage. Review your source code and you should see something similar to:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!--&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;THEME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;DEBUG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!--&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;THEME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;HOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!--&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;FILE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;NAME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;SUGGESTIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;front&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;twig&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;--.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;twig&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;twig&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twig debugging gives a lot of helpful information scattered throughout your source code in the form of comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attaching JS and CSS Assets in Drupal 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/attaching-js-and-css-assets-in-drupal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/attaching-js-and-css-assets-in-drupal-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drupal 8 has introduced a different way of attaching JavaScript and CSS to themes and custom modules via a new concept called libraries, which are covered in Day 9. Libraries are essentially .yml files that define different groups of assets that can later be attached via module code. When I started working with the theme layer in Drupal 8, I quickly realized that certain things are very different from Drupal 7. One of the main gotchas for anyone new to Drupal 8 is the idea that JavaScript libraries are now only loaded where they are needed. In contrast to Drupal 7 where jQuery for example, was loaded on every page, in Drupal 8 jQuery is no longer automatically loaded. This provides for a better optimized site with only the required libraries included in areas that they are needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal 8 Plugin System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-plugin-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-plugin-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of new terminology in Drupal 8 and for anyone not familiar with Object Oriented programming, some of it can be downright confusing. For myself, I have worked with OOP for quite a while, however I have not spent as much time writing custom modules for Drupal 7. While I am familiar on the surface with the hook system and API at a very novice level, I have never really had to do any intense back end development in D7. Now that I am working in Drupal 8, things are quite different with my projects at work. Thankfully my OOP background has filled in some of the gaps, however my lack of Drupal 7 module development knowledge has proven to be a burden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cron Queuing in Drupal 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cron-queuing-in-drupal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cron-queuing-in-drupal-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 7 focuses mainly on the Drupal Queue API. The main resource for this card is an article called Drupal 8 Queue API – Powerful Manual and Cron Queueing, which I had referenced in an earlier post. Before completing any of the materials, I had no previous experience with the Queue API, nor hook_entity_insert, which was used to create a demo queue system in the referenced article. After going through the article I gained a better understanding of how the queue system works. At a high level the following steps outline the process of constructing the module that is documented in this article along with relevant links to the API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Services and Dependency Injection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/services-and-dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/services-and-dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For several years I have worked as an ASP.NET MVC developer and have become intimately familiar with terms such as services and dependency injection and services. It is refreshing to see some of these familiar concepts surfacing in Drupal 8. Day 6 focuses mainly on introducing us to services and dependency injection via several online resources. There is no exercises or tasks in this card as the aim is to simply gain an understanding of some of these concepts. I saw a lot of overlap in terms of syntax and how dependency injection is handled in Drupal 8 compared with Unity and StuctureMap in ASP.NET, so anyone from background or other traditional object oriented languages such as Java will be familiar with a lot of this. I have outlined the main takeaways I got from the Day 6 below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal 8 Migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had some exposure to the migrate module in the past, mostly with Drupal 7 and more recently for a Drupal 8 migration project that required importing of a small (under 1000) set of records stored in a CSV file. Todays D8Card focuses on the new migration module that comes partly with core and also partly in the form of contributed modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrate-core--migrate-contrib&#34;&gt;Migrate Core &amp;amp; Migrate Contrib&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of todays set of tasks was to import a couple of small CSV files using migrate and some of the contributed modules. I started out by reviewing the links posted in the card and then proceeded to download and install migrate_tools, migrate_plus, and migrate_source_csv. What comes with Drupal 8 core out of the box is pretty limited and only contains migration functionality for moving content from previous Drupal sites. It definitely makes the upgrade process less painful, however if you want to get into migration code that can manage a multitude of external sources, then you will want to grab to contrib modules above.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress Genesis Pro Plus Package : All themes at great price</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-genesis-pro-plus-package-all-themes-at-great-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/studiopress-genesis-pro-plus-package-all-themes-at-great-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;StudioPress Genesis Framework powers 1000s of WordPress sites. It is better than Thesis and many other WP frameworks. It is SEO friendly, mobile optimized, lightweight, and fast. SGF includes several intuitive features. It includes special modules that save your money. Example, you won&amp;rsquo;t need a premium opt-in form aka newsletter plugin if you use SGF. Many top bloggers who earn six figure income per month use SGF. StudioPress Genesis is the highest rated and most successful WordPress product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Block System in Drupal 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-new-block-system-in-drupal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-new-block-system-in-drupal-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many changes in Drupal 8, the blocks system received an overhaul, which has improved much of its functionality significantly. Some of the most notable take aways include the new block page layout and UI for updating, adding, and editing blocks, the addition of custom blocks and fieldable types (similar to content types), and integration with display view modes to allow for rendering changes based on block placement. Day 5 directs you to a good introductory video of the new blocks system by the Drupalize.me team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Configuration Forms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/building-configuration-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/building-configuration-forms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Day 3 we are starting to accelerate in terms of skills developed by the cards. This card has us create our first Drupal 8 module, learn about Drupal 8 Form API and learn about the Configuration API. The card starts off with directing you to several Drupal.org documentation pages including Creating a Custom Page,  Defining and using your own configuration in Drupal 8, Providing Default configuration, and Simple Configuration API. Except for the Creating a Custom Page document, everything else here is focused on giving you a solid overview of the configuration system within Drupal 8.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paragraphs Module</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paragraphs-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paragraphs-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to be honest, before completing Day 2 tasks, I had never actually used the Paragraphs module before. I heard others mention it in the past and considered looking at it at some point, however until today I did not realize what I was missing in terms of the power and flexibility that this module has to offer. The d8cards.com Paragraphs Module card begins with directing you to YouTube tutorial by Zane Sensenig, embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal 8 Configuration Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-configuration-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drupal-8-configuration-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-21-day-challenge&#34;&gt;THE 21 DAY CHALLENGE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to learn Drupal 8 for the last couple of months as I was landed in the middle of a D8 project at work. Being involved on the project has taught me a lot about Drupal 8 module development and Symfony in general, however I have started questioning the way I am writing code and if in fact it is the best way or the ‘Drupal’ way. I decided I needed some additional exposure to Drupal 8, not only in terms of module development, but as a platform in its entirety including front-end, configuration as well as back-end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xdebug &#43; Scotchbox Vagrant &#43; PHPStorm in Three Steps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/xdebug--scotchbox-vagrant--phpstorm-in-three-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/xdebug--scotchbox-vagrant--phpstorm-in-three-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I come from a .NET background where I was spoiled by the ease of use and integration of Visual Studio. Recently much of my development work has moved to the open source and the world of Drupal 8 where I have gotten by until recently with Sublime Text and Atom. Since I have started writing custom modules, I needed a way to effectively debug my code and I had heard good things about the PHP debugger Xdebug. Unfortunately it can be a little tricky to setup, so I have outlined the basic steps I needed to go through using my favorite Vagrant environment Scotchbox. If you are unfamiliar with Scotchbox, check out my earlier posts Scotchbox Vagrant LAMP Stack and Drupal Development Environment in less than 10 Minutes&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to compress or minify HTML of a WordPress site?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-compress-or-minify-html-of-a-wordpress-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-compress-or-minify-html-of-a-wordpress-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Minification is a process of stripping whitespaces and comments of a page. When you minify a web page, the visitors to your website will experience faster browsing experience on their desktop or mobile device. The page speed insights tool will not request you to minify HTML, JS, or CSS code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you minify HTML, CSS or JS code on your website, the server will send a small page to the client. The file size is yet another factor in determining the page speed of a website. The browser on the client device will download a smaller file faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using PostGreSQL with Scotchbox Vagrant LAMP Stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/using-postgresql-with-scotchbox-vagrant-lamp-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/using-postgresql-with-scotchbox-vagrant-lamp-stack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Scotchbox for a while now and continue to be impressed by it&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and ease of use compared to other Vagrant environments I have used in the past. Recently I started working on a Drupal 8 project that required the use of a PostGreSQL (PostGres) database. Thankfully, when I checked the Scotchbox 2.0 documentation, it appeared that PostGres came packaged up with the environment and ready to use. After doing a little bit of research I realized I needed to follow a couple of steps in order to get this running properly with a PostGres client. I am outlining the steps below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to remove this site may be hacked message from Google?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-remove-this-site-may-be-hacked-message-from-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-remove-this-site-may-be-hacked-message-from-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google makes sure that the site which the user is about to visit is clean. It displays a warning message for the websites which are not safe. One of the most common messages that a search engine user see is &amp;ldquo;This site may be hacked&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search engine will show this message in the search results in one of the below cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;malicious-code-in-web-pages&#34;&gt;Malicious code in web pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hacker may have inserted a malicious code in the web pages. When Google comes across this code and finds it suspicious, your site will be flagged as hacked. You can use the free AW Snap tool to find malicious pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix 404 not found wp-admin or wp-login PHP error in WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-404-not-found-wp-admin-or-wp-login-php-error-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-404-not-found-wp-admin-or-wp-login-php-error-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a bad day, you may face difficulties in logging into the WP dashboard or opening the login page. These two problems can be easily fixed if you know the HTTP status code or error message shown by the browser when you access the twp pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we will help you out in fixing the 404 not found error message displayed by the web browser when you try to open wp-login or wp-admin PHP files. Earlier, we had shared a tutorial on fixing error establishing a database connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best featured image plugin for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-featured-image-plugin-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-featured-image-plugin-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Featured image is a picture that appears in the post excerpt. When the visitor sees the image, he will find the topic interesting, relevant, and will not hesitate in exploring your website further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the premium and free WordPress themes launched these days support FI. If your website has 100s of posts, it is difficult to set featured images manually unless you are ready to edit posts one by one. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do so because the below free plugins will automate this task for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Genesis Child Themes for blogs and business (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-genesis-child-themes-for-blogs-and-business-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-genesis-child-themes-for-blogs-and-business-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genesis Framework is a WordPress product from the owners of Copyblogger content marketing blog. It is so popular that every blogger using WP is aware of the Genesis Framework and its premium themes. If your site is using this framework, then you&amp;rsquo;ll not face any SEO issues unless you do something wrong Ex: changing code. Genesis Framework powers many top websites and blogs built with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the themes launched by StudioPress Genesis Framework are SEO friendly, responsive, Google AdSense ready, and adhere to HTML5 standards. As they are designed and developed by experts, the templates performance will be great even if the user is using shared hosting service. In case you&amp;rsquo;re planning to purchase the StudioPress Genesis Framework, go through the paragraphs we have shared below as today we&amp;rsquo;ve shared the top best Genesis Child Themes for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Image Sharing Plugin for WordPress (2016)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-image-sharing-plugin-for-wordpress-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-image-sharing-plugin-for-wordpress-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A blog post is incomplete without images. Imagine if a site has no photos, will you spend your time going through the content?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A visitor to your website might be impressed with the picture you&amp;rsquo;ve embedded in the blog post. He may want to share the image on social networks. Some users may not waste their time in copying the photo URL by right clicking on the page. They may exit your website and use Google image search to get a link to the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Affiliate Link Cloaker Plugin for Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-affiliate-link-cloaker-plugin-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-affiliate-link-cloaker-plugin-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Affiliate links are ugly and long. When the user hovers your mouse on an affiliate link and finds your tracking code in the URL, he may not click the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a seasoned webmaster, you should use a plugin to create and manage affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoCodes was one of the best affiliate link Cloaker plugins. I was using it until I update the PHP on my VPS server. Unfortunately, the plugin has become useless because it has not been updated for 2 years. GoCodes will not work on sites using the latest version of PHP because several functions that GoCodes uses have been deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress Plugin update manager (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-plugin-update-manager-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-plugin-update-manager-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[et_pb_section admin_label=&amp;ldquo;section&amp;rdquo;] [et_pb_row admin_label=&amp;ldquo;row&amp;rdquo;] [et_pb_column type=&amp;ldquo;4_4&amp;rdquo;] [et_pb_text admin_label=&amp;ldquo;Text&amp;rdquo;] Auttomatic Inc, the developer of WordPress rolls out a new version of WP ever since the first version of this free blogging platform was first launched. It&amp;rsquo;s not only the core that gets regular updates, but plugins and theme developers also publish latest versions of their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WP-CMS, themes, and plugins get better with every new release. Only the folks who work at Automattic INC know when WordPress update will be released. When a developer releases a newer version of his/her theme or plugin, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a notification for the same in the WP dashboard. The big problem with WordPress is that users will have to update their plugins, core files, and theme manually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hide My WP Review 2018 : Secures your Website like no other plugin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hide-my-wp-review-2018-secures-your-website-like-no-other-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hide-my-wp-review-2018-secures-your-website-like-no-other-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1000s of WordPress websites are hacked every day because the hackers are aware of the security loopholes in plugins and themes that the website is using. Usually, the websites that use outdated or nulled WordPress plugins and themes fall prey to hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are incidents where websites that use powerful WordPress security plugins are hacked. To keep your WordPress website or blog safe, you must back up the database and images on regular basis. You should also use a WordPress security plugin and tweak web server settings to minimize threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyThemeShop Schema Theme Review 2018 : 100% SEO friendly template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-schema-theme-review-2018-100-seo-friendly-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-schema-theme-review-2018-100-seo-friendly-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a premium WordPress theme ensures that you&amp;rsquo;ll be given assistance when you encounter problems with the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme will have clean code and it will be search engine and mobile friendly. Unfortunately, the premium theme which I used earlier on this blog was a waste of my money. I had bought it when I was a newbie blogger after reading a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme was good initially, but the developer removed its inbuilt review system. When I asked the development team why they did so? They asked me to wait for a few weeks because they&amp;rsquo;ll be launching a review plugin. It has been 5 months now, the plugins have not been released yet. All my reviews and the schema start rating markups were gone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cache Enabler Plugin Review: W3TC and WPSC Alternative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cache-enabler-plugin-review-w3tc-and-wpsc-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cache-enabler-plugin-review-w3tc-and-wpsc-alternative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Caching of WordPress posts and pages are two of the best way to increase the page speed. While most of the WP users prefer using WPSC or W3TC, there are a lot of users who are always in search for different plugins. For such users, today we&amp;rsquo;ll share a review on the Cache Enabler plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cache enabler is one of the lightest WordPress plugins. It has been developed by folks at the popular CDN service provider, KeyCDN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best free WordPress Events Calendar Plugin (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-events-calendar-plugin-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-events-calendar-plugin-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The events calendar plugin by the modern tribe is the best calendar plugin for WordPress. More than 20 developers have authored it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin is active on 0.4 million WordPress websites. It is free. Let&amp;rsquo;s find it out why the plugin is so popular among the WordPress users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wordpress-events-calendar-plugin-review&#34;&gt;The WordPress events calendar plugin review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to install this excellent plugin from the WordPress.org repository. Once you activate it, the plugin adds event management controls below the blog post editor in the WordPress dashboard. Thus, you can quickly enter detailed information about the event in the blog post. When the post has been published, your event will be inserted right below the post content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UberMenu plugin : Add responsive mega menu to WordPress site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ubermenu-plugin-add-responsive-mega-menu-to-wordpress-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ubermenu-plugin-add-responsive-mega-menu-to-wordpress-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mega menus have become a new trend in the world of internet. They make navigation much easier for the user as well makes your website more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mega Menus are created with the help of CSS, JS/Jquery, and HTML. Creating them is not an easy task. Only a seasoned developer with good knowledge of the above-mentioned technologies will be able to design and code a perfect mega menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress users are fortunate because they don&amp;rsquo;t have to write code for implementing new features in their websites. They&amp;rsquo;ll find all types of plugins on the WordPress.org repo and CodeCanyon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete unused images in WordPress with Media Cleaner plugin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/delete-unused-images-in-wordpress-with-media-cleaner-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/delete-unused-images-in-wordpress-with-media-cleaner-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is one of the most important elements of a blog post. It not only makes the post attractive but also helps in improving the website&amp;rsquo;s search engine visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when you update a blog post, you may replace the image/pictures in it with some other pictures. Many users don&amp;rsquo;t bother to delete the old images from the uploads directory of wp-content WordPress installation folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a site grows larger, the uploads folder may have tons of unused images. These files waste storage memory, and they impact system&amp;rsquo;s performance. To delete or remove these files, download the Media Cleaner plugin and install it on your WordPress website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegant Themes Monarch WordPress Plugin Review (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elegant-themes-monarch-wordpress-plugin-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elegant-themes-monarch-wordpress-plugin-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a type of online business. If you invest money in your WordPress site, your business will benefit from it. In WP, investment is nothing but purchasing premium themes and plugins which help in improving UX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to plugins, the most important plugin is the one that allows visitors to share blog posts on social networks. Yes! You&amp;rsquo;ve guessed it right! We&amp;rsquo;re talking about social media sharing plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing WordPress Login page and WP Admin area</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/securing-wordpress-login-page-and-wp-admin-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/securing-wordpress-login-page-and-wp-admin-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WP login.php is the most critical page on a WordPress website. Without it, you will not be able to access the WP-admin area aka the WP dashboard and other users will not be able to register an account with your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No website owner would ever want a hacker or an intruder to get full access to the WP-admin area. If they do manage to get its access, intruders will delete your website, change admin password or remove all your post/pages. To avoid this, you should secure the WordPress login page by:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix Error Establishing a Database Connection in WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-error-establishing-a-database-connection-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-error-establishing-a-database-connection-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress saves the post, settings and other data related to your website in an MSQL database. The DB is handled by the user through CMS with a DB management plugin or through a command line terminal from a remote computer (on unmanaged hosting environment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the WordPress PHP files will not be able to connect to the MySQL server, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be notified of this error when you try to access any page of your website.  Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some effective tips to fix this common WordPress problem and avoid it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WP Customer Reviews plugin allows users to rate product or business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp-customer-reviews-plugin-allows-users-to-rate-product-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp-customer-reviews-plugin-allows-users-to-rate-product-or-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before buying any product from a website or before contacting a business, search engine users will go through the reviews. If the reviews are negative, the user may not communicate with the business or he&amp;rsquo;ll leave the website without making any purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers are the best people to judge a product and the best way to get their feedback is by adding a review section to the website. Reviews may help in improving the rankings of a website as it may have many new keywords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WP Statistics is a Google Analytics alternative for WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some webmasters are concerned about their online privacy, and they will never use a popular third party analytics tool like Google Search Console, webmaster tools, clicky, StatCounter, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To safeguard their website statistics, people use a plugin which will create a database to store data related to websites. One of the best plugin to do this job is WP statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin works 24 x 7 to update the DB with visitor data. You can use it to compare website traffic from the best search engines i.e. Google, Bing, Baidu, Yandex, DuckDuckGo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best way to add Google Fonts to WordPress website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-add-google-fonts-to-wordpress-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-add-google-fonts-to-wordpress-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The font is one of the most critical elements on a website. Developers make sure that the typography of their website is best in class. If your visitor finds that your site is ugly, he&amp;rsquo;ll leave it immediately without reading the content or making a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 100s of fonts that you can use for free, but you will have to spend a lot of time in searching for them unless you use Google web fonts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Widgets plugin lets you control widget display in WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dynamic-widgets-plugin-lets-you-control-widget-display-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dynamic-widgets-plugin-lets-you-control-widget-display-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sidebar is one of the most critical section of a website. It not only helps in improving the revenue of a site by allowing users to place adverts above the fold but also helps in decreasing the bounce rate. On WordPress blogs, you&amp;rsquo;ll find banners, related/latest/popular post&amp;rsquo;s widget on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content you add to the sidebar will be visible on all posts. If there are 1000 posts on your website, each and every advertisement or URL you&amp;rsquo;ll add as a widget will be displayed on each post. You may have grouped your posts in many categories. Suppose there are four categories on your website - phones, laptops, tablets, and desktop. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;ve published an article on a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple 301 WordPress Redirect plugin fixes broken link issues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/simple-301-wordpress-redirect-plugin-fixes-broken-link-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/simple-301-wordpress-redirect-plugin-fixes-broken-link-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Google Search Console tool make us aware of various errors that Google encountered while crawling our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;404 errors don&amp;rsquo;t have any impact on the ranking of a website. But if the error is generated because of change in permalink or its structure, you&amp;rsquo;ll lose traffic from the search engines as well as the social networks. Page Rank will be lost as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the best experience of the search bot and user, it is important that we fix the reported error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Image Size in Post Content WordPress?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-change-image-size-in-post-content-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-change-image-size-in-post-content-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may not like your current WordPress theme, and you may think of replacing it with some other template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes allow you to export settings. But the settings you back up will be compatible only with the theme i.e. You can&amp;rsquo;t move settings of a Mythemshop template to TagDiv NewsPaper or Elegant Themes Divi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you change your template, you may have to tweak the design for the best experience of the user. You may also have to change image sizes so that the blog posts don&amp;rsquo;t look horrible or broken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Form DB plugin : Check mails in WordPress Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact-form-db-plugin-check-mails-in-wordpress-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact-form-db-plugin-check-mails-in-wordpress-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know how easy it is to create a contact form page in WordPress. If not, then you might be a newbie who should explore the WordPress plugins repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contact form plugin will allow you to create and add a customized form to your WordPress website. The plugin will allow the user to add fields of his choice to the contact form page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress CMS has been built with PHP, the server-side scripting language. PHP includes the mail function that accepts some parameters to send a mail to an email address. The function is implement, and many WordPress plugins are powered it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to add and customize Facebook feed in WordPress?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-add-and-customize-facebook-feed-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-add-and-customize-facebook-feed-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook allows the webmasters to add the Facebook comment form, like box or the page feed to their websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In WordPress CMS, adding a comment form or the like box is easy, but inserting a page feed is usually a tricky task for a webmaster. Even if the user manages to add FB feed to the sidebar, he won&amp;rsquo;t be able to customize it unless the user knows the working knowledge of CSS. In such cases, the user should use the free custom Facebook feed plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding WordPress Breadcrumbs navigation and customizing it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/adding-wordpress-breadcrumbs-navigation-and-customizing-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/adding-wordpress-breadcrumbs-navigation-and-customizing-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress supports taxonomies. In the WP CMS (content management system), the user can create as many tags and categories as they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A category is different from a tag. It is used to build a menu. If you create a treemap of WordPress structure, then the categories will always be the child of index or root page. They make navigation easier for the search bots and the visitors. On a small blog or a website, the webmaster should create only a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plugins to add 2 step authentication to WordPress website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plugins-to-add-2-step-authentication-to-wordpress-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plugins-to-add-2-step-authentication-to-wordpress-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dual factor authentication has become one of the most important security features in the last few years. Major websites like Google Mail, Outlook, Facebook are now protecting user accounts in a better way by allowing them to use a mobile device as their identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To activate 2 step authentication, the service provider will ask you to install Google Authenticator app (or any of its alternative). Some websites will ask you to verify the mobile phone number so that the authentication service will send a 4 or 5 digit code when required. This code will be used for one-time verification, and it will be valid only for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call to action buttons : Do they really work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/call-to-action-buttons-do-they-really-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/call-to-action-buttons-do-they-really-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to website designing, the User Experience plays a crucial role. If a site is not user-friendly, the conversions and revenue will be flat unless most of your earnings come from Adsense or its alternative advertising platform. This applies to all websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to make sure that your website is effectively generating revenue and the user visits more than one pages of your site, you should add the call to action buttons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes ultimate plugin : generate responsive shortcodes easily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shortcodes-ultimate-plugin-generate-responsive-shortcodes-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shortcodes-ultimate-plugin-generate-responsive-shortcodes-easily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortcodes Ultimate by Vladimir Anokhin is a top rated WordPress plugin with 700000+ downloads. It allows you to generate and use HTML shortcodes of various styles and colors. The plugin allows customization. The code created by this is responsive and clean. Thus, it will work with all types of plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress Shortcodes Ultimate is compatible with other plugins as well. It supports multiple languages and RTL. The plugin supports extensions. For styling, it uses CSS3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inline Related Posts plugin can lower the bounce rate of your blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inline-related-posts-plugin-can-lower-the-bounce-rate-of-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inline-related-posts-plugin-can-lower-the-bounce-rate-of-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On many established blogs, you&amp;rsquo;ll find related or recommended articles in post content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The posts are embedded in a stylized &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and they attract visitor&amp;rsquo;s attention. They&amp;rsquo;re known as inline related posts (IRP). IRPs, when placed at the right position can reduce the bounce rate of a blog. They can also increase the page-views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established websites have enough revenue to hire a WordPress developer who can write the code to insert content hyperlinks inline of the post automatically after the post has been published.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All in One Security and Firewall plugin secures your WP website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/all-in-one-security-and-firewall-plugin-secures-your-wp-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/all-in-one-security-and-firewall-plugin-secures-your-wp-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is claimed to be one of the most secure content management systems of the decade, but you need to take some precautions while using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The login page is accessible to everyone using the Internet. To access the page, the user has to enter example.com/wp-login.php simply. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a weak password, then a software or a bot can easily hack your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some hackers will target your site with a DOS or DDOS attack. If your hosting provider has not set up a firewall for your account, your website and web server will be down. If the site has many visitors, you&amp;rsquo;ll lose some revenue. If the access to the wp-config file is not restricted, the hacker will get your database name and its password.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Ads is Powerful plugin to insert and manage adverts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/advanced-ads-is-powerful-plugin-to-insert-and-manage-adverts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/advanced-ads-is-powerful-plugin-to-insert-and-manage-adverts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I felt the need to install a new third party plugin for inserting advertisements to my blog. My favorite plugin i.e. Quick Adsense has not been updated for over 1.5 years, and it has become unreliable because it has not been tested with latest WordPress versions. I searched the WordPress repository to find a reliable and frequently updated plugin for insert adverts. After a few minutes, I found Advanced ads. I was tempted to try out the plugin after going through its ratings and reviews shared by the real users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create WordPress database backup with or without plugin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-create-wordpress-database-backup-with-or-without-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-create-wordpress-database-backup-with-or-without-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a backup of the database is practiced in all the top organisations. For webmasters who work online, it&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All websites are prone to hacking. Hackers are always in search of a security loophole in a website. When they find one, they&amp;rsquo;ll deface it by changing the index file. Hackers locate the site configuration file stored on the servers to find database password so that they can access the database.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetPack plugin now lets you create a sitemap for WordPress website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jetpack-plugin-now-lets-you-create-a-sitemap-for-wordpress-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jetpack-plugin-now-lets-you-create-a-sitemap-for-wordpress-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jetpack, one of an essential WordPress plugin now allows you to generate a sitemap to google search as well as google news. This new feature has been added to the latest version (v 3.9) of Jetpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sitemap is an important element of a website (no matter what its niche is). It makes the search engine aware of the latest posts on your site. When Sitemap is submitted to Google, Yandex or Bing, your posts will be indexed faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yuzo related posts for WordPress review : Free and Powerful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/yuzo-related-posts-for-wordpress-review-free-and-powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/yuzo-related-posts-for-wordpress-review-free-and-powerful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The developer claims that Yuzo is the fastest and the best plugin for WordPress. We decided to give it a try. Below is our review of this free plugin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yuzo can be installed via FTP or WordPress dashboard. After its installation, activate the plugin and navigate to its settings page. This page has three tabs, main settings, styling, and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can configure this plugin to display maximum 50 related posts per page. You can set a custom title for the relevant content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding analytics dashboard to WordPress site in a minute</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is one of the most valuable free tools for webmasters. With it, you can easily track traffic to your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytics makes you aware of many details like visitor source, average visit time, page views, website loading speed, device, operating system, the browser of the visitor and much more. It is easy to understand the tool. Even new bloggers or website owners will find it intuitive and easy to use. To start tracking the visitor behavior and traffic, the user has to install a tracking code to the header or footer section of their website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classipress review : Best WordPress classifieds theme (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classipress-review-best-wordpress-classifieds-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classipress-review-best-wordpress-classifieds-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a classified site manually from scratch is not an easy task. You must have exceptional website development skills with good knowledge of local SEO, server configuration, database, HTML, JavaScript, and a website scripting language like PHP, Ruby on Rails, ASP, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills mentioned above, there&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to launch a classified website. Yes, Believe Me! You can quickly launch your own classified&amp;rsquo;s portal like OLX, Quikr, Craigslist in half an hour with the world&amp;rsquo;s most robust content management system named WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OnePress social locker plugin for WordPress review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/onepress-social-locker-plugin-for-wordpress-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/onepress-social-locker-plugin-for-wordpress-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content locker WordPress plugins are becoming popular these days. They are useful in increasing the Facebook likes Google plus one and twitter tweet counts. The plugin hides your content for visitors (not for search engines) and displays it only when the user shares your post on the pre-configured social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OnePress is the best content locker plugin for WordPress. It is available in free and premium versions. The free version of OnePress allows webmasters to add maximum three social sharing buttons, i.e., FB, G+, and tweet. The pro version supports many other popular social networks. OnePress comes with an analytics dashboard. To improve your social visibility, you can use this dashboard for analysis and adjusting the position of the locker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress search plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-search-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-search-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The default WordPress search module is useful, but not the best. No matter what keyword or term you search for, you&amp;rsquo;ll not be satisfied with the results generated by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This module is critical because people use it to find relevant information on your site. It can also reduce the bounce rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the WordPress content management system supports hierarchical pages (categories, tags, authors, attachment pages) that make navigation easy for the visitor, it is always a good decision to add a powerful search function to your blog. Thankfully, we don&amp;rsquo;t have to write PHP code for the same. There are a lot of free WordPress search plugins available for download. But the below two plugins are the best and most powerful among them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is the best WordPress popular posts plugin for blogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/this-is-the-best-wordpress-popular-posts-plugin-for-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/this-is-the-best-wordpress-popular-posts-plugin-for-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Displaying popular posts in blog sidebar is useful in many ways. As your top articles are posted, the link juice aka page rank will transfer to them which in turn will help your posts rank higher in search engines like Google, Bing, etc. Adding a widget for the same is a good way of strengthening the internal link structure of your website. If your top posts have affiliate links, displaying them in the sidebar will boost your income and conversions. There are a lot of popular post widgets and plugins but the one which I&amp;rsquo;ve shared today is what you&amp;rsquo;re probably looking for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WP-FFPC settings and features: Powerful caching plugin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp-ffpc-settings-and-features-powerful-caching-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp-ffpc-settings-and-features-powerful-caching-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although W3TC has options to configure Memcache and OPCache modules, this plugin requires some configuration to work according to your expectations. It includes many features that you may not want to use. To be honest, W3TC and WPSC are best plugins for Shared hosting users as users can easily make their site faster by activating disk caching, minification or by setting an expiry date for static resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a VPS package from Hostgator, Bluehost or any other hosting provider, you should try out WP-FFPC. The highlighting feature of this plugin is that it supports various types of web servers and lacks complex features. You can easily run it on NGINX, LightHTTPD, Apache 2 platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumome plugin for WordPress : free list builder social sharing and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sumome-plugin-for-wordpress-free-list-builder-social-sharing-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sumome-plugin-for-wordpress-free-list-builder-social-sharing-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suomeme is an awesome all in one plugin for promoting blog posts. It has a powerful sharing button that not only looks great but also allows users to share posts on top social networks without adding a lot of weight on your pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plugin lets users add a floating bar in the header or footer area of your blog. Thus you can use it as an alternative to hellobar. Sharing images from your blog posts is possible with Sumome. The buttons for the same will appear automatically when the user hovers mouse cursor on the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WPDiscuz plugin: Great Alternative to Disqus and WordPress comment system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wpdiscuz-plugin-great-alternative-to-disqus-and-wordpress-comment-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wpdiscuz-plugin-great-alternative-to-disqus-and-wordpress-comment-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The default WordPress commenting system is good, but some people may want to replace it with a third party plugin like Disqus, Livefyre for better control, spam protection, and administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disqus adds a lot of weight to your site, and you should think before using it. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen LiveFyre plugin on high traffic websites, and it looks great. I&amp;rsquo;ve not tested it. In case you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a Disqus or Livefyre alternative for your WordPress site, there&amp;rsquo;s a good new option available for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WPBakery review: best WordPress page builder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wpbakery-review-best-wordpress-page-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wpbakery-review-best-wordpress-page-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have sound knowledge of PHP, CSS, JS, and HTML, you can quickly build good-looking pages in WordPress. It is also possible with a WPBakery page builder plugin for WordPress. WPBakery is a well-designed plugin that lets users create various types of website layouts and pages with CTA buttons. There are around 29 great designs to choose from. WPBakery is responsive, and your site designed with it will look great on any phone or tablet. It supports all types of WordPress themes, and no other plugin will be affected by its presence. It has a frontend and backend builder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mythemeshop review 2018 : Amazing themes and plugins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-review-2018-amazing-themes-and-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mythemeshop-review-2018-amazing-themes-and-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a premium theme or plugin is not an easy task as there are a lot of WP developers who have launched a variety of templates for the users. To make things less complicated and easy for you, we are trying our level best to shared a detailed review on themes launched by top developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, we had shared a detailed and honest review on Elegant Divi and Themeforest NewsPaper. After going through the two powerful templates, we&amp;rsquo;ve concluded that ET and TF are undoubtedly 2 of the top platform for buying a high-quality WordPress plugin or templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally load scripts in WordPress to boost speed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/conditionally-load-scripts-in-wordpress-to-boost-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/conditionally-load-scripts-in-wordpress-to-boost-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;ve installed a WordPress table plugin on your site. You have 1000 blog posts, and only 10 of them has a table. The Javascript and CSS files for the same will be inserted in the header section, and it will be called on all the pages even though you have not added a table. This increases the page size, and it can affect the page loading time. To solve this problem, you can either write a PHP code that will insert CSS and JS scripts in the site header only when required or you can install WordPress plugin organizer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disqus WordPress plugin : Pros, Cons, issues and fixes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/disqus-wordpress-plugin-pros-cons-issues-and-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/disqus-wordpress-plugin-pros-cons-issues-and-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a lot of users are commenting on your articles, you should make sure that the comments do not affect the load time of the page. If it is affecting posts load time, the user should enable pagination for the same by navigating to Settings&amp;mdash;&amp;gt; discussions page or he must search for an alternative solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my tech blog&amp;rsquo; posts was having over 150 comments from visitors. The post is well written and has 1500 words in it. Due to a large number of comments, the visitor had to scroll down for more than 10 seconds to navigate to the footer section of my site. The footer is the important section for me because it has links to contact me, privacy policy, disclaimer pages, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W3TC W3 Total Cache vs WP Super cache : the best plugin is...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/w3tc-w3-total-cache-vs-wp-super-cache-the-best-plugin-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/w3tc-w3-total-cache-vs-wp-super-cache-the-best-plugin-is.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Caching is one of the most essential and advanced techniques for improving the performance of websites and reducing server resource usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites using this technology are fast, and they yield pretty good results when tested with GTmetrix or Pingdom tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress has been the backbone of many powerful and established websites with 1000s of posts. To make their sites more powerful, the user should install the best third party plugins (including a caching system).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working tips to Reduce CPU Usage in WordPress shared hosting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/working-tips-to-reduce-cpu-usage-in-wordpress-shared-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/working-tips-to-reduce-cpu-usage-in-wordpress-shared-hosting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shared hosting plans are relatively cheap as compared to VPS or dedicated hosting. This is because your site will be offered around 512MB RAM (or lower) and a CPU, which will be shared by many other websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites that are growing at a very fast rate should always be hosted on VPS servers (use dedicated if you require more RAM). If they&amp;rsquo;re hosted on Shared platform, their account might be suspended because of very high CPU usage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress Database plugins to optimize, clean your tables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-database-plugins-to-optimize-clean-your-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-database-plugins-to-optimize-clean-your-tables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Databases like Oracle, MySql, PostgreSQL are designed to store data of the user securely. They&amp;rsquo;re fast and highly secure. Databases are the backbone of almost all types of web applications. Due to incorrect configuration or lack of maintenance, your site or application will slow down. In severe cases, it may also crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the major multinational companies, you&amp;rsquo;ll find DB Administrators who will take care of the data. The DBA guys work in shifts so that the firm&amp;rsquo;s applications are always running. If DB server is down, the revenue will be affected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best free akismet alternatives that you are not aware of</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-free-akismet-alternatives-that-you-are-not-aware-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-free-akismet-alternatives-that-you-are-not-aware-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Akismet is no doubt one of the best plugins to avoid trackback, pingback and comment spam. It is free for WordPress sites. Paid version of this service will cost the user within 5 to 30 dollars. The pro version (security and enterprise) will give WordPress users access to the backup tool and advanced reports. They&amp;rsquo;ll also get quality support from Akismet team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you install Akismet, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to have to enter API key by creating an account on the official website of this free service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIVI Theme Review 2018 : A great Multi Purpose WordPress Template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/divi-theme-review-2018-a-great-multi-purpose-wordpress-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/divi-theme-review-2018-a-great-multi-purpose-wordpress-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elegant Themes is known for its blazing fast and highly responsive mobile friendly WordPress templates and plugins. It is the only developer that offers all its premium 50+ themes and plugins on a payment of 89 dollars. Others will charge you the same amount for a single theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The templates published by ET are updated, and they adhere to every SEO and webmaster standards that you might be aware of. They have been featured on Mashable, Smashing Magazine, and many other top blogs. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen ET plugins on high traffic blogs that have millions of page views every month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress X Theme Review 2018: Fast WP template with great features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-x-theme-review-2018-fast-wp-template-with-great-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-x-theme-review-2018-fast-wp-template-with-great-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bloggers want a lot of features in their themes. They also expect their WordPress blogs and websites to load fast. Free templates have limited support and features. Thus, many of the bloggers buy a premium template. Before they make payment, the user will explore 100s of available options. This task induces a headache and creates a lot of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, it is a job for professional and experienced bloggers like me to make newbies or WordPress users aware of the top themes. Last week, we published a detailed review of Newspaper template. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed one of the most popular and powerful WordPress theme named X. No other WP template is as perfect and user-friendly as X.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Best WordPress coupon themes (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-5-best-wordpress-coupon-themes-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-5-best-wordpress-coupon-themes-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coupon websites can be very profitable if you bring traffic to it. For example, RetailmeNot consistently earns over 100 million dollars in revenue it has millions of monthly unique visitors. It is nothing but a well-designed coupon site. Coupon Raja was bought by one of the India&amp;rsquo;s largest media hours, i.e., Times Group. Before being purchased, it had reported over five crores of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such sites, you will find short posts with an affiliate link to eCommerce portal or any other service. This post includes rating, code, social sharing links, and a small description. When the user clicks on your link and makes a purchase from the affiliate, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a commission. By the month end, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive payment via cheque, PayPal or net banking. All affiliate account include a dashboard where you can find details on the clicks, conversion rate, returns, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themeforest Newspaper WordPress Theme Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themeforest-newspaper-wordpress-theme-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themeforest-newspaper-wordpress-theme-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Newspaper themes for WordPress are recommended for technology, travel, health, news, video and sports niche blogs. There are a lot of newspaper and magazine themes available for download in the wordpress.org directory. Most of them claim to be SEO friendly but unfortunately they&amp;rsquo;re not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free themes have a major drawback that their support is limited. If you encounter any problems, you will have to post your query on WordPress.org forum. Most of the times, instead of the developers, other users will help you out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best live chat plugins for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-live-chat-plugins-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-live-chat-plugins-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Live chat system is an application that you&amp;rsquo;ll find on many websites. When a customer has some doubts about a product or a service, he can use this web-app to get his doubts cleared before making a purchase. This application is used by costumers as well as support teams at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress is a robust content management system, and you can create any website with it. Developers have published several plugins for WordPress and webmasters use live chat plugin on many business websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress sitemap plugins for better SEO (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-sitemap-plugins-for-better-seo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-sitemap-plugins-for-better-seo-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sitemap is one of the most important elements of a website. It is nothing but an XML document that features all the pages and post of your blog. It should be defined in a correct way. Failing to do so will confuse search engines and the users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users start a new blog, they should immediately create a sitemap and submit it to Google and Bing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly Speaking, these two search engines are smart, and they can determine the structure of your site without a sitemap. But you should add this document to your site as it will be useful for the users (in case they&amp;rsquo;re  looking for it).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robots.txt for WordPress : Useful tips and settings for better SEO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/robots.txt-for-wordpress-useful-tips-and-settings-for-better-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/robots.txt-for-wordpress-useful-tips-and-settings-for-better-seo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google bot and other search spiders will visit the robots.txt file of your website immediately after they hit the htaccess file. Both these files are crucial as they can affect your site&amp;rsquo;s organic presence. Htaccess has rules to block IP addresses, redirect URLs, enable gzip compression, etc. The robots.txt will have a set of rules for the search engines. It has few lines that will either block or allow crawling of files and directories. Google has been penalizing blogs with thin content. If you&amp;rsquo;re a WordPress user, you should be aware of the taxonomies of the CMS. If you have generated many tags on your site, make sure that you make then no index as they&amp;rsquo;ll cause duplicate content issues on your blog. Don&amp;rsquo;t block them in the robots.txt file if you&amp;rsquo;ve enabled tags on single posts. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do this, page rank and link juice will be wasted. No index attribute for tags can be easily added via Yoast plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Post dates : Don&#39;t be a fool to hide them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-post-dates-dont-be-a-fool-to-hide-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-post-dates-dont-be-a-fool-to-hide-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many self-proclaimed SEO experts believe that hiding WordPress date helps in improving search engine rankings. I supported their strategy until I started thinking more about user experience and rich snippets. If you&amp;rsquo;ve come across a post that claims to improve SERP position after removing dates from the blog, you&amp;rsquo;re being misled. Google knows when you&amp;rsquo;ve published a blog post through the sitemap file that has both published/modified dates. So you can&amp;rsquo;t fool it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best way to Change WP Login and admin URL in WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-change-wp-login-and-admin-url-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-change-wp-login-and-admin-url-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every content management system has a login page, and dashboard that allows bloggers and webmasters to manage the data published on their site and WordPress is no exception. This page is relevant. Thus it will always be on the attack of website hackers that may/may not use automated program to gain access to your site&amp;rsquo;s dashboard. The default slug to log in to your WordPress dashboard is wp-login.php, and every hacker and WordPress user knows it knows it. Thus if you&amp;rsquo;re using the default password or if you&amp;rsquo;re using weak login credentials, your site might get easily hacked (You can remove the default user i.e., admin through the users page in WP).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 404 errors : How to fix them easily with plugins?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-404-errors-how-to-fix-them-easily-with-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress-404-errors-how-to-fix-them-easily-with-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;404 errors in WordPress is caused when a user or a search bot is not able to find a page on your site. This page might be linked from your blog post or another website. According to Google webmaster tools, these errors won&amp;rsquo;t affect your site&amp;rsquo;s performance in the search engine, but you should try to get rid of them for a better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a lot of WordPress 404 errors can do more harm than any other factor. For example, the bounce rate will be very high as users didn&amp;rsquo;t find the page they wanted to access, they&amp;rsquo;ll hit the back button of the browser immediately without spending much time on your blog. Thus it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get rid of 404 errors. You can use the below tips and plugins for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WP super cache settings to increase website page speed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wp-super-cache-settings-to-increase-website-page-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wp-super-cache-settings-to-increase-website-page-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is my favorite CMS as you can start any site with it. I have seen classified, job posting, eCommerce, forum sites that employ WordPress content management system. As a webmaster, you must take care of your site as if it is your old dad or newborn child. To improve the performance and user experience, you should first consider improving the page load time. On WordPress site, you can easily do this by installing a caching plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best AdSense plugins for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-adsense-plugins-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-adsense-plugins-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adsense is being used on millions of blogs, and it is a source of online income for many bloggers. Have you ever wondered how the webmasters manage to add advertisements to the best and hottest positions? Most blogs are using either WordPress or Blogger CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogger comes with an inbuilt utility to insert ads in various popular areas, i.e., above, middle and below post content. On WordPress, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a PHP and HTML programmer to add Google AdSense unit to your favorite position. Simply install any of the below &lt;strong&gt;best Adsense plugins for WordPress&lt;/strong&gt; and follow its setup instructions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best author bio box plugins for WordPress (2016)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-author-bio-box-plugins-for-wordpress-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-author-bio-box-plugins-for-wordpress-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have seen author bio widget below posts on many popular blogs. Bio section is important as it makes website users aware of the writer&amp;rsquo;s skills, hobbies, experience, etc. Just like about me, disclaimer, privacy policy pages, the bio section is one of the most useful elements of a WordPress site. Most WordPress themes include the author bio box and to display your information in it, navigate to your profile page by hovering your mouse cursor over users menu (This menu appears on the left side of your WordPress dashboard). If your theme lacks this widget, make sure that you install any of the below plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy Social Share Buttons for WordPress Review (latest)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/easy-social-share-buttons-for-wordpress-review-latest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/easy-social-share-buttons-for-wordpress-review-latest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Backlinks from social networks like Facebook, Google plus, twitter, etc are nofollow. But you&amp;rsquo;ll be shocked to know that Google uses data from social networks to rank websites in the search engine regardless whether the link is dofollow or nofollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone reads and article on your site and if he/she shares it in a group/page or on his public timeline, this link will be considered as a vote of trust. Thus, if your blog articles are shared 100s of time, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that your site will rank in the 1st 2 or 3 pages of Google. Making people share content is not a piece of cake. The user will not share your blog post unless he has a reason to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best free WordPress spam blocker plugins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-spam-blocker-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-spam-blocker-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As WordPress content management system has a commenting and trackback system, it&amp;rsquo;s always on the target of spammers. Trackback links are added below the post content. A spammer who wants his website or YouTube videos to rank high in Google or Bing will drop useless comments with some URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re allowing dofollow backlinks, link juice will be transferred to the commentators website. To avoid this, install and activate the ultimate nofollow plugin on your blog. This plugin will allow you to convert all dofollow links in comments to nofollow. To block spam comments on your WordPress website, you install any of the below free plugins:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best free WordPress themes that are responsive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-themes-that-are-responsive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-free-wordpress-themes-that-are-responsive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, Google had rolled out its mobile friendly algorithm update. As a part of Google&amp;rsquo;s strategy to improve the user experience of search engine users, websites that were not having responsive design or websites whose theme was not mobile friendly were penalized. Immediately after the Google algorithm update, Bing updated its search algorithm to improve rankings of responsive and mobile friendly websites. If you&amp;rsquo;re a webmaster or a newbie blogger, you should use the below &lt;strong&gt;free themes for WordPress:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drupal-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drupal-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drupal can be installed on any number of environments, but since it was developed primarily to run on an Apache server with PHP and MySQL database, it makes sense to mimic this environment as much as possible in a development sandbox. There are LAMP applications for both Windows (WAMP / XAMP) and Mac OS (MAMP) which can serve as a Linux replacement, however recent innovations with Virtual Machines and Vagrant means that we can re-create a more native environment for development quickly and easily. Below I will describe how you can setup Drupal using some of these tools in less than 10 minutes. The Vagrant setup used here is Scotch Box. The objective is to setup a Drupal development environment with full LAMP stack capabilities including command line access and Drush integration using the native Linux file system for speed and compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commentluv review : WP plugin to increase referral traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/commentluv-review-wp-plugin-to-increase-referral-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/commentluv-review-wp-plugin-to-increase-referral-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Commentluv is a powerful WordPress plugin that comes in 2 versions – free &amp;amp; paid. The free version can be found in WordPress.org directory, and it has limited features. The premium or paid variant of CommentLuv offers many interesting and useful utilities that help a webmaster in many ways. When paid or free version of this plugin is active on a blog, visitors will be able to add any of the ten latest posts in the comments. Commentluv premium plugin maintains the number of clicks on a link generated by it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to auto generate meta description tag in WordPress blogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-auto-generate-meta-description-tag-in-wordpress-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-auto-generate-meta-description-tag-in-wordpress-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to blogging and search engine optimization, no other on-page element is as important as title and meta descriptions. According to Google webmaster guidelines, every page on a WordPress blog must have unique meta description and title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t follow this guideline, your site won&amp;rsquo;t rank well in search engines, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve verified your blog with Google Webmaster tools, you&amp;rsquo;ll see duplicate tag warning in HTML improvements section of your GWT account. Meta description is one of the most important on-page elements as it is the first thing that a search engine users see (if your site appears in the search results) when they search for some information. If you&amp;rsquo;ve not added relevant keyword and a useful short information in this tag, the user will not visit your blog. Meta description length should not be less or more than 170 characters, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be stuffed with keywords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best solution to gravatar redirect chain problem on wp blogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-solution-to-gravatar-redirect-chain-problem-on-wp-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-solution-to-gravatar-redirect-chain-problem-on-wp-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gravatar is one of the top software products of Automatic. It is used on 1000s of WordPress content management powered blogs. With this service, commentators are allowed to add their profile image that will appear alongside their comment on WordPress blogs. Gravatar is useful in many ways. It can increase user engagement on sites, and it saves a little bit of bandwidth because the commentator&amp;rsquo;s image will be served from Gravatar servers. It will also attract more comments on your blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing WordPress dashboard not working, showing up properly issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fixing-wordpress-dashboard-not-working-showing-up-properly-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fixing-wordpress-dashboard-not-working-showing-up-properly-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is no doubt better than many other blogging platforms. As it is a self-hosted CMS, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to manage the site yourself. When you encounter technical issues, you or any other person with good knowledge of PHP, WP, htaccess, CSS should solve the problem. Blogger is user-friendly but it cannot be customized as WordPress. Technical issues in Blogger platform is handled by Google engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share 3 working solutions to one of the most frustrating WordPress issue i.e. locked or slow dashboard. If your WordPress site&amp;rsquo;s dashboard is not working, loading or showing up or if it is loading slow, don&amp;rsquo;t worry! Just follow the below instructions to restore access to the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easiest way to create SEO friendly WordPress slideshows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/easiest-way-to-create-seo-friendly-wordpress-slideshows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/easiest-way-to-create-seo-friendly-wordpress-slideshows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slideshows are attractive, aren&amp;rsquo;t they? Blogs with slideshows have a very less bounce rate, high level of user engagement and better conversion rate. Many webmasters embed a picture slideshow in their sites. This makes users spend more time on the sites which in turn increases its search engine rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use an online tool to create slides, there&amp;rsquo;s no better tool than SlideShare. This tool can generate slideshow code. Thus, you can easily embed your slideshow on any blog/website. If you use this code, you will be wasting your page rank as the code will link your site to SlideShare without adding rel=&amp;ldquo;nofollow&amp;rdquo; attribute. The generated code will add an iframe to your site. Some search engines ignore the content in iframes. In such cases, you can use the best WordPress slideshow plugin, the Meta Slider. If you don&amp;rsquo;t use WordPress content management system, you can use a Jquery slideshow plugin. There are two main advantages of using the WP plugin:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Move WordPress site from one server to another with no downtime</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/move-wordpress-site-from-one-server-to-another-with-no-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/move-wordpress-site-from-one-server-to-another-with-no-downtime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to move my WordPress site from one server to another a couple of times with 0 seconds downtime and no loss of traffic. For a newbie, the transfer process can take almost an hour. For an experienced guy, the time will be reduced to 20 or 25 minutes. Migrating a WordPress site is impossible if you&amp;rsquo;re using a slow internet connection. So make sure that you&amp;rsquo;re a broadband user with a web speed of at least 1 or 2 MBPS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress security and malware removal plugins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-security-and-malware-removal-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-security-and-malware-removal-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress CMS has been prone to many online threats ever since Matt Mullenweg and the team officially launched it. The content management system is impressive, but you can’t stop hackers from attacking websites powered by WP. Attacks can be prevented by installing a WordPress security plugin. If the internet is the only source of your income, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t risk your site. There are a lot of useful web tools that can keep your website safe. The best ones are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EWWW image optimizer reduces JPG, PNG file size on WP blogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ewww-image-optimizer-reduces-jpg-png-file-size-on-wp-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ewww-image-optimizer-reduces-jpg-png-file-size-on-wp-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reducing jpg, png file size on self-hosted WordPress blogs will not only improve its load time but it will also increase the search engine rankings of your post. Google considers site speed as a ranking factor. There are two ways to reduce picture size before uploading to your blog. Install a standalone Windows or Linux software that will resize images or use a WP plugin. The 2nd option is better than the 1st. Ever since I started blogging, I used the WP-SmushIt plugin for the same. Last night, after updating the WP-smushIt plugin, I saw a message that Yahoo would be stopping its free version of WP-smushIt service and to continue using the plugin, I have to upgrade to pro version. This made me search for a WP-smushIt alternative. After doing a bit of internet research, I ended up installing EWWW. Here&amp;rsquo;s my review for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best keyword density checker for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-keyword-density-checker-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-keyword-density-checker-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My technology blog was penalized at least 4 to 5 times. In my initial days of blogging career, I was not aware of terms like keyword density, on page SEO, backlinks, etc. I indulged myself in link building activities, and I was not focused on sharing top quality content. These three blogging mistakes killed my blog&amp;rsquo;s traffic up to 70 to 80%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they say, we learn from our mistakes and hard work pays off, I worked hard for 3 to 4 months to regain the lost traffic and rectified all errors that I committed. In those four months, I removed around 400 blog posts and improved the content quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autoptimize vs Better WordPress minify plugins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/autoptimize-vs-better-wordpress-minify-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/autoptimize-vs-better-wordpress-minify-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Page load times of WordPress CMS powered blogs can decrease if webmasters start using a caching plugin. The two most widely used plugins for caching are W3TC and WordPress super cache. These 2 plugins create static HTML files from all of your blog posts and it saves these files to the cache folder on a disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress saves blog posts in database tables. When a search engine or a visitor requests it via permalink, WordPress loads the post from the database and it renders it as an HTML file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Wordpress Related Posts Plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-related-posts-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-related-posts-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Related posts plugins on blogs are useful in many ways. All blogs powered with WordPress content management system use them. They improve the internal linking structure of your website. They also help in reducing bounce rate of a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These plugins can be configured to show related posts on the sidebar as a widget. They can show relevant posts above or below a blog post with or without shortcodes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging since the year 2013, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used these below best Wordpress related posts plugins on my blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress social media plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-social-media-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-social-media-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time when search engines like MSN, Bing, Yahoo, and Google were considered as the only source of website traffic. Now things have changed a lot. Social network sites like FB, Twitter, Google+ are used by billions of people across the world. When you have a good audience on sites like Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus, Instagram, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to depend on search engines for website traffic. Blogs are probably incomplete without a social media plugin. These plugins make sharing of blog posts easier for visitors. Almost all websites (excluding social network sites) have such plugins installed on their website. Below are the three main advantages of these plugins:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working tricks to reduce bandwidth usage for a site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/working-tricks-to-reduce-bandwidth-usage-for-a-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/working-tricks-to-reduce-bandwidth-usage-for-a-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for a limited hosting limited plan, then follow the below tricks/methods to reduce the bandwidth usage for your site. I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully implemented the below tricks in one of my site, and the bandwidth usage has reduced by 25 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reduce-image-size&#34;&gt;Reduce Image size&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using large images of a site can kill hosting bandwidth within a week unless you&amp;rsquo;re signed up for an unlimited hosting plan. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a content management system like WordPress, plugins like EWWW Image Optimizer or WP Smush it can take care of pictures you upload. If you&amp;rsquo;ve developed your site from scratch, then you should use Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s smushit online tool. The tool will reduce image size without affecting its quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockville Drupal Meetup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rockville-drupal-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rockville-drupal-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a Drupal developer or someone who is interested in learning or hearing more about the platform?  Each month there are various &amp;lsquo;meet-ups&amp;rsquo; that take place across the area.  ICF International now co-sponsors two of these meet-ups, one is held in our Fairfax office and the other in Rockville.  Last night we held our first Rockville meet-up, which was a big success. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
