<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Creative on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/creative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creative on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/creative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adobe&#39;s Secrets Revealed for New Creative Suite 5</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been quite a few videos in regards to the new Adobe Creative Suite 5, most specifically Photoshop and design software. There have been a lot of updates from the not-so-old CS4 set of Web and Graphic design software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Float Launches their Inspiration Blog with New Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design Float is one of the top social news sites for web design and graphics articles. Having been online for almost 2 years now, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk and hype about the site which has contributed to its popularity. However over the past few weeks, the owner of DF has begun to post again on the Design Float Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digzign - New Social News for Designers that Dig</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social news has sprung along the web, and with the popularity of web design and graphics blogs sharing links has become commonplace. With popular sites such as DesignFloat and DesignBump, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine much else. However I have recently found a great-looking Digg clone website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://digzign.com/&#34;&gt;http://digzign.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Martin Leblanc Eigtved, Founder of IconFinder.net</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-martin-leblanc-eigtved-founder-of-iconfinder.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-martin-leblanc-eigtved-founder-of-iconfinder.net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many design blogs and showcases today are giving away icons for free. Even in large sets, social media icons and small graphics are making their way into the big time. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of collecting icons, and all of these free sites are extremely useful and always in my bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Web&#39;s Cutest URL Shortening Service Moourl.com</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I know, I&amp;rsquo;m a guy and the word &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in my vocabulary. Well if I ever needed to use the word cute to describe anything, it would have to be moourl.com. It&amp;rsquo;s a URL shortening service with an actually &lt;em&gt;bearable&lt;/em&gt; design to it. Beautiful vectors and color scheme, I love the site!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CollegeHumor&#39;s Designer Anna Hiort</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten my fair share of laughs from all of the hilarious content on the internet today. Photoshopped photos and amazing/retarded videos are spread like wildfire through forums and social networking sites. However, one of the best sites I&amp;rsquo;ve ever run across for generally hilarious content has to be Collegehumor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrazyLeaf Design Blog - Inspiration and Resources for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/crazyleaf-design-blog-inspiration-and-resources-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/crazyleaf-design-blog-inspiration-and-resources-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web designers can spend hours looking for inspiration. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, up at 1 in the morning trying to work out a project you&amp;rsquo;ve got lined up but nothing seems to be hitting you. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m at a design roadblock I usually turn to typical web design blogs to get the juices flowing again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Your Music Anywhere with MeCanto</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/listen-to-your-music-anywhere-with-mecanto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/listen-to-your-music-anywhere-with-mecanto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to carry your music library on an iPod or MP3 player has revolutionized how we listen to music. It&amp;rsquo;s allowed us to bring our favorite songs anywhere we go, keep us busy when waiting on appointments, and share some of our favorite music with friends. However, with MeCanto you can now bring your entire music library anywhere you can get an internet collection - that&amp;rsquo;s practically anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Steven Snell of DesignM.ag</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Website Design has become one of the most popular career paths, especially with many teenagers taking entry-level classes in high school, and with so many available resources to learn from. There are tons of web design blogs, galleries, news sites, and much more. However, there are only a select few that actually post up quality content, update frequently, and are run my professional web designers who can teach us all a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Express your 3D Avatars with Frenzoo</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating your own avatar online has become a popular trend. Everybody wants to have their own personal expression to make them stand out from the crowd. There is a different type of communication over the internet, and you need something to make yourself stand out next to everyone else. Most people have unique username&amp;rsquo;s on websites, but avatars are a great way to stand out with style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
