<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Web-Design on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/web-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web-Design on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/web-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Inside The Webb Layout with Genesis</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-inside-the-webb-layout-with-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-inside-the-webb-layout-with-genesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since the last major update to Inside The Webb, so I am pleased to post that today I completed customization of the new site layout using Studiopress Genesis Wordpress theme framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreshWebJobs: A Unique Job Board for Web Designers &amp;amp; Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back a few years ago I used to work full-time freelance web design. It&amp;rsquo;s a tiring job, and many people who can do it today earn a lot of money working for themselves in the trade. Web professionals are always in demand, but it&amp;rsquo;s difficult at times to find good web projects. Freshwebjobs.com changes all that with professional listings to pair up webmasters and developers to those looking into projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional XHTML/CSS Slicing Company Slicejack</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSD Conversion is a very high-paying business. Many amazing designers know how to work through Photoshop but just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or haven&amp;rsquo;t learned how to code their designs into XHTML and CSS code. This is where many popular companies come in to help, the most popular being psd2html.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional Freelance Web Designer Shay Howe</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the fastest growing professions is website design and web developers, especially with the attraction of working freelance. Many people hate the 9-5 grind induced through corporate America, and having the option to work from home on your own time seems like a much more viable and interesting option to many. Although in the end it may require a bit more work on your end, the ultimate freedom of your time seems to pay for itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Successful Design Blog: Lessons from Web Designer Depot</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs are the new in, everybody who is interested in making money online and knows any amount about web design is starting their own blog. Granted only a few have made it and gained star-status in the blogosphere, but there are thousands of others who struggle to build their way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with PSDFan&#39;s Designer and Blogger Tom Ross</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-psdfans-designer-and-blogger-tom-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-psdfans-designer-and-blogger-tom-ross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding good tutorials on web design and development can be tough these days. Although so many people have and use Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and all of the creative suite, there are very few that know how to utilize the tools properly and create astounding designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CollegeHumor&#39;s Designer Anna Hiort</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten my fair share of laughs from all of the hilarious content on the internet today. Photoshopped photos and amazing/retarded videos are spread like wildfire through forums and social networking sites. However, one of the best sites I&amp;rsquo;ve ever run across for generally hilarious content has to be Collegehumor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside FudgeGraphics: Web Design Freebies and Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-fudgegraphics-web-design-freebies-and-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-fudgegraphics-web-design-freebies-and-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: we all love free stuff. As web designers, graphic designers, PHP programmers, or AJAX gurus we all love finding free code snippits or templates to work with. I have recently found a great new web design and development-focused blog Fudgegraphics which is full of all the freebies any web designer could want!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Blog.SpoonGraphics with Creator Chris Spooner</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personally one of my favorite graphic design blogs on the web, Blog.Spoongraphics provides amazing resources, tutorials, and tips for graphic and web designers everywhere. The creator and designer of the blog Chris Spooner is also a freelance web designer himself, and I landed a great interview with him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Designer and Blogger Andrew Houle of MyInkBlog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/graphic-designer-and-blogger-andrew-houle-of-myinkblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/graphic-designer-and-blogger-andrew-houle-of-myinkblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Graphic and web designers, lend me your ears! We have another great graphic design blog to add to our list today, MyInkBlog. Featuring all sorts of free goodies to download, amazing tutorials, inspiring articles, and a whole lot more! MyInkBlog is one of the premiere graphic and web design blogs on the web, with over 3,000 Twitter followers and almost 4,000 RSS followers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Web Design Dev with Creator Michael Dunlop</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-web-design-dev-with-creator-michael-dunlop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-web-design-dev-with-creator-michael-dunlop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Dunlop is what you could call an &amp;ldquo;internet marketer&amp;rdquo;, making enough money online to provide a livable income since he was in college. Since he has started in internet marketing, Michael has created a slew of websites, one of which is a very popular website design blog. Web Design Dev posts up large collections of lists, tools, tricks, and tutorials to help beginning and professional web designers alike to find the best resources on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Digg-Clone for Designers DesignBump</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg was the first social news site to really skyrocket into popularity, gaining millions of pageviews a day to the site. No doubt, there would be similar sites in separate niches on the web. The first of these niche sites in the web design category was Design Float, which has had many issues with databases and keeping the site up and running properly. Therefore, a new competitor has stepped up to the plate: DesignBump.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Steven Snell of DesignM.ag</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Website Design has become one of the most popular career paths, especially with many teenagers taking entry-level classes in high school, and with so many available resources to learn from. There are tons of web design blogs, galleries, news sites, and much more. However, there are only a select few that actually post up quality content, update frequently, and are run my professional web designers who can teach us all a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
