<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Typography on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/typography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typography on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/typography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best way to add Google Fonts to WordPress website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-add-google-fonts-to-wordpress-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-add-google-fonts-to-wordpress-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The font is one of the most critical elements on a website. Developers make sure that the typography of their website is best in class. If your visitor finds that your site is ugly, he&amp;rsquo;ll leave it immediately without reading the content or making a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 100s of fonts that you can use for free, but you will have to spend a lot of time in searching for them unless you use Google web fonts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Vibrant and Inspiring Design Blog ilovecolors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most graphic design blogs today can serve as a source of inspiration and creativity. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a fantastic design blog covering everything from Photoshop to Typography. ilovecolors is a fantastic blog run by Elio Rivero, and I was lucky enough to get a behind-the-scenes interview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Little Box of Ideas Design Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much alike many designers out there, I&amp;rsquo;m constantly craving new graphic design inspiration, web design galleries, and everything the life of a designer should be filled to the brim with. This leads me on my quest of finding the best design blogs out on the internetz, and my interview today is no shortage. Little Box of Ideas is a great design and creativity blog, focusing on great topics such as graphics tutorials and typography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
