<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Artistic on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/artistic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artistic on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/artistic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Vibrant and Inspiring Design Blog ilovecolors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most graphic design blogs today can serve as a source of inspiration and creativity. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a fantastic design blog covering everything from Photoshop to Typography. ilovecolors is a fantastic blog run by Elio Rivero, and I was lucky enough to get a behind-the-scenes interview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Blog.SpoonGraphics with Creator Chris Spooner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personally one of my favorite graphic design blogs on the web, Blog.Spoongraphics provides amazing resources, tutorials, and tips for graphic and web designers everywhere. The creator and designer of the blog Chris Spooner is also a freelance web designer himself, and I landed a great interview with him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Colorburned with Designer Grant Friedman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/getting-inside-colorburned-with-designer-grant-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/getting-inside-colorburned-with-designer-grant-friedman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a large collection of design blogs leaves your options open to so much. You can find original content very quickly, learn a lot more through tutorials and freebies, and also get to know a lot of people in the design community. Colorburned is another very popular and well-respected graphic design blog which features some of the best design news, resources, and tutorials from around the web. This can include free textures, patterns, Photoshop brushes, tutorials, and a whole lot more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Indaba Music: The Online Music-Making Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-indaba-music-the-online-music-making-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-indaba-music-the-online-music-making-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a musician looking to find others to jam with, write music with, or just talk to? Or maybe you have a band, but want to find others who are writing the same kind of stuff? Yeah, listen to their tunes, kick back, maybe even share some wisdom with each other. Well look no further, as Indaba Music can cure all your problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Express your 3D Avatars with Frenzoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating your own avatar online has become a popular trend. Everybody wants to have their own personal expression to make them stand out from the crowd. There is a different type of communication over the internet, and you need something to make yourself stand out next to everyone else. Most people have unique username&amp;rsquo;s on websites, but avatars are a great way to stand out with style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
