<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Amazon on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/amazon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amazon on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/amazon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Highest paying affiliate programs (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/highest-paying-affiliate-programs-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/highest-paying-affiliate-programs-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Affiliate programs are great alternatives to PPC and CPC networks. Once you join an AP, you&amp;rsquo;ll get access to tools that will allow you to build affiliate links. A webmaster/website owner must use the tool to generate affiliate links. Once you generate a link, paste it into the blog posts. When a visitor clicks the link and buys a product from a website, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To know how your site is performing and which URLs on your website are giving you leads, the affiliate programs features a reporting section. There are 1000s of affiliate programs, but the ones that pay affiliates the highest commission fee are mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates Link Builder plugin for WordPress now available</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-link-builder-plugin-for-wordpress-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-link-builder-plugin-for-wordpress-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular affiliate program. Until December 2016, the user had to place affiliate URLs manually in the blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manual method of inserting affiliate URLs in the blog post is cumbersome. The user should first create affiliate link using the Amazon Site Stripe tool or with the AA dashboard. Then, they must use the WordPess post editor to insert the affiliate URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon, for the first time, has introduced a WordPress plugin that lets users find products on Amazon and create affiliate links for them from the WordPress dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdSense vs Affiliate Marketing : The best monetization technique is...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/adsense-vs-affiliate-marketing-the-best-monetization-technique-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/adsense-vs-affiliate-marketing-the-best-monetization-technique-is.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People join affiliate programs or signup for AdSense to earn money online. In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering which monetization technique you should implement on your blog, go through the following 6 to 7 paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adsense-or-affiliate-marketing--which-is-better&#34;&gt;AdSense or Affiliate Marketing : Which is better?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AdSense is the world&amp;rsquo;s best CPC network. It has the highest CPC rates. AdWords is the backbone of AdSense. It has a large number of advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you become a part of AdSense program, you have to place an ad code on your website in accordance with the AdSense terms and conditions. You can get the ad code from your AdSense dashboard. AdSense provides various types of ad formats&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to increase Amazon Affiliate sales?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-increase-amazon-affiliate-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-increase-amazon-affiliate-sales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Associates affiliate program is one of the most important sources of revenue for many bloggers. If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to earn money from Amazon, follow the below tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;effective-tips-to-increase-amazon-affiliatesales&#34;&gt;Effective tips to increase Amazon affiliate sales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;send-more-traffic&#34;&gt;Send more traffic:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is counted among the most trusted brands in the world. It has listings of more than a million products. The products include household items, accessories for mobile devices, cameras, etc. They have a competitive price tag due to which people don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate in buying expensive or inexpensive stuff from Amazon. Hence, the more traffic you send to Amazon, the higher will be the conversions. I can say this from my personal experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Affiliate Link Cloaker Plugin for Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-affiliate-link-cloaker-plugin-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-affiliate-link-cloaker-plugin-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Affiliate links are ugly and long. When the user hovers your mouse on an affiliate link and finds your tracking code in the URL, he may not click the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a seasoned webmaster, you should use a plugin to create and manage affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoCodes was one of the best affiliate link Cloaker plugins. I was using it until I update the PHP on my VPS server. Unfortunately, the plugin has become useless because it has not been updated for 2 years. GoCodes will not work on sites using the latest version of PHP because several functions that GoCodes uses have been deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon associates affiliate program tips for 100% success</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-affiliate-program-tips-for-100-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/amazon-associates-affiliate-program-tips-for-100-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warren buffet says that you should not depend on a single source of income. This statement from the US-based Billionaire and one of the richest man in the world is brilliant and it makes sense in many ways. If you’re a blogger, go through the below article to know why the statement from Warren Buffet is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many online sources that can generate revenue from a blog. Google AdSense is at the top. If you own a technology blog, you can start earning money by registering an affiliate account with eCommerce sites. Most of these sites will accept you into their affiliate program in a couple of days. But to achieve success with them, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow some genuine tips. This article will reveal tips that I follow. I&amp;rsquo;m using amazon, Flipkart and SnapDeal affiliate links on one of my site along with Adsense. Thus, I make a fair income working from the comfort of my home. Amazon is the best affiliate network for technology niche blogs. It has the highest commission rates. It was initially difficult for me to make money with the affiliate networks as I was a newbie or a beginner. But now, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my earnings. Anyways, here are the tips that you should follow. Please note that you use the below tips for any affiliate network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
