<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Image on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/image/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Image on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/image/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Latest Free Icon Search Engine FindIcons.com</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-latest-free-icon-search-engine-findicons.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-latest-free-icon-search-engine-findicons.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a few weeks ago I got a great interview with the creator of IconFinder.net, one of the only free icon search engines online. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve come across another one which has just as many great icons shared, plus the ability to log in and save your favorite sets!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Express your 3D Avatars with Frenzoo</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating your own avatar online has become a popular trend. Everybody wants to have their own personal expression to make them stand out from the crowd. There is a different type of communication over the internet, and you need something to make yourself stand out next to everyone else. Most people have unique username&amp;rsquo;s on websites, but avatars are a great way to stand out with style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Display Your High-Resolution Photos Online with ClosR.it</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/display-your-high-resolution-photos-online-with-closr.it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/display-your-high-resolution-photos-online-with-closr.it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ClosR.it is another great web 2.0 application I stumbled upon while browsing the net. It allows photo enthusiasts, designers, professional photographers, and really anyone who takes pictures to upload their photos in high-resolution. The problem with many other image hosting services is that they cap limits on the site of the photos, or just re-size them. ClosR.it allows full HD image views, perfect to share with all of your photo-enthusiastic friends and family!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
