<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Competitor-Analysis on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/competitor-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competitor-Analysis on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/competitor-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best tools to check Google keyword rankings for a website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once your website starts ranking in search engines, you should check its Google keyword rankings often. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, competitors may steal your keywords and use them on their portals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website with high domain authority won&amp;rsquo;t be affected by this. But if a site is new, competitor stealing your major keywords may have a negative impact on your website traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some of the best free tools to check website ranking in Google search engine. Most of the tools covered in this blog post won&amp;rsquo;t ask you to create an account. Nor they&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to enter credit or debit card details. Apart from free tools, we&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned a powerful premium SEO tool that provides plenty of useful SEO tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Website Traffic Free Online with these awesome tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website visit you visit uses an analytics tool to track visitors and their activity. Only the organization that own its will have access to the tracking data. The company doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to make their data public unless they&amp;rsquo;re generating advertising revenue from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people using the internet are always curious to know how much traffic does their favorite website get. But as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned earlier, the real data is with the site&amp;rsquo;s owner. Thus, no matter what tool you use, you cannot get the exact statistics of a website traffic unless the company decides to share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and Best SEO tools that every webmaster should use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization aka SEO is one of the most important topics of discussion in the online world. Without following the right guidelines and SEO tips, it will be tough to survive as a blogger or a webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use search engines and Facebook more than any other website. Promoting a product on Facebook is not free. If you want to do this without any costs, you will have to build a large community and huge fan following. Search engines like Google are powerful and every major or minor website is indexed by them. It indexes your site without any costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEMRush Free Trial account : Find Competitor Keywords and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professional bloggers are successful because they make wise use of SEO tools. For example, Pat Flynn, the owner of smart passive income has launched a few niche blogs that earn him over 5000 dollars every month. Patt is one of the most intelligent bloggers in the world. He makes more than 50000 dollars every month by promoting various products. He makes use of different keyword research tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amit Agarwal, the top Indian blogger, initially used Google Keyword Planner to find relevant and high traffic keywords, as a result, his blog labnol generates more 2.5 million INR revenue through AdSense. Most of the articles on his site labnol.org rank on 1st page of Google.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
