<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nginx on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nginx on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nginx gzip_static: What it does and how to use it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nginx-gzip_static-what-it-does-and-how-to-use-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nginx-gzip_static-what-it-does-and-how-to-use-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;NGINX logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/nginx-gzip_static-what-it-does-and-how-to-use-it/images/NGINX-logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other top web servers, Nginx lets webmasters enable Gzip compression for their websites. It can compress scripts and stylesheets in a web page on the fly. The Gzip file&amp;rsquo;s size is significantly lower than the original file. Nginx supports 9 Gzip compression levels.1 is the lowest and 9 is the highest. To gzip a file, Nginx will use invoke a function and the function will use system resources during the file conversion process. The function will take few milliseconds to execute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to move or renew LetsEncrypt SSL certificate manually?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-move-or-renew-letsencrypt-ssl-certificate-manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-move-or-renew-letsencrypt-ssl-certificate-manually/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my earlier blog post, I am using LetsEncrypt free SSL certificate on one of my sites. The certificate was due to expire in few weeks. The CertBot dispatched an alert message for the same on my official email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m using SSL for the first time and having several doubts in mind, I decided to renew LetsEncrypt certificate immediately. I fired the following command in the Linux terminal (10 days prior the certificate&amp;rsquo;s expiry date) and restarted Nginx.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix logrotate not working problem?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-logrotate-not-working-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-logrotate-not-working-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your app is appending the errors and website visitor&amp;rsquo;s IP address, browser data, etc to a log file, you should manually archive old log files or use Logrotate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, the server will run out of storage memory and your application may crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logrotate is a powerful program that archives and removes old log files. It saves heaps of storage memory by automatically compressing log files generated by Apache, NGINX, MySQL, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fix No space left on device error while reading upstream in Nginx</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-no-space-left-on-device-error-while-reading-upstream-in-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-no-space-left-on-device-error-while-reading-upstream-in-nginx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nginx is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most powerful web servers. It has a robust caching system which eliminates the need for optimizing websites with third-party caching solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While managing your website, you may come across the strange error called No Space Left on Device while reading upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t know that Nginx is throwing the &amp;ldquo;No Space Left error&amp;rdquo; until you check the HTTP response header or go through the log files. To see the response header, install the Redirect Path Chrome extension or use the online redirect checker tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Nginx and Apache access log and error log files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/analyzing-nginx-and-apache-access-log-and-error-log-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/analyzing-nginx-and-apache-access-log-and-error-log-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A log file generated by a web/database server is one of the most important files. It contains useful information on visitors, errors, warnings, etc. Some people think log files as server resource killer. Hence, they disable them in Apache, DB or NGINX configuration file. One more reason why people disable or ignore server logs is because the content of logs is difficult to understand. Hence, most noob webmasters use a log file analyzer program to check server logs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Nginx PHP-FPM MySQL (MariaDB) stack for Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-nginx-php-fpm-mysql-mariadb-stack-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-nginx-php-fpm-mysql-mariadb-stack-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I own a laptop which has a dedicated graphics card. I am a developer who prefers using Linux OS. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried 3 distros of Linux, Mint, Ubuntu, OpenSuse. No matter what version of Linux I use, the OS fails to recognize the AMD graphics card in my laptop and the WiFi connection always drops. I fixed the WiFi issue by upgrading the driver but the GPU installation always fails. Hence, I decided to give up using Linux and stick with Windows 10 OS for development tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix 403 forbidden error in Nginx?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-403-forbidden-error-in-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-403-forbidden-error-in-nginx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;403 access forbidden error message is displayed on the browser when you try to open a file whose public access has been blocked by the webmaster or because of a permission problem. In other words, the web server is saying that you are not allowed to view the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a webmaster (blogger) and if you&amp;rsquo;re facing this issue, then it &amp;rsquo;s obvious that you don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in web server configuration and management. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing to be ashamed of. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand these two issues in detail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
