<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hostgator on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/hostgator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hostgator on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/hostgator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Hostgator Black Friday 2016 discount - best deal of the year</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/get-hostgator-black-friday-2016-discount-best-deal-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/get-hostgator-black-friday-2016-discount-best-deal-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a newbie blogger, I kept changing my hosting provider until I signed up for HostGator. To be honest, I had faced a hard time in finding the best hosting provider for my website. To help you out in choosing the best themes and plugins, I have shared the list of WordPress Black Friday deals. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a special Hostgator deal, with which you can get flat 65% off on any hosting of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justhost vs Hostgator Comparison (March 2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/justhost-vs-hostgator-comparison-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/justhost-vs-hostgator-comparison-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many people shortlist Hostgator and Justhost for their new WordPress blog or website. But they are unsure about the hosting company they should signup for. For such people, today we have shared a detailed comparison of Justhost and Hostgator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endurance International Group owns Hostgator as well Justhost. The two shared hosting providers might be owned by the same company, but the infrastructure and services offered by HG &amp;amp; JH are different. Check the below comparison to understand the difference between the features and services offered by the two organisations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HostGator Review 2018 : Powerful servers and great uptime</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/hostgator-review-2018-powerful-servers-and-great-uptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/hostgator-review-2018-powerful-servers-and-great-uptime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the 1st of April might have been the best day for you but it was an awful day for me. My top site, which generates a decent income was down for nearly 4 hours in the daytime. The site was not accessible to 100s of search engine users from 12:30 PM to 4:20 PM. The downtime was due to a network issue and misconfiguration by ASO staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network issue started around 12:30 PM and it was resolved after 45 minutes. The staff moved the affected domains to a new IP address but the mapping was not correct. So from 1:00 PM onwards, the homepage of my blog was being redirected to some shi*t site. This resulted in 100s of 404 errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
