<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infamous Design Blog DesignM.ag Being Auctioned on Flippa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs have become the de-facto of the internet revolution over the past 2-3 years. As web design has shot off and every 16 year old and their mother has started to learn XHTML/CSS, blogging about it has just become another step in the process. DesignM.ag is one of the most popular, sharing free tutorials and graphics frequently in their posts. As of April 5 the site has been put up for auction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing DesignMoo for Social Media Traffic to your Design Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all of you running a design blog out there, DesignMoo is a site you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to bookmark. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all know of Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity, this has caused many smaller sites to spawn offspring and grow into micro-niche Digg sites. DesignMoo is one of these style of sites for graphic and web design, and can bring in a lot of traffic to your blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Information and Photo now Displayed After each Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep, I finally decided to add some of those updates I had planned on rolling out so long ago! I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to add author info to the posts on Inside the Webb for a while, just haven&amp;rsquo;t had time. Well I finally found some time, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Your Compete Rank can Directly Affect your Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-your-compete-rank-can-directly-affect-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-your-compete-rank-can-directly-affect-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mostly all internet marketers are aware of what Google&amp;rsquo;s PageRank is. Ranking pages on a scale of 0-10 based on the amount of backlinks, and the quality of those links. Compete works in a very similar way to Alexa, where it ranks different site&amp;rsquo;s positions in the grand scheme of thinks. Now with Alexa Ranking the lower the better, and the same goes for Compete Ranking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Profitable are Niche Video Game Forums and Communities?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of the web 2.0 boom is communication. People are communicating now more than ever, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise. With the vast size of apps these days, along with almost every website running some type of forum or blog, users are more connected than ever! Many marketers can see ways to utilizing this new &amp;ldquo;social networking fever&amp;rdquo; as a turning point to make some serious money online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Vibrant and Inspiring Design Blog ilovecolors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most graphic design blogs today can serve as a source of inspiration and creativity. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a fantastic design blog covering everything from Photoshop to Typography. ilovecolors is a fantastic blog run by Elio Rivero, and I was lucky enough to get a behind-the-scenes interview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Creativity Den: New Inspiration Blog for Designers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/getting-inside-creativity-den-new-inspiration-blog-for-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/getting-inside-creativity-den-new-inspiration-blog-for-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web designers have no shortage of inspiration these days. It seems as though there are new design and inspiration blogs popping up every hour, and there&amp;rsquo;s never a shortage of posts to go around. With new social media sites such as Design Moo and DesignBump, articles for graphic artists and web designers are able to spread like wildfire. It&amp;rsquo;s rare when you run across a unique and helpful blog, and this is the case with CreativityDen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Webb is back with a New Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-the-webb-is-back-with-a-new-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-the-webb-is-back-with-a-new-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So yes, there haven&amp;rsquo;t been many updates here at Inside the Webb in the past few months. However, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a whole new batch of great interviews, reviews, and demos of the latest and greatest web 2.0 apps across the internet! We&amp;rsquo;ve launched with a brand new design and look, and we&amp;rsquo;re back to claim all web 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Successful Design Blog: Lessons from Web Designer Depot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs are the new in, everybody who is interested in making money online and knows any amount about web design is starting their own blog. Granted only a few have made it and gained star-status in the blogosphere, but there are thousands of others who struggle to build their way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
