<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Csec-620 on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/csec-620/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Csec-620 on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/csec-620/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Piracy on an International Scale</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/software-piracy-on-an-international-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/software-piracy-on-an-international-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Copyright has become a huge issue and talking point recently with continual legal challenges, the introduction and defeat of the Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA) and considerations for future legislation, challenges and controversy.  The United States leads the world in having some of the toughest copyright laws on the books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Monitoring and Blocking Software</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/workplace-monitoring-and-blocking-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/workplace-monitoring-and-blocking-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software monitoring and blocking tools have become commonplace within the work environment and have been used in order to protect company intellectual assets from employees who either deliberately or accidentely become the cause of security issues. In addition to this, one of the main arguments for such tools is the idea that they increase employee productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing, Copyright and Legal Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/3d-printing-copyright-and-legal-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/3d-printing-copyright-and-legal-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the 1980s the role playing games like Dungeons and Dragons saw the rise in popularity of model or figurine molds, which essentially allowed players to create character’s using casting kits.  These were in effect a very early day version of 3D printing, which has introduced the production of physical objects in the home.  3D printing has become more sophisticated in recent years and with that, the overall costs have decreased dramatically to the point where they are becoming widespread. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation vs Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/regulation-vs-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/regulation-vs-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the ongoing discussions in the United States focuses on the need for regulation versus the need to free business from restrictive laws that would hinder innovation.  There are many sources that provide strong arguments for both sides.  You only have to look as far as the current state of patent regulations and recent lawsuits involving tech giants Samsung and Apple to see the impact these laws make within the industry. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Theft and Inexperienced Internet Users</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/identity-theft-and-inexperienced-internet-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/identity-theft-and-inexperienced-internet-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identity theft has been a growing concern over the last decade.  In recent years it has become a major problem for many as the Internet has taken over much of the day to day banking many traditionally did at their physical located branches.  Is there however a bigger concern with less knowledgeable and inexperienced Internet users, and are these users at a higher risk of becoming victims of identity theft? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Anonymity: Good or Bad?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/online-anonymity-good-or-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/online-anonymity-good-or-bad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anonymity on the Internet provides an important layer of protection for people to express themselves online, while keeping their real life identity private.  It has led to both positive as well as negative implications over the years and there has been much discussion on the benefits and drawbacks on both sides. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financial Sector Cybersecurity Regulations</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/financial-sector-cybersecurity-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/financial-sector-cybersecurity-regulations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Bidgoli, 2006) describes the statutory approach in the United States as being sectorial in nature “because the laws are drawn along industry lines.” This contrasts other parts of the world, such as the European Union, which has a non-sectorial approach where, for example a comprehensive privacy law applies to all organizations regardless of their industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacktivism, Anonymous, and the Bureau of Justice Statistics</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/hacktivism-anonymous-and-the-bureau-of-justice-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/hacktivism-anonymous-and-the-bureau-of-justice-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years news stories have highlighted the increasing rate of cybercriminal activity targeting both private organizations and government entities. Cases from mischievous amateur hackers managing to exploit basic vulnerabilities, to more advanced security breaches carried out by expert criminal hackers and cybercrime organizations overseas, have grabbed the attention of the media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Cybersecurity Policies in the Private and Public Sector</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-cybersecurity-policies-in-the-private-and-public-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-cybersecurity-policies-in-the-private-and-public-sector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“We are moving into a new era of mobile computing, one that promises greater variety in applications highly improved usability, and speedier networking.” Godwin-Jones (2008). This statement rings true for the past five years where mobile computing has seen a massive explosion in growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacking as an Addiction</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/hacking-as-an-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/hacking-as-an-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hacking can be broken into several categories, including criminal hacking where the perpetrator is motivated by some tangible gain, usually monetary.  There are other forms of hacking which are driven by other factors such as political reasons. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivation and Intent of Hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/motivation-and-intent-of-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/motivation-and-intent-of-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just over a decade ago I began learning about web technologies and found myself learning basic HTML.  I was excited when I managed to publish my first website, which was no more than a basic homepage with some external links. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical vs Non-Ethical Hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/ethical-vs-non-ethical-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/ethical-vs-non-ethical-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In their paper on understanding risks associated with hackers/crackers, (Smith, &amp;amp; Rupp 2002) discuss the various types of classification hackers have been placed into by different authors over the years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Mandiant Report Raise Public Awareness?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/will-the-mandiant-report-raise-public-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/will-the-mandiant-report-raise-public-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mandiant report: APT1: Exposing One of China&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Espionage Units, has stirred up a lot of media attention over the past few weeks.  The report was originally released to show evidence that a specific Chinese military unit has been behind many major Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs) within the United States. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Security</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Underlying vulnerabilities in mobile device software has also opened up the door to potential security breaches.  In an article describing mobile application security flaws, (Westervelt, 2010) wrote that it was discovered that many mobile application security vulnerabilities were similar to those found in early web applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One audit standard fits all?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/one-audit-standard-fits-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/one-audit-standard-fits-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer applications are constantly evolving; while web based systems continue to grow in complexity.  It is essential that these systems are properly secured both at the server level as well as at the code or application level, therefore Information Systems audit standards, more specifically focused on application and development measures provide some of the most useful valuable information at an organizations disposal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Values and Moral Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cultural-values-and-moral-legitimacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cultural-values-and-moral-legitimacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a paper that discussed various cyber-crimes throughout the years carried out by juveniles, Radnofsky (2006) points us to the seriousness of these types of threats.  The paper discusses the importance of changing cyber-culture through education and points to education through safety, security and ethics. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost and Challenges with E-Government</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cost-and-challenges-with-e-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cost-and-challenges-with-e-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that E-Government provides conveniences today that many take for granted, however there is an underlying cost for these services.  First of all, government sites are attractive targets for malicious activities, whether or not this involves deliberate disruption of service, or the stealing of sensitive information for profit. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime: Law Enforcement and E-Government Transnational Issues</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cybercrime-law-enforcement-and-e-government-transnational-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cybercrime-law-enforcement-and-e-government-transnational-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During his 2013 State of the Union address, President Obama highlighted the importance of defending our nation from the many cyber threats that are continuing to dominate the news cycles. Just days prior to the President’s speech, eighteen people were charged in a massive credit card fraud ring. The Associated Press (2013) described it as a “sprawling international scam that duped credit-rating agencies” by using stolen identities of individual victims to steal $200 million.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Policies</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/security-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/security-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bosworth et al (2009) stress the importance of formality that should be adopted when creating an ethics policy.  They emphasize that clear documentation, clear motivation, clear sanctions, and clear management support at every level, including the top, are all important pieces of an effective policy. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks, Threats and Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/risks-threats-and-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/risks-threats-and-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to SANS (2009) attacks against websites and web applications constitute more than 60% of total attacks observed on the internet.  The risk of attack is generally based on the probability that a threat of some kind will exploit a vulnerability or weakness in a system or network.  In recent years risks have been taken more seriously with many businesses that conduct online activities. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime vs Traditional Crime</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cybercrime-vs-traditional-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cybercrime-vs-traditional-crime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Eighteen people were charged in what may be one of the nation&amp;rsquo;s largest credit card fraud rings, a sprawling international scam that duped credit-rating agencies and used thousands of fake identities to steal at least $200 million, federal authorities said Tuesday.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges Policy Makers face to Counter Cybercrime</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/challenges-policy-makers-face-to-counter-cybercrime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/challenges-policy-makers-face-to-counter-cybercrime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pfleeger (2005) reminds us that modern cyber-criminals can often be individuals that are difficult to detect.  They “wear business suits, have university degrees, and appear to be pillars of their communities.”  In addition to this, because of the wide spread accessibility to the internet and communications, it makes it easier for these criminals to operate in groups spread across the globe.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
