<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social-Networks on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/social-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social-Networks on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/social-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Marketplace vs Craigslist: Which site is better?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/facebook-marketplace-vs-craigslist-which-site-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/facebook-marketplace-vs-craigslist-which-site-is-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After destroying MySpace, Orkut, Flickr and several other internet companies. FB is now after Craigslist, Olx, Kijiji, and 100s of other classified listing sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social networking giant opened its marketplace for everyone using FB. The new feature has not gone well with people using this site just for fun. But it has been received well by business owners using Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is FB&amp;rsquo;s new tool a great alternative to OLX, CL, and other similar websites? Go through the below comparison of the two sites to get the answer!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revive Old Post WordPress plugin review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/revive-old-post-wordpress-plugin-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/revive-old-post-wordpress-plugin-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike search engines that rank pages on the basis of various factors, Social networking portals display posts in groups and on pages in first-in-last-out order. If the page is old, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to scroll down the group until you find it. If the title of the post is interesting, people will share the post on their profiles or in groups they&amp;rsquo;ve joined. Such pages are called viral posts. They have the potential of bringing a large amount of traffic to a website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Viral WordPress themes 2018 : Responsive, fast &amp; feature packed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-feature-packed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-feature-packed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A viral theme is one which helps website owners in garnering tons of traffic from social networks such as Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, etc. It should have excellent layout and beautiful social network icons. The icons in a viral WordPress theme must be placed at the best position so as to increase the chances of a visitor sharing the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to launch a viral WordPress site and looking for a good theme which above mentioned features, consider using the following templates:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Viral WordPress themes 2018 : Responsive, fast &amp;amp; feature packed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-amp-feature-packed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-viral-wordpress-themes-2018-responsive-fast-amp-feature-packed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A viral theme is one which helps website owners in garnering tons of traffic from social networks such as Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, etc. It should have excellent layout and beautiful social network icons. The icons in a viral WordPress theme must be placed at the best position so as to increase the chances of a visitor sharing the content. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to launch a viral WordPress site and looking for a good theme which above mentioned features, consider using the following templates:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumome plugin for WordPress : free list builder social sharing and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sumome-plugin-for-wordpress-free-list-builder-social-sharing-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sumome-plugin-for-wordpress-free-list-builder-social-sharing-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suomeme is an awesome all in one plugin for promoting blog posts. It has a powerful sharing button that not only looks great but also allows users to share posts on top social networks without adding a lot of weight on your pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plugin lets users add a floating bar in the header or footer area of your blog. Thus you can use it as an alternative to hellobar. Sharing images from your blog posts is possible with Sumome. The buttons for the same will appear automatically when the user hovers mouse cursor on the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Social bookmarking sites list : boost rankings of your website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-social-bookmarking-sites-list-boost-rankings-of-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-social-bookmarking-sites-list-boost-rankings-of-your-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social bookmarking websites are important as they can bring tons of visitors to your blog. They will also increase your post&amp;rsquo;s ranking and visibility in search engines. There are two categories of bookmarking sites, i.e., nofollow and dofollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most do follow sites that allow you to share links are considered as spam by Google. Sites that link to such bookmarking portals are penalized, and they don&amp;rsquo;t rank anywhere in top 20 to 25 pages of the search engine. People promoting these websites don&amp;rsquo;t know SEO, and you should avoid following their tips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy Social Share Buttons for WordPress Review (latest)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/easy-social-share-buttons-for-wordpress-review-latest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/easy-social-share-buttons-for-wordpress-review-latest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Backlinks from social networks like Facebook, Google plus, twitter, etc are nofollow. But you&amp;rsquo;ll be shocked to know that Google uses data from social networks to rank websites in the search engine regardless whether the link is dofollow or nofollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone reads and article on your site and if he/she shares it in a group/page or on his public timeline, this link will be considered as a vote of trust. Thus, if your blog articles are shared 100s of time, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that your site will rank in the 1st 2 or 3 pages of Google. Making people share content is not a piece of cake. The user will not share your blog post unless he has a reason to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best WordPress social media plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-social-media-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-wordpress-social-media-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time when search engines like MSN, Bing, Yahoo, and Google were considered as the only source of website traffic. Now things have changed a lot. Social network sites like FB, Twitter, Google+ are used by billions of people across the world. When you have a good audience on sites like Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus, Instagram, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to depend on search engines for website traffic. Blogs are probably incomplete without a social media plugin. These plugins make sharing of blog posts easier for visitors. Almost all websites (excluding social network sites) have such plugins installed on their website. Below are the three main advantages of these plugins:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
