<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Web-20 on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/web-20/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web-20 on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/web-20/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Joomla 1.6 Pushes Enterprise Level Features</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new version of the popular Joomla Content Management System (CMS) was released early last week and has already reached over 115k in downloads. 1.6 has been in the making for some time and earlier beta versions have been tested over the last few month. The first release candidate (RC1) was made available for download on December 14th, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySpace More Layoffs and Reflecting on What Went Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last July, Inside the Webb reported on new changes coming to MySpace in an effort to streamline the overall design of the social networking giant. As reported at the time, the changes were long overdue, however overhauling such a large organization was no easy task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Discussion Boards and Dynamic Chatrooms with Donut Chat</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/social-discussion-boards-and-dynamic-chatrooms-with-donut-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/social-discussion-boards-and-dynamic-chatrooms-with-donut-chat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new chatroom client has been released on the market, and it runs so smooth I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s not being used elsewhere. Donut Chat is my latest find in the ways of community and boards, and the software runs perfectly. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of chat rooms, they&amp;rsquo;re useful as support forums, sharing ideas with friends and business partners&amp;hellip; really anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Webb v3.0 Launches Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-the-webb-v3.0-launches-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-the-webb-v3.0-launches-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 3.0 of Inside the Webb has finally launched live. Since our last design update in December I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy at work contemplating how I could take Inside the Webb to the next level. Well it hit me about a week ago, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been tweaking the latest and greatest design launch!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Mashable so Quick to Promote Google Buzz?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mashable is one huge blog, a very large competitor to Inside the Webb and what I wish we could be someday! They run some amazing articles about social networking, social media, tech news, and everything internet related. They usually have articles hitting the front page of Digg and Delicious, gaining well into 1500+ ReTweets and tons of Stumbles: bottom line, their blog is huge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chill to your Music Library anywhere with Grooveshark</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/chill-to-your-music-library-anywhere-with-grooveshark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/chill-to-your-music-library-anywhere-with-grooveshark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I found out about Grooveshark a few months ago, it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionized the way I listen to music. No longer am I stuck with my iTunes playlists and limitions on songs - nor do I even need to store the songs on my computer!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with is.gd URL Shortener</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-is.gd-url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-is.gd-url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New URL Shortening services hit the web every week it seems. I can remember not too long ago when TinyURL was just starting up, and that hit with a huge bang. Ever since then, there have been countless creations of URL shorteners (where some even provided stats). However, only a select few have really succeeded to hit mainstream popularity and be of any use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founder of Omegle.com Answers Questions From Redditors</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omegle.com has spread across many social networking hubs, forums, and internet chatrooms rapidly over the past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s a new site with a very simple concept: you log in anonymously and talk to someone else. Someone random, someone you&amp;rsquo;ve *probably* never even met before, just talking about whatever. It seems like a breeding ground for spam and pranks, but it ultimately seen very positive results in traffic and user response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Posterous.com:  Filesharing Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing files over the internet used to be a devilish task. Finding the right application, storage space, or transporation method for files used to be very difficult only 5 years ago. Now with file upload sites and forums/bulletin boards to share files, sending your friend a song or posting up a funny picture has never been easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with BloggersBase: A Community Built for Bloggers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-bloggersbase-a-community-built-for-bloggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-bloggersbase-a-community-built-for-bloggers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;blogging&amp;rdquo; is thrown around so much these days. There are millions of blogs, bloggers, blog posts, and people blogging every day. In fact, this post you&amp;rsquo;re reading is on a blog! It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder this area has exploded over the past couple of years, and there are many social networking sites connecting both bloggers and readers together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Your Music Anywhere with MeCanto</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/listen-to-your-music-anywhere-with-mecanto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/listen-to-your-music-anywhere-with-mecanto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to carry your music library on an iPod or MP3 player has revolutionized how we listen to music. It&amp;rsquo;s allowed us to bring our favorite songs anywhere we go, keep us busy when waiting on appointments, and share some of our favorite music with friends. However, with MeCanto you can now bring your entire music library anywhere you can get an internet collection - that&amp;rsquo;s practically anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Digg-Clone for Designers DesignBump</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg was the first social news site to really skyrocket into popularity, gaining millions of pageviews a day to the site. No doubt, there would be similar sites in separate niches on the web. The first of these niche sites in the web design category was Design Float, which has had many issues with databases and keeping the site up and running properly. Therefore, a new competitor has stepped up to the plate: DesignBump.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link Your Social Networking Profiles Together with SocialFollow</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social Follow is a cool new web application that combines all of your other social networking and social bookmarking profiles. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all have accounts on Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Digg, and many other profiles around the net. With SocialFollow, you are able to combine all of these profiles into one handy button. These are great for posting to your blog, sharing in your forum sigs, or posting it anywhere around the web!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flick.to.Twitt - Easily share your Flickr Photos on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/flick.to.twitt-easily-share-your-flickr-photos-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/flick.to.twitt-easily-share-your-flickr-photos-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has become one of the largest web 2.0 applications on the web today, in comparison with Facebook, MySpace, and Digg. Along with this, Flickr has become a giant web app where users can share their photos. However, with the use of Flick.to.Twitt you are now able to post your Flickr photos right to your Twitter account! I have an interview with the site&amp;rsquo;s founder Marco Almeida, in which we discussed the site&amp;rsquo;s creation and also future goals for the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Task.fm - The world&#39;s simplest reminder app</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-task.fm-the-worlds-simplest-reminder-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-task.fm-the-worlds-simplest-reminder-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently been scoping out some cool web 2.0 sites to add to my blog for my first interview, and I found my answer lying in the new startup task.fm. This app has only been online for about a week so far, but already has a booming userbase of 1000 regular users and growing daily. Task.fm allows its users to have reminders sent through e-mail, phone, and SMS. The reminders can be entered by the user, and typed in regular speech, too! Below is my interview with the site&amp;rsquo;s creator Anthony Feint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
