<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Keyword on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/keyword/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keyword on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/keyword/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best way to Auto Tag WordPress posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-auto-tag-wordpress-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-way-to-auto-tag-wordpress-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress tags are important, no matter how small or large a site is. Tags allow users to group posts. They make website navigation easier. They allow search engines to discover and index new posts quickly. WordPress Related posts plugins use tags to calculate post relevancy and display related articles below blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human beings make mistakes. Sometimes, a webmaster may delete an important tag unintentionally. Once a tag is removed, the structure of the related post on your site may change. If you have a small blog with 10 to 20 posts, readding tags manually shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. If you own a large site, readding tags to posts is an annoying task. The best way to add tags to blog posts is to use Automatic Post Tagger WordPress plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best tools to check Google keyword rankings for a website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once your website starts ranking in search engines, you should check its Google keyword rankings often. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, competitors may steal your keywords and use them on their portals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website with high domain authority won&amp;rsquo;t be affected by this. But if a site is new, competitor stealing your major keywords may have a negative impact on your website traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some of the best free tools to check website ranking in Google search engine. Most of the tools covered in this blog post won&amp;rsquo;t ask you to create an account. Nor they&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to enter credit or debit card details. Apart from free tools, we&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned a powerful premium SEO tool that provides plenty of useful SEO tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
