<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vps on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/vps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vps on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/vps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to limit CPU usage on server effectively?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-limit-cpu-usage-on-server-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-limit-cpu-usage-on-server-effectively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most hosting companies have introduced 2+ plans. The price of the hosting depends on the hardware and software the company is offering the customer. A plan that offers a low amount of RAM or a single core processor will be less expensive as compared to a plan that provides heaps of system memory and CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what plan you use, you must always keep an eye on the server CPU usage. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, a user process may use up to 90 - 100% CPU and other applications/system processes won&amp;rsquo;t be able to execute their tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A2 Hosting review: Is it the fastest shared hosting service?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;A2 Hosting&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/images/A2-Hosting.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2 is one of the top 10 hosting companies in the world. The company has been operating since 2001/2002 and it has launched several hosting plans for every budget. As of today, over 10K sites are hosted on A2 servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2 offers cloud, VPS, dedicated and shared hosting service. Is it a reliable hosting firm? Are its plans affordable? Is its support staff customer friendly? Let&amp;rsquo;s find it out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linode Review 2018: Great uptime and affordable plans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/linode-review-2018-great-uptime-and-affordable-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/linode-review-2018-great-uptime-and-affordable-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my online career with a site hosted on Godaddy. I switched to A Small Orange from Godaddy after finding its plans cheap. After a major DNS incident, I quit ASO and bought shared hosting plan from Hostgator. HG shared plans are great for growing sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic to my site grew and I had launched a few more sites. To make sure that HG doesn&amp;rsquo;t ban my sites by high server resource usage, I bought unmanaged Hostgator VPS plan. The VPS had 512 MB RAM. Everything was going great. When I was holidaying at my native place, my sites were down for 8 hours. To find the reason for this, I logged into the server to go through PHP, Nginx, MySQL log, and system log files. The system log file had several &amp;ldquo;MYSQL server has gone away&amp;rdquo; entries. This problem occurs when the system doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough free memory for MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linode vs DigitalOcean : Best Cloud hosting platform is...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/linode-vs-digitalocean-best-cloud-hosting-platform-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/linode-vs-digitalocean-best-cloud-hosting-platform-is.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linode and Digital Ocean cloud VPS providers offer KVM based servers for hosting a website and 40 GbE for high-speed networking. These two companies are growing at a very fast rate giving a cut throat competition to Hostgator, Bluehost, Vultr, and many other VPS providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we have compared the features and services offered by Linode and Digital Ocean. In case you&amp;rsquo;re confused in choosing between DO &amp;amp; Linode, go through the paragraphs shared below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proof : HTTP 500 Internal Server Errors Impact Google Rankings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a regular reader of this blog, you may have noticed that this site was throwing error establishing database connection or internal server errors last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue which was caused by the Linux out of memory manager has now been fixed, and the site is now live 24 x 7. I&amp;rsquo;m using this server to host some other WordPress websites as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing the error was a very confusing task for me. To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about OOM process killer in Linux. If I knew how this module worked, the error would have been fixed on the day the error message appeared the system log file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hostgator VPS review 2018 : Linux Hosting with great uptime</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hostgator-vps-review-2018-linux-hosting-with-great-uptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hostgator-vps-review-2018-linux-hosting-with-great-uptime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shared hosting plans are suitable for beginners and people with no knowledge of PHP, MySQL and Web servers. In a shared hosting, the company offers PhpMyAdmin, CPanel, Awstats (Google Analytics Alternative) and many more tools to make website configuration or deployment easier for a webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shared hosting comes with several limitations. Your site will be hosted with several other web portals, and it will have limited resource to use. Bandwidth usage will be a matter of concern. You are not allowed to experiment with PHP MySQL modules. Nor you can switch from Apache/Nginx to some other web server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
