<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Keyword-Density on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/keyword-density/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keyword-Density on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/keyword-density/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free and Best SEO tools that every webmaster should use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization aka SEO is one of the most important topics of discussion in the online world. Without following the right guidelines and SEO tips, it will be tough to survive as a blogger or a webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use search engines and Facebook more than any other website. Promoting a product on Facebook is not free. If you want to do this without any costs, you will have to build a large community and huge fan following. Search engines like Google are powerful and every major or minor website is indexed by them. It indexes your site without any costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Tail Pro 3.0 Discount and Review (Aug 2016)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/long-tail-pro-3.0-discount-and-review-aug-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/long-tail-pro-3.0-discount-and-review-aug-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the user opens a search engine like google or bing? What is the 1st thing he sees? A large text box accompanied with a search button. To find information, the user must enter some data in the textbox. This data in SEO world is known as the keyword. Many bloggers, webmasters, and SEO professionals use keywords to rank their websites in search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right keywords is not an easy task. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to spend plenty of hours using online tools like Google AdWords, sem rush, etc. Adwords is owned by Google. It is used by online marketing professionals and agencies to advertise products or websites in Google. The advertisers use AdWords to find keywords that a user enters in the search field of the Google. You can use this free tool only if you have a Google account.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEMRush Free Trial account : Find Competitor Keywords and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professional bloggers are successful because they make wise use of SEO tools. For example, Pat Flynn, the owner of smart passive income has launched a few niche blogs that earn him over 5000 dollars every month. Patt is one of the most intelligent bloggers in the world. He makes more than 50000 dollars every month by promoting various products. He makes use of different keyword research tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amit Agarwal, the top Indian blogger, initially used Google Keyword Planner to find relevant and high traffic keywords, as a result, his blog labnol generates more 2.5 million INR revenue through AdSense. Most of the articles on his site labnol.org rank on 1st page of Google.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best keyword density checker for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-keyword-density-checker-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-keyword-density-checker-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My technology blog was penalized at least 4 to 5 times. In my initial days of blogging career, I was not aware of terms like keyword density, on page SEO, backlinks, etc. I indulged myself in link building activities, and I was not focused on sharing top quality content. These three blogging mistakes killed my blog&amp;rsquo;s traffic up to 70 to 80%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they say, we learn from our mistakes and hard work pays off, I worked hard for 3 to 4 months to regain the lost traffic and rectified all errors that I committed. In those four months, I removed around 400 blog posts and improved the content quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
