<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Find Popular and Useful Websites Easily with TopSite</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/find-popular-and-useful-websites-easily-with-topsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/find-popular-and-useful-websites-easily-with-topsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever find yourself wondering &amp;ldquo;how can I find the best blogs on the web, or the best social media apps for rating food or movies&amp;rdquo;? Well look no further, your web search engine is here! When your trust pal Google has failed you, I recommend giving TopSite a shot. It&amp;rsquo;s a social search engine which tracks down the top 10 most popular websites based on a keyword.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jay Adelson Steps Down as CEO of Digg.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jay-adelson-steps-down-as-ceo-of-digg.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jay-adelson-steps-down-as-ceo-of-digg.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent blog post entitled simply &amp;ldquo;Update from Jay&amp;rdquo;, it has been officially announced that Jay Adelson will be stepping down as Digg&amp;rsquo;s CEO after 5 prosperous and amazing years. Jay has done an amazing job as CEO, and I firmly believe Digg wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hold it&amp;rsquo;s current success status today if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for his ideas and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Digg-Clone Thuhm Updates Design and Added Features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-clone-thuhm-updates-design-and-added-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-clone-thuhm-updates-design-and-added-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had written a Review for Thuhm a while back, and have to say I still love the app. It&amp;rsquo;s a brand new social news website for sharing all kinds of news, and it combines the best features of Reddit and Digg together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although still just breaking off the ground, Thuhm has a lot to offer it&amp;rsquo;s readers. Recently there had been a post mentioning new updates on the site, including a new front page design and the addition of categories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Virtual Online Gaming Community FactPile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many great online gaming communities. Video games have taken a huge rise in popularity over the years, and what a better way to celebrate your favorite games than hanging out with like-minded people on a fun and active community? FactPile does just that, collecting all gamers and tech-lovers from around the globe to interact and enjoy the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Digg-Themed Social News and Media Website Thuhm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has become the popular site for internet marketers and bloggers to aspire to. Digg used to be a popular tech website, where tech enthusiasts and internet lovers could gather to share links. Whichever links got the most &amp;ldquo;diggs&amp;rdquo; would hit the front page, generally to recieve a surge of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
