<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Csec-650 on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/csec-650/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Csec-650 on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/csec-650/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Business Continuity Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/business-continuity-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/business-continuity-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of business continuity planning is to ensure continued operations of an organization in the event of a catastrophic event, whether this may be a natural disaster or something more sinister. In recent years, we have seen the increase of cyber-attacks and breaches to the point that they have become common news worldwide. As systems have grown in complexity and capacity to store large amounts of data, so too has the appeal of targeting such systems by cyber criminals. In order to meet these challenges head on, business organizations must adapt and implement a comprehensive business continuity plan. Cerullo and Cerullo (2004) describe a business continuity plan as dynamic and evolving as the business environment changes and its dependency on advanced technology changes. They go on to describe three interdependent objectives which include identification of major risks, development of a plan to mitigate or reduce impact of risks, and testing and training. While there is no single recipe to the ideal continuity plan, stakeholders across the organization must play a role in building out a framework for business continuity management that can be used to mitigate major risks while maintaining ‘business as usual’ in the event of a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of different data sources used in a forensics investigation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/an-analysis-of-different-data-sources-used-in-a-forensics-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/an-analysis-of-different-data-sources-used-in-a-forensics-investigation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article provides an overview of four different data sources used in various forensics investigations. The first source includes system log files containing system logs within the operating system as well as an overview of some tools that can be used in order to effectively understand these logs. File systems are also discussed including the effectiveness of metadata and their overall relevance to an investigation or analysis. The third source involves intrusion detection and prevention systems that give a greater overview of traffic at the network layer. Finally, the most volatile of data sources, memory is examined in depth along with the impact such data may have on an investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forensics in Business Continuity Planning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/forensics-in-business-continuity-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/forensics-in-business-continuity-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Business continuity planning in any organization today must incorporate aspects of computer forensics in order to be sustainable. According to Majore, Yoo &amp;amp; Shon (2014) in their article on secure and reliable electronic record management, over 90% of records created today are electronic. In addition to this electronic records require a greater amount of maintenance due to their volatility and dependence on reliable hardware and software. In continuity planning, organizations must face these challenges head on and prepare strategies that integrate digital forensics disciplines into their underlying processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Role of Computer Forensics?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-role-of-computer-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-role-of-computer-forensics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer forensics can play a vital role in an organization’s recovery from a cyber attack. By properly following forensics processes carefully in the aftermath of an attack, recovery can begin to play out. According to Čisar &amp;amp; Maravić Čisar (2012), in accordance with digital forensic analysis methodology three processes are essential, which include preparation, identification, and analysis. It is during these processes that a post-mortem analysis occurs including file system, event logs, and recovery of deleted files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malicious Code Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/malicious-code-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/malicious-code-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Malicious code detection is an ongoing obfuscation-deobfuscation game because of the nature of the malware or goals of the attacker. Detection of malicious executables known to an investigator is usually performed using signature-based techniques. In their forensic research article, Rozenberg, Guides, Elovici and Fledel (2010) made the point that obfuscated or encrypted files could not easily be detected this way. Instead they recommended a behavioral approach to real time detection. As hackers continue to find new and more advanced techniques to encrypt and hide malicious code, security personnel will have to continue to upgrade their skills and toolsets used in investigations, resulting in an ongoing obfuscation-deobfuscation game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access Trojans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/remote-access-trojans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/remote-access-trojans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote Access Trojans have become a serious security concern as hackers have developed more sophisticated code that can be installed and hidden on a target system, unknown to the user. According to UMUC (n.d.) Remote Access Trojans are a form of backdoor that can provide unauthorized access and use of digital assets on a victim’s computer system. It essentially masquerades as a legitimate application. They allow hackers to perform a number of malicious tasks such as stealing information from a system, or installing other malicious software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presenting Digital Evidence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/presenting-digital-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/presenting-digital-evidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testifying and writing a report are both essential ingredients to a successful digital forensics investigation. Digital forensics personnel will potentially spend months of time working with complex data and processes. The delivery and result of this work is reflected in the forensics report and then ultimately testified in court. Cohen (2012) discussed the report as integral to the overall investigation. Evidence, analysis, interpretation, and attribution, must ultimately be presented in the form of expert reports, depositions, and testimony. The report will present the data captured during the investigation in a way that can be communicated with other people. In addition to this, it serves as a living record that will be referenced and updated throughout the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confusion over Terminology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/confusion-over-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/confusion-over-terminology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The terms risk, vulnerability and threat are often confusing and sometime interchangeable leading to a lack of understanding when presenting evidence. Risks are usually based on a probability that a threat of some kind will exploit a vulnerability or weakness in a system or network. In recent years risks have been taken more seriously with many businesses that conduct online activities. Vulnerabilities as mentioned above are typically weaknesses that can be exploited by an attacker. This can include anything from poorly configured software and firewalls to badly written pieces of code that can affect secrecy, integrity and control of data and functionality within a system. Bergeron et al. (2001).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Hiding and Steganography</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/data-hiding-and-steganography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/data-hiding-and-steganography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The term ‘Steganography’ refers to ‘covered writing’ and encompasses methods of transmitting secret messages through innocuous cover carriers in a manner that their existence is undetectable. Johnson &amp;amp; Jojodia (1998). For years hackers have been finding more innovative ways of hiding data within existing systems usually for the purpose of transporting it to a target destination. The term ‘carrier’ often refers to a type of common file that covert information can be embedded in unknowingly to anyone else. Kessler (2007) discusses the fact that any form of digital information can be stored inside many types of carrier files, including image, audio, video and executable files. Digital forensics tools can be used to scan carriers to determine whether or not suspicious information lies underneath the surface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation Phase of a Digital Search</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/preparation-phase-of-a-digital-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/preparation-phase-of-a-digital-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The preparation phase of digital search is the most important phase of the digital investigation process. If not carried out correctly, the can lead to improper handling of evidence that may lead to damage of crucial materials to an investigation. This phase involves the preparation of tools, techniques, search warrants, and monitoring authorizations and management support. Venansius &amp;amp; Tushabe (2004). It is therefore important that adequate resources are allocated to the preparation phase. Beebe &amp;amp; Clark (2007) elaborate more on this phase as the process of preparing tools and equipment, honing forensics skills, and continuing to become educated about on new technologies and tools that may be useful in dealing with the incident.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important Cybercrime Laws</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/important-cybercrime-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/important-cybercrime-laws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a number of cybercrime laws that are extremely important in the field of digital forensics and cybersecurity as a whole. Two of the most important laws include the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act (CFAA) of 1984 and the Electronic Communications Privacy Act (ECPA) of 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original intent of CFAA was to address computer related crimes and more specifically protect information assets. The law made it a federal crime to gain unauthorized access to data or information on protected computer systems. It does not come without criticism. Kerr (2009) made many points that the current law is too vague stating that CFAA has become so broad, and computers so common, that expansive or uncertain interpretations of unauthorized access will render it unconstitutional. Nevertheless, the law has been a cornerstone for shaping the way we deal with cybercrime and since its introduction, has been since amended a number of times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet More Theft of Information Assets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/yet-more-theft-of-information-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/yet-more-theft-of-information-assets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t seem that long ago that I received an official letter in the mail from the United States Office of Personnel Management (OPM) detailing that sensitive information about me had been compromised. I had been following the news and knew about the breach, so the letter didn’t come as a huge shock. It did make me think about the impact of such a breach, originally reported as affecting 4 million individuals, later estimated to have compromised sensitive information of 21.5 million. Christensen et al (2015). Just this past week I once again learned, along with the majority of the country, that with high probability my identity along with millions of others had been stolen in another data breach. It has since come to light that the cause of the breach was unpatched systems affected by Apache’s open-source Struts software, a vulnerability that should have been mitigated months before the breach took place. Brandom (2017).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
