<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Comparision on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/comparision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comparision on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/comparision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best cheap WordPress hosting with great reviews (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-cheap-wordpress-hosting-with-great-reviews-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-cheap-wordpress-hosting-with-great-reviews-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is the best blogging software and free content management system. It performs well on a powerful server. If the server has a poor configuration, WordPress may not provide the best experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites hosted on an underpowered server suffers from heavy downtimes. The website takes ages to open on the visitor&amp;rsquo;s browser. This results in poor user experience. As the first impression is the best impression, visitors may not visit your site in the future. Search engines fuelled by Artifical Intelligence can distinguish between a user-friendly and a user-hostile website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InMotion vs Hostgator 2018 : Which hosting is worth the money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inmotion-vs-hostgator-2018-which-hosting-is-worth-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inmotion-vs-hostgator-2018-which-hosting-is-worth-the-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several hosting companies challenge Hostgator by providing competitive plans with mouth-watering features. But the big question always haunts the minds of money spenders. Are the plans worth the money or is the company reliable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an answer to the above two big questions, we&amp;rsquo;ve shared comparisons and reviews of various hosting services. We&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share more comparisons so that you can buy get the best hosting for your site. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve compared InMotion and Hostgator plans and features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPage vs HostGator shared Hosting Comparison (March 2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ipage-vs-hostgator-shared-hosting-comparison-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ipage-vs-hostgator-shared-hosting-comparison-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;iPage and Hostgator are two of the most popular shared website hosting companies. They have a customer base of over a million users. iPage is operational since 1998 whereas HostGator brand started flourishing from 2002 onward. Both companies are reliable. Thus, many users who want to launch a new website or change the host are often confused in choosing a shared hosting service between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll try to clear the confusion for you by sharing a comparison of the pricing, performance, uptime, features and customer support offered by iPage and HostGator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Website Traffic Free Online with these awesome tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website visit you visit uses an analytics tool to track visitors and their activity. Only the organization that own its will have access to the tracking data. The company doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to make their data public unless they&amp;rsquo;re generating advertising revenue from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people using the internet are always curious to know how much traffic does their favorite website get. But as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned earlier, the real data is with the site&amp;rsquo;s owner. Thus, no matter what tool you use, you cannot get the exact statistics of a website traffic unless the company decides to share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Blogging Platform : Blogger vs WordPress Comparision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-blogging-platform-blogger-vs-wordpress-comparision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-blogging-platform-blogger-vs-wordpress-comparision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress and Blogger are 2 of the most popular blogging platforms/content management systems of all time. They are free to use. These 2 platforms are so powerful that users can build/launch a new website within a couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newbie, I used Blogger platform as I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to risk my money in an adventure that I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a part of before. After 5 - 6 months, I migrated my site to WordPress. Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re starting up with blogging and if you&amp;rsquo;re confused in choosing the best blogging platform for you then please go through the below paragraphs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
