<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Best web hosting services for 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-7-best-web-hosting-services-for-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-7-best-web-hosting-services-for-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web hosting is the backbone of a website. It is crucial to the success of a blogger, business, and the website. A poor web hosting firm will have big downtimes. Because of poor infrastructure, the network latency will be high and your site will rank below faster websites in the search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web hosting services are of three types, shared, VPS, dedicated, and cloud. The shared hosting plans are the cheapest of the three. They are ideal for small sites owned by newbie webmasters and beginners. VPS and dedicated plans are costly as compared to shared. They are suitable for business or larger websites owned by experienced webmasters. Cloud platforms are suitable for websites whose traffic may explode anytime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One.com hosting review (2018) : 1 year free hosting and domain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/one.com-hosting-review-2018-1-year-free-hosting-and-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/one.com-hosting-review-2018-1-year-free-hosting-and-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One.com is a hosting company founded 14 years back by Jacob Jensen. The firm hosts around a million sites and has branches in various countries. Top brands and experts recommend one.com hosting for its quality service and great uptime of over 99%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the various features the customers of One.com hosting enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;control-panel&#34;&gt;Control panel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;one com : control panel&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/one.com-hosting-review-2018-1-year-free-hosting-and-domain/images/one-com-control-panel.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A control panel is a web-based server and website management tool. You&amp;rsquo;ll find an option to install CMS such as WordPress and manage database in the control panel. One.com offers a beautiful CP with plenty of options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EMD SEO and Google : 3 Important things that you should know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/emd-seo-and-google-3-important-things-that-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/emd-seo-and-google-3-important-things-that-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google penalizes spammy EMD sites, but do you know that Exact match domain names can outrank an authority site for a specific keyword? If you don&amp;rsquo;t know this, you are probably a newbie or an immature SEO professional. Here are the three important things that you should know as a Sear Engine Optimization professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;emd-domains-rank&#34;&gt;EMD domains rank&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can give 10 good examples that exact match domain names rank high for the keywords. Google starts ranking EMD sites only after a certain time period. The sites using EMD have 100s of polished articles with an average content length of 500 words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Website Traffic Free Online with these awesome tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website visit you visit uses an analytics tool to track visitors and their activity. Only the organization that own its will have access to the tracking data. The company doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to make their data public unless they&amp;rsquo;re generating advertising revenue from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people using the internet are always curious to know how much traffic does their favorite website get. But as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned earlier, the real data is with the site&amp;rsquo;s owner. Thus, no matter what tool you use, you cannot get the exact statistics of a website traffic unless the company decides to share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proof : HTTP 500 Internal Server Errors Impact Google Rankings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a regular reader of this blog, you may have noticed that this site was throwing error establishing database connection or internal server errors last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue which was caused by the Linux out of memory manager has now been fixed, and the site is now live 24 x 7. I&amp;rsquo;m using this server to host some other WordPress websites as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing the error was a very confusing task for me. To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about OOM process killer in Linux. If I knew how this module worked, the error would have been fixed on the day the error message appeared the system log file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BigRock Hosting Review, Plans and Coupon code 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bigrock-hosting-review-plans-and-coupon-code-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bigrock-hosting-review-plans-and-coupon-code-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BigRock is an India web hosting and domain name registration company owned by Directi, a company with excellent infrastructure and revenue more than 300 MN USD. It is one of the best hosting companies in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bigrock is the first choice for people who have just begun their online careers by launching a website., thanks to the cheap web hosting plans. Around million users use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bigrock is ideal for hosting websites that target Indian audiences and for registering domain names at a cheap rate. It offers customer support with highly talented staff members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WP Statistics is a Google Analytics alternative for WordPress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some webmasters are concerned about their online privacy, and they will never use a popular third party analytics tool like Google Search Console, webmaster tools, clicky, StatCounter, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To safeguard their website statistics, people use a plugin which will create a database to store data related to websites. One of the best plugin to do this job is WP statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin works 24 x 7 to update the DB with visitor data. You can use it to compare website traffic from the best search engines i.e. Google, Bing, Baidu, Yandex, DuckDuckGo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding analytics dashboard to WordPress site in a minute</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is one of the most valuable free tools for webmasters. With it, you can easily track traffic to your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytics makes you aware of many details like visitor source, average visit time, page views, website loading speed, device, operating system, the browser of the visitor and much more. It is easy to understand the tool. Even new bloggers or website owners will find it intuitive and easy to use. To start tracking the visitor behavior and traffic, the user has to install a tracking code to the header or footer section of their website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and Best SEO tools that every webmaster should use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization aka SEO is one of the most important topics of discussion in the online world. Without following the right guidelines and SEO tips, it will be tough to survive as a blogger or a webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use search engines and Facebook more than any other website. Promoting a product on Facebook is not free. If you want to do this without any costs, you will have to build a large community and huge fan following. Search engines like Google are powerful and every major or minor website is indexed by them. It indexes your site without any costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block referrer spam without plugin and Google Analytics filter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/block-referrer-spam-without-plugin-and-google-analytics-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/block-referrer-spam-without-plugin-and-google-analytics-filter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, my Google Analytics account has started showing a lot of referrer spam sites like SexyAli, free-social-buttons, Semalt, etc. The spammers are screwing up my GA reports. I have some websites. Tho site with 1000s of visitors is not affected but for my new portals, the referrers are causing high bounce rate which makes the report data confusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some referrers seem to be attacking WordPress sites as the real-time reports show 30+ visitors (from spam sites) from various parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track adsense clicks and invalid activity easily with these 2 tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/track-adsense-clicks-and-invalid-activity-easily-with-these-2-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/track-adsense-clicks-and-invalid-activity-easily-with-these-2-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you own an AdSense account, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to safeguard it. Many accounts get banned every day because they take AdSense program lightly. There are two ways you can keep your account safe i.e., avoid clicking on your ads and report invalid activity to Google. The 1st method is easy to follow because you just have to install an ad blocker plugin on your browser. The browser will prevent ads from loading on websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
