<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is Your Organization Using Evidence-Based Decision Making?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/is-your-organization-using-evidence-based-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/is-your-organization-using-evidence-based-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are more ways to access data through a large amount of software tools than there has ever been in the history of analytics. We have access to a wealth of information that, if used properly, can help drive decisions and bring about success within organizations. Why then are so many top-level executive decisions driven by intuition and gut feel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been countless examples over the last decade of commercial failures that could have been avoided if a greater analytical approach had been adopted and used in evidence based thinking and decision making. Unfortunately adopting and integrating analytics into the operational and strategic decisions has it&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Two of the largest hurdles to successful integration of evidence-based decision making fall within the organizational culture and awareness or education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Culture Changes and Impacts on the Individual &amp; Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-culture-changes-and-impacts-on-the-individual-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-culture-changes-and-impacts-on-the-individual-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Organizational culture has an impact on how a business functions. (O’Reilly III, Chatman, &amp;amp; Caldwell, 1991) echo the agreement of researchers over the years that culture may be an important factor in determining how well an individual fits an organizational context. I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed the positive and negative effects of organizational culture both in regards to the individual as well as decision making, that has a profound effect on others. In the article Decision-Making: The Impact of Organizational Culture, (Buchanan, 2018) cites the positives of a small organizational structure with a culture of collaboration (everyone wearing multiple hats and helping each other out). At the same time she warns about misalignment between culture and behaviors and how evidence and data driven decision making, when used incorrectly, can have adverse results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency: Future Money or Unicorn of Century?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cryptocurrency-future-money-or-unicorn-of-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cryptocurrency-future-money-or-unicorn-of-century/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency is virtual currency or digital currency that is designed to be used as a medium of exchange to make secure transactions. It does not have any centralized control and there isn’t any regulatory authority as opposite of banks and electronic money. Its control works as a blockchain that is a distributed ledger. The technical system that is base of cryptocurrency was created by an unknown person or a group named Satoshi Nakamoto. In 2017 thousands of cryptocurrencies were created, most of them were like Bitcoin. Is the system of cryptocurrencies the balance and safety of ledgers are managed by miners which are a community of distrustful parties. Miners get a financial benefit for maintaining the security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Hostgator Black Friday 2016 discount - best deal of the year</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/get-hostgator-black-friday-2016-discount-best-deal-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/get-hostgator-black-friday-2016-discount-best-deal-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a newbie blogger, I kept changing my hosting provider until I signed up for HostGator. To be honest, I had faced a hard time in finding the best hosting provider for my website. To help you out in choosing the best themes and plugins, I have shared the list of WordPress Black Friday deals. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a special Hostgator deal, with which you can get flat 65% off on any hosting of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Black Friday Deals 2016 : Unbelievable discounts for you</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-black-friday-deals-2016-unbelievable-discounts-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-black-friday-deals-2016-unbelievable-discounts-for-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been waiting for the WordPress Black Friday sale 2016, then your wait is over. The WP BF sale has begun and top WordPress theme and plugin developers are throwing massive discounts on their top products. Hence, if you buy a premium product now, you&amp;rsquo;ll save huge money by the end of next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re not able to find the best deals for WordPress, here is the list of top offers you can avail this November.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Quick Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/freedom-of-information-act-foia-quick-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/freedom-of-information-act-foia-quick-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying out some work involving the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). There is tons of information about FOIA on the web including on the official foia.gov website, however I decided to summarize the main points of this law in an easy to read / digestible format. This article is broken down into three main parts, a brief intro, the main areas covered in the law, and concludes with the exemptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aptana acquired by Appcelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aptana, the company behind the popular programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Aptana Studio, announced today that they have been acquired by Appcelerator. Aptana has been the choice for many web development professionals for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Joomla 1.6 Pushes Enterprise Level Features</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new version of the popular Joomla Content Management System (CMS) was released early last week and has already reached over 115k in downloads. 1.6 has been in the making for some time and earlier beta versions have been tested over the last few month. The first release candidate (RC1) was made available for download on December 14th, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySpace More Layoffs and Reflecting on What Went Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last July, Inside the Webb reported on new changes coming to MySpace in an effort to streamline the overall design of the social networking giant. As reported at the time, the changes were long overdue, however overhauling such a large organization was no easy task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are WMAL’s Grandy and Andy?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/where-are-wmals-grandy-and-andy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/where-are-wmals-grandy-and-andy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many of the residents in the Washington DC Metro area, driving to work listening to their talk local radio station WMAL has become a daily part of their lives. Those familiar with the station, are of course avid listeners of the famous morning show duo, Grandy and Andy, aka Fred Grandy and Andy Parks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreshWebJobs: A Unique Job Board for Web Designers &amp;amp; Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back a few years ago I used to work full-time freelance web design. It&amp;rsquo;s a tiring job, and many people who can do it today earn a lot of money working for themselves in the trade. Web professionals are always in demand, but it&amp;rsquo;s difficult at times to find good web projects. Freshwebjobs.com changes all that with professional listings to pair up webmasters and developers to those looking into projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Office 2010 Outlook has some New Digs</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/microsoft-office-2010-outlook-has-some-new-digs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/microsoft-office-2010-outlook-has-some-new-digs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s official release of Office 2010 being pushed out of Beta, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see where they plan on going next. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running 2010 beta since they released them for download months ago, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been more than pleased with all of it! The biggest noticeable change is with Outlook, my favorite e-mail client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Merges Startup Visual Search Engine Plink with Google Goggles</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-merges-startup-visual-search-engine-plink-with-google-goggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-merges-startup-visual-search-engine-plink-with-google-goggles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has taken another step forward in visual and image search after acquiring UK-based startup Plink. Having only launched 4 months ago, Plink is a visual search engine which you can download as an Android app and take a photo of a picture to find out more information about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jay Adelson Steps Down as CEO of Digg.com</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/jay-adelson-steps-down-as-ceo-of-digg.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/jay-adelson-steps-down-as-ceo-of-digg.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent blog post entitled simply &amp;ldquo;Update from Jay&amp;rdquo;, it has been officially announced that Jay Adelson will be stepping down as Digg&amp;rsquo;s CEO after 5 prosperous and amazing years. Jay has done an amazing job as CEO, and I firmly believe Digg wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hold it&amp;rsquo;s current success status today if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for his ideas and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional XHTML/CSS Slicing Company Slicejack</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSD Conversion is a very high-paying business. Many amazing designers know how to work through Photoshop but just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or haven&amp;rsquo;t learned how to code their designs into XHTML and CSS code. This is where many popular companies come in to help, the most popular being psd2html.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;amp;A with Premium Wordpress Theme Developer WPMonk</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many premium Wordpress themes roam the internet these days, all of varying quality and development. I recently found a really neat Premium Wordpress design company WP Monk. They run a very impressive website design, plus their premium themes are impeccable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional Freelance Web Designer Shay Howe</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the fastest growing professions is website design and web developers, especially with the attraction of working freelance. Many people hate the 9-5 grind induced through corporate America, and having the option to work from home on your own time seems like a much more viable and interesting option to many. Although in the end it may require a bit more work on your end, the ultimate freedom of your time seems to pay for itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with a Digg.com Software Engineer Kurt Wilms</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-a-digg.com-software-engineer-kurt-wilms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-a-digg.com-software-engineer-kurt-wilms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a web designer myself, I have found that other web designers I talk to always have favorite websites they go to for inspiration. Not saying they want to copy a specific website, but there are just some site&amp;rsquo;s that &amp;ldquo;stick&amp;rdquo; and really inspire you to create web designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with ThisWebHost - An Impressive new Web Hosting Company</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-thiswebhost-an-impressive-new-web-hosting-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-thiswebhost-an-impressive-new-web-hosting-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding a decent web hosting company today is difficult. So many companies overprice, can&amp;rsquo;t keep uptime promises, have horrible support, or offer you barely any space to store your site&amp;rsquo;s files and content. The few that have shown promise in the past are some of my favorites: Hostgator, Dreamhost, Bluehost, etc. However as I was browsing the web one night (like always) I ran into a great looking hosting company, This*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Posterous.com:  Filesharing Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing files over the internet used to be a devilish task. Finding the right application, storage space, or transporation method for files used to be very difficult only 5 years ago. Now with file upload sites and forums/bulletin boards to share files, sending your friend a song or posting up a funny picture has never been easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CollegeHumor&#39;s Designer Anna Hiort</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten my fair share of laughs from all of the hilarious content on the internet today. Photoshopped photos and amazing/retarded videos are spread like wildfire through forums and social networking sites. However, one of the best sites I&amp;rsquo;ve ever run across for generally hilarious content has to be Collegehumor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with New Web 2.0 Web Conferencing Tool Fuze Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-new-web-2.0-web-conferencing-tool-fuze-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-new-web-2.0-web-conferencing-tool-fuze-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We can all agree that connecting with each other is important. This is especially the case in the world of business, where communications can be as important as arranging a business meeting promptly at 9:30AM. I spoke with Patrick Moran of Fuze Meeting&amp;rsquo;s Marketing division, and got the inside scoop on the new web conferencing tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage Your Businesses Internet Marketing with twtapps</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/manage-your-businesses-internet-marketing-with-twtapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/manage-your-businesses-internet-marketing-with-twtapps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has skyrocketed into mainstream with seemingly no meaning behind it. The simple application allowing everyone in the world to share what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, thinking, or feeling in 140 characters has grown into one of the most popular web 2.0 applications on the web, and it&amp;rsquo;s no doubt there are many apps on the web to accompany it. Although not affiliate with Twitter in any way, twtapps is a neat website that features some of the coolest web 2.0 applications that help businesses market on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with ManageME7: Learn to Save Your Money the Easy Way!</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-manageme7-learn-to-save-your-money-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-manageme7-learn-to-save-your-money-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for some stability with your income? I think we all do, since we all can&amp;rsquo;t make 100k every month. Especially in times like these, managing money properly is a great skill to have and utilize, and knowing when to spend money and on what can be a challenge. With manageME7, you can manage your money 7 days a week, 24 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with GigTide - The Online Resume Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-gigtide-the-online-resume-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-gigtide-the-online-resume-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many online applications to help with business-type things: You&amp;rsquo;ve got your invoice applications, e-mail marketing, time management, project management&amp;hellip; the list could go on and on. And although there are so many sites out there for businesses to utilize, GigTide is definitely one of the greatest all-around useful sites for anybody looking to create, manage, or perfect their resume&amp;rsquo;s online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Task.fm - The world&#39;s simplest reminder app</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-task.fm-the-worlds-simplest-reminder-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-task.fm-the-worlds-simplest-reminder-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently been scoping out some cool web 2.0 sites to add to my blog for my first interview, and I found my answer lying in the new startup task.fm. This app has only been online for about a week so far, but already has a booming userbase of 1000 regular users and growing daily. Task.fm allows its users to have reminders sent through e-mail, phone, and SMS. The reminders can be entered by the user, and typed in regular speech, too! Below is my interview with the site&amp;rsquo;s creator Anthony Feint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Need Financial Regulation?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-do-we-need-financial-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-do-we-need-financial-regulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[1]  “The purpose of financial regulation is to improve upon the performance of financial markets relative to how they would perform driven solely by the forces of the private marketplace.” Banking is one of the most highly regulated industries within the United States.  We can understand the impact of regulation by taking a look at the history and evolution of the banking system through to the present day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-early-banking-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Early Banking System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the early days of banking, the industry has faced many changes in regulation due to different needs arising throughout the years.  In the early days, government control was not favored among most of the original settlers who had come from countries where too much federal control was exerted.  Therefore the early banking system comprised of a multitude of different small banks printing their own currency, which would often fail and leave customers with lost funds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Financial Transactions</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/electronic-financial-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/electronic-financial-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electronic financial transactions have become a common part of everyday life with enhancements in technology and a gradual acceptance and trust of these new ways of doing business.  As the world continues to grow smaller through communication and other technologies, demands have increased dramatically for methods of providing instant financial services.  This has become especially true for people traveling globally with a need to access their finances in different currencies.  Both credit and debit card transactions provide a convenient 24 hour per day access to funds on demand, while other technologies are available for wiring money and sending electronic funds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work Visas within the United States</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/work-visas-within-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/work-visas-within-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more companies within the US are hiring foreign personnel on work visas.  As a result, it is vital that any organization wishing to hire a person from a different country must fully understand the laws behind the process of sponsoring an alien to work for their business.  Obtaining work visas can be complicated and, more importantly, time-consuming processes. It is therefore vital that business objectives be clearly established and that visa planning occurs as early as possible to ensure a smooth process of employment.  There are many ways that foreign citizens can apply for residence to the United States; however, the focus of this research paper is on obtaining a work visa through organizational sponsorship and does not outline immigration-visas or ‘green cards’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Dynamics within Marconi Communications</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/team-dynamics-within-marconi-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/team-dynamics-within-marconi-communications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marconi is a Telecommunication and Networking solutions organization involved in new technology products and solutions as well as the service to provide invaluable support to its customers.  Marconi was originally a division of the former General Electric Corp (GEC) of Great Britain.  Several years ago, the newly installed executive management of GEC realized that the conglomerate was essentially a slow growth entity with poor shareholder growth prospects.  Several of the companies that were a part of the GEC, had a foundation of a strong telecommunications and networking business, one with rapid growth performance and prospects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of the Internet &amp; Service Providers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/development-of-the-internet-service-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/development-of-the-internet-service-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet was the result of some visionary people in the early 1960s who saw great potential value in allowing computers to share information on research and development in scientific and military fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howe, W (1998) A Brief History of the Internet&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www0.delphi.com/navnet/faq/history.html&#34;&gt;http://www0.delphi.com/navnet/faq/history.html&lt;/a&gt; (January 28th, 2000)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history-of-the-internet&#34;&gt;History of the Internet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has had a relatively brief but also explosive history over the last few decades. It originated from an experiment, started by the U.S. Department of Defence during the 1960s. The Department of Defence wanted to create a computer network that would continue to function in the event of a disaster, such as a nuclear war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of ISPs Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/evolution-of-isps-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/evolution-of-isps-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Internet has grown beyond a simple tool for a small number of education and government agencies over the last few years. The commercialization of the Internet has opened a brand new market for small, medium and large commercial bodies to provide access to this huge network of opportunity for business and home users alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These companies are the sole providers of access to the ‘Information Super-Highway’ and it is therefore important to analyse how they have managed to survive in the past as well as their current and future success. The basis of this dissertation has concentrated mainly on the small to medium sized ISP providing services to the local business community and tends to concentrate on the issues involved here. It is important to look into periods of the past few years and how ISPs have developed into the providers that are common on the market place today. Through analysing the changes that ISPs have faced in the past, this will give a better gauge as to where the ISP needs to look to for future opportunities and more importantly, future survival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISPs Currently in Today’s Changing Market</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/isps-currently-in-todays-changing-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/isps-currently-in-todays-changing-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned within the last chapter, Internet Service Providers have been forced and are currently being driven away from the traditional subscription access only service. Nowadays, many ISPs have started to offer free access to the Internet in order to drive customers to their services. The first of this kind of service within the United Kingdom was Freeserve. They originally had the backing of the Currys group to market their free Tier 3 ISP to the general public, which proved to be extremely successful. After the launch of Freeserve, many other Internet Service Providers began to offer free access through a dial-up service in order to compete within the market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ITS Internet Case Study</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/its-internet-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/its-internet-case-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been surprising to see the amount of small Internet based companies that have ‘made it big’ within a very short period of time. Perhaps it has been the pure innovation of releasing a particular service on-line or offering goods that no one else had yet thought of. Perhaps it has just been a case of the company getting in before others had giving them the edge that would continue for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Issues to be Addressed by ISPs</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/security-issues-to-be-addressed-by-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/security-issues-to-be-addressed-by-isps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become a vast marketplace for global goods and services. For e-commerce to prosper, you have to feel safe about transmitting credit card and other financial information over the Internet. Because information traveling over the network actually passes through many computers along the way, the opportunity exists for someone to steal confidential information. Hackers also break into computers to steal data. No one really knows how often this actually happens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Internet Service Providers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-evolution-of-internet-service-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-evolution-of-internet-service-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Internet has grown beyond a simple tool for a small number of education and government agencies over the last few years. The commercialization of the Internet has opened a brand new market for small, medium and large commercial bodies to provide access to this huge network of opportunity for business and home users alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These companies are the sole providers of access to the ‘Information Super-Highway’ and it is therefore important to analyse how they have managed to survive in the past as well as their current and future success. The basis of this dissertation has concentrated mainly on the small to medium sized ISP providing services to the local business community and tends to concentrate on the issues involved here. It is important to look into periods of the past few years and how ISPs have developed into the providers that are common on the market place today. Through analysing the changes that ISPs have faced in the past, this will give a better gauge as to where the ISP needs to look to for future opportunities and more importantly, future survival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of ISPs</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-future-of-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-future-of-isps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet Service Providers (ISP) frequently have to face the question as to how they can protect their existing business and, at the same time, remain profitable in the future. For, on the one hand, the strong concentration process drastically shrinks the margins of pure access providing. New competitors, for example the major telecommunications companies, are flooding the market with ever cheaper offers. Prices continue to fall. And customers, who are becoming more and more &amp;ldquo;literate&amp;rdquo;, are now designing their own HTML pages. To quote a study issued by the European Union (EG DGXIII.A3) ISPs will not survive in the long term if they do not provide add-on services such as consulting or electronic publishing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSI (Ireland) Ltd.</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tsi-ireland-ltd./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/tsi-ireland-ltd./</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-information&#34;&gt;Background Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TSI Ireland was formed over a year ago in February 1999 as a Private Limited Company.  Financial backing came from the two partners within the company, Mr. Martin Hamill and Mr. Eric Carson (Business Manager for Orange, Northern Ireland).  Staff comprised of 6 full time workers split into the following areas: two Administration personnel, a telecoms engineer, sales director, account manager and the managing director.  The company also undertakes contract work from additional 6 workers who are primarily involved with sales.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Behavior Leadership and Teamwork</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-behavior-leadership-and-teamwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-behavior-leadership-and-teamwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the summer of 1997 I worked for a period of four months on a contract for a company called the Environment and Heritage Service (EHS) Northern Ireland.  During this time I worked primarily within the Computing Department of the organization and our team was involved with all the Information Technology issues across the various offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper will look at the two main areas of leadership and team working as I learned a great deal while working there.  The main Information Technology department comprised of a Systems Manager with three main Network Managers working for him and staff working under the database managers for various computing related jobs. To give an idea of the responsibilities of the staff within the computing department I will list briefly what each position has entailed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of having one large government over individual governments</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/advantages-of-having-one-large-government-over-individual-governments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/advantages-of-having-one-large-government-over-individual-governments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The information gathered for this essay on social space and the European Social Chapter was obtained from various sources.  These included Internet sites listed in the Bibliography and numerous books and material from the University of Ulster Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will attempt to show how the benefits for and the objectives against the European Social Chapter affect social space within various countries in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;european-social-space&#34;&gt;EUROPEAN SOCIAL SPACE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind social space within the European Union has highlighted certain areas of concern within countries of the European Union.  Employment, industrial health, social costs of industry, labour mobility and social spending within these countries are all elements dealt within European Social Space.  Social space also involves education, training, housing and health.  Over recent years the issues of social welfare have become extremely important as the EU has grown.  One of the main reasons for this is that public expectations have increased rapidly that their governments will play a major role in improving overall quality of life, bringing social affairs firmly into the public domain.  It is only over recent years that the idea of Social Space within the European Union has become a vital factor to the expansion of the EC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manpower Planning Versus Human Resource Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/manpower-planning-versus-human-resource-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/manpower-planning-versus-human-resource-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The differences between manpower planning and human resource planning will be outlined within this essay along with how human resource planning has built on and developed traditional manpower planning. The main sources of information to compile this assignment have come mostly from Coleraine and Jordanstown University of Ulster Libraries and the books used and referred to have been listed in the references and bibliography section of this essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;manpower-planning&#34;&gt;MANPOWER PLANNING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason the process of manpower planning came about was to help the management of employees within a business organization.  Manpower planning looks at the organizations current and future need of labour within the business.  The current and future employment needs are a great concern and the examination of supply within the local area for possible new employees if required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tesco - Marketing Strategy in Northern Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tesco-marketing-strategy-in-northern-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/tesco-marketing-strategy-in-northern-ireland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early in 1996 the supermarket giant Tesco bought over the complete Stewarts / Crazy Prices group for an investment of £641 million.  By 24th November 1996 Crazy Prices, Abbeycentre had been converted to Tesco, Abbeycentre after several other branches including Carrickfergus had undergone the same changeover earlier on in the year.  Although many of the objectives of the company remain the same there are noticeable changes that have occurred within the company as a whole. I will not be focusing on the past ‘Crazy Prices / Stewarts / West Side Stores’ supermarkets therefore as all of my research has been based around the newer Tesco developments&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
