<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Themes on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/themes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Themes on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/themes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Themeisle Hestia Pro review</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/themeisle-hestia-pro-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/themeisle-hestia-pro-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hestia Pro is a powerful material design based WP template with which you can launch websites of various types without writing a single line of code. It is one of the best multi-purpose WordPress themes. According to Themeisle, the developer of Hesita Pro, HP is idle for business, blog, e-commerce sites based on the WordPress content management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the Hestia Pro theme SEO friendly and fast? Should you replace your current theme with it? Here&amp;rsquo;s my review of this premium WP template:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress News Pro theme review</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-news-pro-theme-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-news-pro-theme-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;News Pro is one of the flagship StudioPress themes. It is also one of the most widely used WP magazine templates. Powered by the HTML5 markup, StudioPress NP is based on minimal flat responsive design. It is ideal for magazine sites that cover a variety of topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NP is built on Genesis Framework which powers 100K+ sites. Is the News Pro theme suitable for your site? Is it easy to use and SEO friendly? Let&amp;rsquo;s find it out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academy Pro review: Great theme for educational and membership sites</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/academy-pro-review-great-theme-for-educational-and-membership-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/academy-pro-review-great-theme-for-educational-and-membership-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academy Pro is a premium WordPress theme developed by StudioPress. It has a brilliant design and many features. It is ideal for membership and educational websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academy Pro is powered by Genesis framework and it looks great on all types of computing devices. Here&amp;rsquo;s my review of this theme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academy-pro-review&#34;&gt;Academy Pro review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other StudioPress templates, AP is easy to install. Once you download the theme, use the WordPress Content Management System&amp;rsquo;s theme installer tool to get started with Academy Pro. Here are the various features of this theme:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monstroid2 review: A great multipurpose WordPress bootstrap theme</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/monstroid2-review-a-great-multipurpose-wordpress-bootstrap-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/monstroid2-review-a-great-multipurpose-wordpress-bootstrap-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monstroid2 is a premium multipurpose WordPress theme powered by Twitter Bootstrap and Cherry Framework, a secure modular open-source framework for developing themes and plugins. It is the successor to the Monstroid theme which had become a talk of the town within few months of its launch. Monstroid2 has new and powerful features. It also includes a powerful live theme customizer and page builder tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme has been developed by a firm called Jetimpex. Like StudioPress, Elegant Themes, Jetimpex is one of the top WP development companies. JI has launched 100+ templates for WordPress, Joomla, Prestashop on TemplateMonster, a marketplace for webmasters and developers. It has also published several plain HTML templates. Monstroid is Jetimpex&amp;rsquo;s best-selling WP theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to test WordPress plugins online without installing?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-test-wordpress-plugins-online-without-installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-test-wordpress-plugins-online-without-installing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your site is getting good traffic, and if a new version of the plugin you&amp;rsquo;re using has been launched, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the following two questions in the mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the plugin break your site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the plugin worth installing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the plugins are thoroughly tested before launch, it may have some bugs. If you install the update, your site may crash or it may add HTML code which may affect your site&amp;rsquo;s ranking in Google or Bing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avada Theme review: Is it the best premium WordPress theme?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/avada-theme-review-is-it-the-best-premium-wordpress-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/avada-theme-review-is-it-the-best-premium-wordpress-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avada is a top-rated premium WP theme, which you can download from ThemeForest marketplace. There are plenty of free themes that haven&amp;rsquo;t surpassed 1000 downloads. Interestingly, Avada has 300K+ users. It is not only best-selling WordPress theme on the ThemeForest market place but also the most popular premium WP template. Themeforest is a marketplace where developers across from various parts of the world publish their products. As the ratings and reviews are not in control of theme and plugin developers, you can consider ThemeForest as a transparent marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Best WordPress directory theme (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-wordpress-directory-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-wordpress-directory-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A directory site has a massive listing of businesses. If a site is successful, it will have a listing of 1000+ business. A small site may have fewer listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEO plays a key role in deciding the fate of a directory site. A well-optimized website will rank high in search engines. A good example of this is Yelp, a large restaurant directory site that ranks at number 1 position in Google SERPs for several 1000 keywords. We must not forget that Yelp has 100s of employees working 24 x 7.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Best WordPress restaurant theme (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-10-best-wordpress-restaurant-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-10-best-wordpress-restaurant-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of free website builder tools with which you can launch a restaurant site within an hour. The site builders have limited features. Furthermore, they don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to add maps, reservation forms, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about your restaurant business, you must use the WordPress CMS. WP allows you to create an incredibly powerful restaurant website within 50 to 55 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To launch your restaurant site, you must download one of below top WordPress restaurant themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress Foodie Pro Theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-foodie-pro-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-foodie-pro-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike tech and WordPress niche, food blogging is not a competitive niche. Hence, if you share unique recipes on the food blog, you can make good money online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to start a food blog or you already own a food blog, your objective should be to get as many loyal visitors as you can and make money from the site without affecting the visitor experience. To get desired results, you must use a powerful and SEO friendly food blog theme. One of the best templates for the recipe sites is Foodie Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themify Ultra theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/themify-ultra-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/themify-ultra-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress theme development companies don&amp;rsquo;t run for a long time unless they offer quality support to the customers or launch products that are worth the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themify is one of the most successful WP theme development firms. It has introduced several themes till date. The themes launched by this firm are active on 50000+ sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular theme from Themify is the Ultra theme. I had purchased the WordPress Ultra theme a few months back and I&amp;rsquo;m using it on two sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Best WordPress Magazine themes (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-6-best-wordpress-magazine-themes-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-6-best-wordpress-magazine-themes-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magazine themes are used on WordPress News sites of all types of niches. A news website may have several categories and tags. To make sure that the visitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t get bored while browsing the site, your site should have attractive pages and powerful navigation system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the theme must allow users to customize pages with easy so that you can test the performance of various layouts. Frankly speaking, free themes have limited features and customizing them is a difficult task. Only the users with good knowledge of PHP and CSS can customize their sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegant Themes review 2018: Great themes for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/elegant-themes-review-2018-great-themes-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/elegant-themes-review-2018-great-themes-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A theme is responsible for the success of a blogger. Many bloggers end up buying a theme which looks attractive but scores 0 when it comes to SEO. Despite publishing high-quality content on their sites, these bloggers don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy success and they quit blogging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newbie blogger, I had committed a huge mistake of trusting a third class theme developer. The developer rolled out an update which created the dreaded duplicate title, meta description problem on my site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus WordPress theme review (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/nexus-wordpress-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/nexus-wordpress-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nexus is a powerful WordPress magazine theme developed by ElegantThemes. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t aware, ET is one of the top WP theme and plugin development companies. Some of its most popular products are Divi theme, Monarch social sharing plugin, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nexus template has a beautiful layout and it provides a plethora of widgets. It is a customizable theme that supports full-width layout. It is ideal for news websites and blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ark WordPress theme review 2018: Killer WP Business template</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/ark-wordpress-theme-review-2018-killer-wp-business-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/ark-wordpress-theme-review-2018-killer-wp-business-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ark theme for WordPress was introduced on Themeforest marketplace in December 2016. Within a month of its launch, Ark has registered 1000+ downloads. It has an excellent rating of 5 from 50+ users. The theme has 200+ customizable elements and 1000+ customization options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ark was declared the top-selling WordPress theme last month. It has become a popular item on ThemeForest within a month of its launch is because FreshLance (developer) is selling the powerful feature rich Ark template for an unbelievable price of $29.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magazine Pro Theme Review 2018 : SEO Friendly and Fast</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/magazine-pro-theme-review-2018-seo-friendly-and-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/magazine-pro-theme-review-2018-seo-friendly-and-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magazine Pro Theme from StudioPress is a powerful WP template for news and technology websites. It is based on responsive and minimal design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme lacks lengthy CSS and JS codes and it looks great. It has clean SEO friendly HTML tags. The small assets and search engine friendly nature of the Magazine Pro make it one of the fastest loading WordPress themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M Pro Genesis Child theme comes with valid Schema markups that help search engines identify various elements on your site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right way to update a WordPress theme or plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-right-way-to-update-a-wordpress-theme-or-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-right-way-to-update-a-wordpress-theme-or-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Themes and plugins are the most important parts of a WordPress website. If the code of the theme is not SEO friendly, your site will not perform well in search engines. Likewise, if the plugin has an erroneous code, it can lead to poor user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In worst cases, the problematic theme or plugin may cause high server resource utilization. The search bots will begin to ignore your site. If you don&amp;rsquo;t fix the problem ASAP, the site&amp;rsquo;s rankings will tank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyThemeShop Authority theme review 2018 : Feature packed SEO optimized template</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-authority-theme-review-2018-feature-packed-seo-optimized-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-authority-theme-review-2018-feature-packed-seo-optimized-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authority is one of the best-selling WordPress templates of MyThemeShop. It has a large number of users. It is inspired by design of the website of popular blogger Matthew Woodward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authority is a responsive WordPress theme that supports customization of almost every element you&amp;rsquo;ll find on it. It has amazing page speed. It is a premium template with great design and plenty of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mythemeshop-authority-wordpress-theme-review&#34;&gt;MyThemeShop Authority WordPress theme review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you buy the theme, download its ZIP file and upload it to the wp-content folder of your blog. Extract the zip file and activate the theme from your WordPress dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress BeTheme review (2018) : Super theme to Build any type of site</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-betheme-review-2018-super-theme-to-build-any-type-of-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-betheme-review-2018-super-theme-to-build-any-type-of-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BeTheme is a responsive multipurpose WP Premium template compatible with BuddyPress, WooCommerce, Gravity forms, BBpress, and many other premium WordPress products. It works on IE9 to IE11 browsers and other top web browsers such as Google Chrome, Opera, Safari, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeTheme has over 45000 users. It is one of the best-selling paid WordPress themes of all time and the best product from top WP development firm Muffingroup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to buying a WordPress Theme which you can model into any type of website, then you should check out the BeTheme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPI Smart Passive Income Pro Theme Review (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/spi-smart-passive-income-pro-theme-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/spi-smart-passive-income-pro-theme-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;StupdioPress has launched the new Smart Passive Income Pro theme which resembles the blog of famous blogger Patt Flynn. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Patt is one of the smartest affiliate marketing professionals who has been making over $100000 every month through his Smart Passive Income blog. Patt Flynn has earned over a 3 million dollars so far because of his great strategies and smart design of his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlighting feature of SPI Pro theme is its large fonts in the footer, sidebar, and header section. The big size immaculate fonts give a distinct look to the blog using the SPI Pro template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extra WordPress Theme Review 2018 : Superb Theme powered by Divi Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/extra-wordpress-theme-review-2018-superb-theme-powered-by-divi-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/extra-wordpress-theme-review-2018-superb-theme-powered-by-divi-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a searching for a multi-purpose WordPress theme which supports customization up to a great extent, then you&amp;rsquo;re at the right place. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared a detailed review of the ET Extra Theme. Extra is one of the best selling themes from ElegantThemes. It is also one of the most beautiful templates I&amp;rsquo;ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it is a multipurpose theme, you can easily create a WP based eCommerce, Portfolio, News, Magazine, Food blog with Extra. Below are the highlighting features of Xtra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to buy WordPress themes when free templates are available?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-to-buy-wordpress-themes-when-free-templates-are-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-to-buy-wordpress-themes-when-free-templates-are-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is a great content management system because it allows users to launch a new self-hosted blog or website within half an hour. Launching a site is easy but you&amp;rsquo;ll not make money with it if the site doesn&amp;rsquo;t get decent traffic from search engines. To make sure that the site is SEO friendly, you must write good quality content, buy a good hosting plan, and purchase a premium theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StudioPress Genesis Pro Plus Package : All themes at great price</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-genesis-pro-plus-package-all-themes-at-great-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/studiopress-genesis-pro-plus-package-all-themes-at-great-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;StudioPress Genesis Framework powers 1000s of WordPress sites. It is better than Thesis and many other WP frameworks. It is SEO friendly, mobile optimized, lightweight, and fast. SGF includes several intuitive features. It includes special modules that save your money. Example, you won&amp;rsquo;t need a premium opt-in form aka newsletter plugin if you use SGF. Many top bloggers who earn six figure income per month use SGF. StudioPress Genesis is the highest rated and most successful WordPress product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Genesis Child Themes for blogs and business (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-genesis-child-themes-for-blogs-and-business-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-genesis-child-themes-for-blogs-and-business-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genesis Framework is a WordPress product from the owners of Copyblogger content marketing blog. It is so popular that every blogger using WP is aware of the Genesis Framework and its premium themes. If your site is using this framework, then you&amp;rsquo;ll not face any SEO issues unless you do something wrong Ex: changing code. Genesis Framework powers many top websites and blogs built with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the themes launched by StudioPress Genesis Framework are SEO friendly, responsive, Google AdSense ready, and adhere to HTML5 standards. As they are designed and developed by experts, the templates performance will be great even if the user is using shared hosting service. In case you&amp;rsquo;re planning to purchase the StudioPress Genesis Framework, go through the paragraphs we have shared below as today we&amp;rsquo;ve shared the top best Genesis Child Themes for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyThemeShop Schema Theme Review 2018 : 100% SEO friendly template</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-schema-theme-review-2018-100-seo-friendly-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-schema-theme-review-2018-100-seo-friendly-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a premium WordPress theme ensures that you&amp;rsquo;ll be given assistance when you encounter problems with the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme will have clean code and it will be search engine and mobile friendly. Unfortunately, the premium theme which I used earlier on this blog was a waste of my money. I had bought it when I was a newbie blogger after reading a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme was good initially, but the developer removed its inbuilt review system. When I asked the development team why they did so? They asked me to wait for a few weeks because they&amp;rsquo;ll be launching a review plugin. It has been 5 months now, the plugins have not been released yet. All my reviews and the schema start rating markups were gone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classipress review : Best WordPress classifieds theme (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/classipress-review-best-wordpress-classifieds-theme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/classipress-review-best-wordpress-classifieds-theme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a classified site manually from scratch is not an easy task. You must have exceptional website development skills with good knowledge of local SEO, server configuration, database, HTML, JavaScript, and a website scripting language like PHP, Ruby on Rails, ASP, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills mentioned above, there&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to launch a classified website. Yes, Believe Me! You can quickly launch your own classified&amp;rsquo;s portal like OLX, Quikr, Craigslist in half an hour with the world&amp;rsquo;s most robust content management system named WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mythemeshop review 2018 : Amazing themes and plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-review-2018-amazing-themes-and-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mythemeshop-review-2018-amazing-themes-and-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a premium theme or plugin is not an easy task as there are a lot of WP developers who have launched a variety of templates for the users. To make things less complicated and easy for you, we are trying our level best to shared a detailed review on themes launched by top developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, we had shared a detailed and honest review on Elegant Divi and Themeforest NewsPaper. After going through the two powerful templates, we&amp;rsquo;ve concluded that ET and TF are undoubtedly 2 of the top platform for buying a high-quality WordPress plugin or templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIVI Theme Review 2018 : A great Multi Purpose WordPress Template</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/divi-theme-review-2018-a-great-multi-purpose-wordpress-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/divi-theme-review-2018-a-great-multi-purpose-wordpress-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elegant Themes is known for its blazing fast and highly responsive mobile friendly WordPress templates and plugins. It is the only developer that offers all its premium 50+ themes and plugins on a payment of 89 dollars. Others will charge you the same amount for a single theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The templates published by ET are updated, and they adhere to every SEO and webmaster standards that you might be aware of. They have been featured on Mashable, Smashing Magazine, and many other top blogs. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen ET plugins on high traffic blogs that have millions of page views every month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress X Theme Review 2018: Fast WP template with great features</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-x-theme-review-2018-fast-wp-template-with-great-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/wordpress-x-theme-review-2018-fast-wp-template-with-great-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bloggers want a lot of features in their themes. They also expect their WordPress blogs and websites to load fast. Free templates have limited support and features. Thus, many of the bloggers buy a premium template. Before they make payment, the user will explore 100s of available options. This task induces a headache and creates a lot of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, it is a job for professional and experienced bloggers like me to make newbies or WordPress users aware of the top themes. Last week, we published a detailed review of Newspaper template. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed one of the most popular and powerful WordPress theme named X. No other WP template is as perfect and user-friendly as X.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Best WordPress coupon themes (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-wordpress-coupon-themes-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-wordpress-coupon-themes-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coupon websites can be very profitable if you bring traffic to it. For example, RetailmeNot consistently earns over 100 million dollars in revenue it has millions of monthly unique visitors. It is nothing but a well-designed coupon site. Coupon Raja was bought by one of the India&amp;rsquo;s largest media hours, i.e., Times Group. Before being purchased, it had reported over five crores of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such sites, you will find short posts with an affiliate link to eCommerce portal or any other service. This post includes rating, code, social sharing links, and a small description. When the user clicks on your link and makes a purchase from the affiliate, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a commission. By the month end, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive payment via cheque, PayPal or net banking. All affiliate account include a dashboard where you can find details on the clicks, conversion rate, returns, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themeforest Newspaper WordPress Theme Review</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/themeforest-newspaper-wordpress-theme-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/themeforest-newspaper-wordpress-theme-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Newspaper themes for WordPress are recommended for technology, travel, health, news, video and sports niche blogs. There are a lot of newspaper and magazine themes available for download in the wordpress.org directory. Most of them claim to be SEO friendly but unfortunately they&amp;rsquo;re not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free themes have a major drawback that their support is limited. If you encounter any problems, you will have to post your query on WordPress.org forum. Most of the times, instead of the developers, other users will help you out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best free WordPress themes that are responsive</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-free-wordpress-themes-that-are-responsive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-free-wordpress-themes-that-are-responsive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, Google had rolled out its mobile friendly algorithm update. As a part of Google&amp;rsquo;s strategy to improve the user experience of search engine users, websites that were not having responsive design or websites whose theme was not mobile friendly were penalized. Immediately after the Google algorithm update, Bing updated its search algorithm to improve rankings of responsive and mobile friendly websites. If you&amp;rsquo;re a webmaster or a newbie blogger, you should use the below &lt;strong&gt;free themes for WordPress:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
