<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Top-Websites on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/top-websites/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top-Websites on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/top-websites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 8 Best Business Listing Sites (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-8-best-business-listing-sites-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-8-best-business-listing-sites-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of internet users has grown from 100 to 3+ billion. Although a lot of firms have benefited from the internet revolution, many businesses have become bankrupt. eCommerce platforms have destroyed the business of 1000s of brick and mortar stores. The only way to survive the wrath of these sites is to make people aware of your shop/service and the products you sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listing a business online is the best way to promote it. Although there are 100s of sites where you can list your office, shop, or service, not all sites are trustworthy or complete. Businesses won&amp;rsquo;t benefit from such sites. Hence, they should not be listed on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best IDE for PHP Web Development</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-ide-for-php-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-ide-for-php-web-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PHP is a scripting language that powers over some of the busiest websites on the web. Several languages have been introduced since 2005. None of them have affected the popularity of PHP. Before IDEs were launched, seasoned developers and beginners used vi or notepad to write PHP code. Once the code was ready, developers moved the PHP file to the webapps folder of the web server to check whether their code is working as expected or not. If the browser didn&amp;rsquo;t display error, developers used to check log files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best blogs to read daily : Top Tech, Design, IT blogs in world</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-blogs-to-read-daily-top-tech-design-it-blogs-in-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-blogs-to-read-daily-top-tech-design-it-blogs-in-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our today&amp;rsquo;s article - 10 most popular blogs on the internet (2015) has been published to inspire you. As a blogger, you need inspiration. Many times, you may not be satisfied with your online career and you may think to quit blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t recommend you to do this as many months of your hard work will go in vain. Just go through the content published on the most popular blogs. Quality content has helped the best websites on the internet to rank very high in search engines. As they rank high, they get 1000&amp;rsquo;s of do-follow natural backlinks every day. The owners of these blogs are self-made millionaires and they&amp;rsquo;re an inspiration to all of us. If you&amp;rsquo;re a newbie blogger, your articles won&amp;rsquo;t rank as high as the articles found on the most popular blogs. But they&amp;rsquo;ll outrank low quality and thin websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
