<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social-News on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/social-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social-News on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/social-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MySpace More Layoffs and Reflecting on What Went Wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last July, Inside the Webb reported on new changes coming to MySpace in an effort to streamline the overall design of the social networking giant. As reported at the time, the changes were long overdue, however overhauling such a large organization was no easy task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Page /r/circlejerk Clones 4Chan&#39;s Website Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After visiting Reddit today, it was pretty obvious my favorite SubReddit circlejerk was up to no good. After toying around all week with a funny upvote arrow which looked similar to male genitalia, we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen an invasion of 4chan into Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digzign - New Social News for Designers that Dig</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social news has sprung along the web, and with the popularity of web design and graphics blogs sharing links has become commonplace. With popular sites such as DesignFloat and DesignBump, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine much else. However I have recently found a great-looking Digg clone website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://digzign.com/&#34;&gt;http://digzign.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixx Partners with Marketfish for New Ad Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mixx-partners-with-marketfish-for-new-ad-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mixx-partners-with-marketfish-for-new-ad-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the popularity of social news, there have been many launches and premieres of new apps on the scene. One of the most popular and rising clone site&amp;rsquo;s is Mixx.com. Very similar to Digg, Mixx allows users to vote up the hottest articles and news based on categories ranging from world news, technology, science, and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Digg&#39;s New Ad System is Gaining Popularity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has always been an extremely innovative company. Launching into the social news bit in 2004, the site has grown immensely popular with monthly pageviews in the tens of millions. Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity has allowed for a counter-culture of internet users to become Diggers, voting on the best stories to hit the front page and sent traffic spikes to interesting and useful blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Newest Trending Social News Sharing Community Humsurfer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult these days to track down the best social news sharing communities. There are the classics such as Digg and Reddit, and also smaller niche communities containing topics like design and programming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Digg-Clone Thuhm Updates Design and Added Features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-clone-thuhm-updates-design-and-added-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-clone-thuhm-updates-design-and-added-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had written a Review for Thuhm a while back, and have to say I still love the app. It&amp;rsquo;s a brand new social news website for sharing all kinds of news, and it combines the best features of Reddit and Digg together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although still just breaking off the ground, Thuhm has a lot to offer it&amp;rsquo;s readers. Recently there had been a post mentioning new updates on the site, including a new front page design and the addition of categories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing DesignMoo for Social Media Traffic to your Design Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all of you running a design blog out there, DesignMoo is a site you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to bookmark. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all know of Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity, this has caused many smaller sites to spawn offspring and grow into micro-niche Digg sites. DesignMoo is one of these style of sites for graphic and web design, and can bring in a lot of traffic to your blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CypherBox.net - Great Pligg-based PR4 Social Bookmarking Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cypherbox.net-great-pligg-based-pr4-social-bookmarking-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cypherbox.net-great-pligg-based-pr4-social-bookmarking-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just want to say, I absolutely love Pligg. It&amp;rsquo;s an amazing PHP script, free to download which allows you to set up your own social news site similar to Digg. Many micro-niche sites have popped up running on Pligg&amp;rsquo;s backend, and CypherBox is my latest find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Digg.com is heading for a Major Pitfall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-digg.com-is-heading-for-a-major-pitfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-digg.com-is-heading-for-a-major-pitfall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember a time when Digg used to roam wild in the Social News kingdom. It was the force to be reckoned with when it came to internet marketing - everybody needed to hit the front page to gain some traffic to their site. I&amp;rsquo;m sure tons of blogs have built their popularity off of Digg&amp;rsquo;s massive traffic influx, but there are many signs pointing towards this site closing the lid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Digg-Themed Social News and Media Website Thuhm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has become the popular site for internet marketers and bloggers to aspire to. Digg used to be a popular tech website, where tech enthusiasts and internet lovers could gather to share links. Whichever links got the most &amp;ldquo;diggs&amp;rdquo; would hit the front page, generally to recieve a surge of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring TortoiseSVN to Manage Updates on Pligg Sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/configuring-tortoisesvn-to-manage-updates-on-pligg-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/configuring-tortoisesvn-to-manage-updates-on-pligg-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am extremely fond of the new social news script Pligg CMS. I have been following it since early release, and updating Pligg sites used to be very difficult. However from instructions from this wiki, you can use TortoiseSVN to control the version and upgrades of your Pligg site with ease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with a Digg.com Software Engineer Kurt Wilms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-a-digg.com-software-engineer-kurt-wilms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-a-digg.com-software-engineer-kurt-wilms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a web designer myself, I have found that other web designers I talk to always have favorite websites they go to for inspiration. Not saying they want to copy a specific website, but there are just some site&amp;rsquo;s that &amp;ldquo;stick&amp;rdquo; and really inspire you to create web designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founder of Omegle.com Answers Questions From Redditors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omegle.com has spread across many social networking hubs, forums, and internet chatrooms rapidly over the past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s a new site with a very simple concept: you log in anonymously and talk to someone else. Someone random, someone you&amp;rsquo;ve *probably* never even met before, just talking about whatever. It seems like a breeding ground for spam and pranks, but it ultimately seen very positive results in traffic and user response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collection of Photos from Digg&#39;s Office in San Francisco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collection-of-photos-from-diggs-office-in-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collection-of-photos-from-diggs-office-in-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg is undoubtedly the most popular social news website on the internet. Hell, it sort of invented the social news genre itself! Digg has been a huge inspiration to me as a designer and developer, and I have learned so much through Digg&amp;rsquo;s progression over the years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Digg-Clone for Designers DesignBump</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg was the first social news site to really skyrocket into popularity, gaining millions of pageviews a day to the site. No doubt, there would be similar sites in separate niches on the web. The first of these niche sites in the web design category was Design Float, which has had many issues with databases and keeping the site up and running properly. Therefore, a new competitor has stepped up to the plate: DesignBump.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with the Genius Behind Fark, Drew Curtis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-the-genius-behind-fark-drew-curtis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-the-genius-behind-fark-drew-curtis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article bookmarking and submission sites have become a commodity on the web today. There have been only a few veterans that have been around long before it was &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; to have a site in the social news niche, and Drew Curtis&amp;rsquo; Fark.com is one of them. Fark is social news with a twist: comedy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
