<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make Money with Short URL Service adf.ly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With web URL shortening services in high demand these days, it&amp;rsquo;s no wonder adf.ly hadn&amp;rsquo;t come around sooner. Allowing you the same benefits of other free short URL services, adf.ly allows one big benefit - each pageview you get counts towards a small percentage of CPM costs for advertisers! Long story short, you get paid to use adf.ly&amp;rsquo;s services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Newest Trending Social News Sharing Community Humsurfer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult these days to track down the best social news sharing communities. There are the classics such as Digg and Reddit, and also smaller niche communities containing topics like design and programming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Mashable so Quick to Promote Google Buzz?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mashable is one huge blog, a very large competitor to Inside the Webb and what I wish we could be someday! They run some amazing articles about social networking, social media, tech news, and everything internet related. They usually have articles hitting the front page of Digg and Delicious, gaining well into 1500+ ReTweets and tons of Stumbles: bottom line, their blog is huge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Virtual Online Gaming Community FactPile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many great online gaming communities. Video games have taken a huge rise in popularity over the years, and what a better way to celebrate your favorite games than hanging out with like-minded people on a fun and active community? FactPile does just that, collecting all gamers and tech-lovers from around the globe to interact and enjoy the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rumors of Yahoo! Taking Down MyBlogLog could be False</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rumors-of-yahoo-taking-down-mybloglog-could-be-false/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rumors-of-yahoo-taking-down-mybloglog-could-be-false/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting around December I had seen a lot of blogs posting about Yahoo! considering closing the doors on MyBlogLog. I was sad to hear this news, as I have been a huge fan of MyBlogLog since it first launched in 2005. It was a simple community of bloggers with a simple goal of uniting the best writers and bloggers on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Introduces a Brand New, Sleek Home Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Facebook released their newest design. Nothing has changed on personal profile pages, but when you log into your account you should see some major changes to how everything is layed out. This came as a shock to me when I logged in to check my status for the first time earlier today - a brand new look!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Yahoo! Answers Q&amp;amp;A Competitor Blurtit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Answers has to be the most well-known and popular Question &amp;amp; Community on the web. However there is always room for improvement on apps like these, and Blurtit takes the cake. Building more of a community around the idea of the &amp;ldquo;Ask Any Question&amp;rdquo; niche, Blurtit allows users to connect like never before, searching for the most popular questions and sharing knowledge between everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plurk Rivals Twitter as the Next Popular Microblogging Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter - you either love it or hate it. The application has exploded onto the web, where not only everybody seems to need one, but even larger corporations have set up Twitter accounts. Tweeting is the next big thing! tons of people are getting into this new trend, while naysayers stand behind and wave their fingers in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founder of Omegle.com Answers Questions From Redditors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omegle.com has spread across many social networking hubs, forums, and internet chatrooms rapidly over the past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s a new site with a very simple concept: you log in anonymously and talk to someone else. Someone random, someone you&amp;rsquo;ve *probably* never even met before, just talking about whatever. It seems like a breeding ground for spam and pranks, but it ultimately seen very positive results in traffic and user response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Indaba Music: The Online Music-Making Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-indaba-music-the-online-music-making-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-indaba-music-the-online-music-making-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a musician looking to find others to jam with, write music with, or just talk to? Or maybe you have a band, but want to find others who are writing the same kind of stuff? Yeah, listen to their tunes, kick back, maybe even share some wisdom with each other. Well look no further, as Indaba Music can cure all your problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link Your Social Networking Profiles Together with SocialFollow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social Follow is a cool new web application that combines all of your other social networking and social bookmarking profiles. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all have accounts on Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Digg, and many other profiles around the net. With SocialFollow, you are able to combine all of these profiles into one handy button. These are great for posting to your blog, sharing in your forum sigs, or posting it anywhere around the web!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bet on Anything You Like with Flusta.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bet-on-anything-you-like-with-flusta.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bet-on-anything-you-like-with-flusta.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flusa is a new web 2.0 application that allows you to place bets on almost anything you like. Well, not even almost, you can create your own topic and have anyone you want place bets on it, sort of like a &amp;ldquo;social gambling&amp;rdquo; website. Ranging from topics of cutest boys to the best next-gen gaming console, Flusta has it all with a easy-to-use user interface and a great concept in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
