<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sonic and the Black Knight - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sonic-and-the-black-knight-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sonic-and-the-black-knight-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before, Sonic was running really fast and he jumped on his enemies to get rid of them. It was the good old days you would say the nostalgia of his adventures on the Megadrive. Today, his platform of choice is the Nintendo Wii and its controls to the Wiimote air. A search from noon to fourteen hours, if the blue hedgehog explores the legend of King Arthur and the Knights of the Round Table, it is only a pretext for a gigantic sword that it leads to Using the remote control. For the rest, the gameplay of the previous component is included, since it always leads Sonic in a sort of corridor using the Nunchuk. The game is in 3D, and rather pretty, but when we want to go back, the hedgehog is the moonwalk idling. As in Secret Rings, it is impossible to turn back. We regret a bit of Sonic Adventure for the Dreamcast console. Even if we admit that this game forces us to move forward by taking advantage of the speed of this oh so endearing character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The House of the Dead: Overkill - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-house-of-the-dead-overkill-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-house-of-the-dead-overkill-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Dead House has risen the degumming of zombies to the rank of an art. After a through enough portage in episodes 2 and 3, the Wii will finally host an original and jubilant forthcoming opus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Overkill.3&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-house-of-the-dead-overkill-wii-preview/images/Overkill.3-300x205.jpg&#34;&gt;At the outset, the fans can rest assured, the unique atmosphere of The House of the Dead has been preserved. Bad taste, humor at twenty cents, torrents of hemoglobin, the Sega team has worked hard to restore the atmosphere of horror cinema of the 60s. The image is deliberately patina, the soundtrack evokes the films &amp;ldquo;Pulp&amp;rdquo; dear to the heart of Tarantino and just take a look under the letter written in levels of blood (“Papa&amp;rsquo;s Palace of Pain,&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Scream Train&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;) to understand that the script never takes itself too seriously. Chronologically situated before the original episode, it is far from devoid the interest since we propose to follow the beginning of the famous Agent G and his sidekick, Issac Washington. The opportunity to try to learn more about one of the most enigmatic characters in the series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenchu Shadow Assassins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tenchu-shadow-assassins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tenchu-shadow-assassins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a flash on Xbox 360, Tenchu arrives at as a wolf on Wii. Scheduled for March 5th, Tenchu Shadow Assassins has the honor of a preview after what it achieved at the last Tokyo Game Show. The result seems always so convincing? This is the question that the following attempt to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Tenchu.3&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tenchu-shadow-assassins/images/Tenchu.3-300x170.jpg&#34;&gt;The first strong point of the game is to return to a more classical style than Tenchu Z which included creating your own ninja. A point of creation but the possibility to find the cheap Rikimaru and Ayame adorable. Originality, it is very nice because we don’t face a narrative echoing like those of the other episodes but on the contrary, the pleasure of the reunion is indeed real. In addition, it helps to consolidate a mythology implementation that is over 10 years old. It will therefore not be surprised to find Lord Goda, for who the knights of the shadow work, or the princess Kiku who don’t find anything better than to be kidnapped early in the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Zero: Mask of the Lunar Eclipse - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project-zero-mask-of-the-lunar-eclipse-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project-zero-mask-of-the-lunar-eclipse-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remained in the shadow of Resident Evil (with whom it has little in common) and Silent Hill, Project Zero is still a safe bet in survival-horror. Better still, it is complementary to the two sets mentioned above in its construction based on the constant effects of surprise to even make you jump like a frightened virgin. Mask of the Lunar Eclipse is of course no exception to the rule and do not forget to maintain multiple links screenplay with his elders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock Band 2 - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rock-band-2-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rock-band-2-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Rock Band has hit the headlines, it&amp;rsquo;s the least we can say. We know you suffered and the video game world has a scale of change of its own. As required, the most obvious change in this new version is aesthetic. Guitars, always drawn by the contours of a Fender, have inherited a sunburst finish that will clear copper brown in the center burned on the edges. There is also an effort at the handle to give it a wood effect. On a more technical note the arrival of a tiny camera and microphone to facilitate synchronization with the scores scrolling on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Piece Unlimited Cruise: Episode 1 - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/one-piece-unlimited-cruise-episode-1-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/one-piece-unlimited-cruise-episode-1-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Echoing the broad outline of the pattern established in One Piece Unlimited Adventure, the Unlimited Cruise series certainly does more of the element of surprise but it should nevertheless allow us to follow for a long time wandering the straw hat and his band of pirates off standards. Before entering the heart of the matter, it is better to warn immediately the reader: One Piece Unlimited Cruise: Episode 1 is based on narrative elements that we discovered that from Volume 46 of a manga. Thus, although the scenario of the game does not follow the pattern of the series, there are characters and elements that may not have the players not yet reached this stage of history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySims Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mysims-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mysims-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know MySims is a simulation game on Wii. But over the management of family, you can head a Sims and invests in a real mission, if not a destiny: to revive a virtually abandoned city. The next MySims almost deserves to be renamed OurSims. Indeed, MySims Party is a license that offers a real multiplayer aspiration and explores new ways to play video games. However, it forgets nothing that made its success, starting with its so special graphics style and its total originality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MadWorld - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/madworld-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/madworld-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that the family friendly Wii console from Nintendo would host a game for sweet crazy days as steam as MadWorld? Make no mistake about it, with its black and white graphic with only the red color of blood, MadWorld is a work of unprecedented violence and barbarism without a name. But while Manhunt disturbed by realistic context similar to our daily and conventional weapons, MadWorld plays the cards of immoderation outrageously. Chainsaw, sharp barbs, shredded body, nothing will be spared. Disturbing? Strangely no, not at all. Once the Wii controller in hand, we forget the immoral side of the title to focus on our goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Creatures - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/deadly-creatures-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/deadly-creatures-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While scorpions and tarantulas are generally slaughtered by the heroes of most RPG and all other beat&amp;rsquo;em, Deadly Creatures offers us the opportunity to become one of those horrible creatures today and to explore the labyrinths infested with vermin. Brrrr!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Deadly.3&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/deadly-creatures-wii-preview/images/Deadly.3-300x239.jpg&#34;&gt;Pertussis of casual players, Wii hosts traditionally family games party, brain coaches or public platforms games. Who would have thought therefore that developers of Deadly Creatures can choose this as a console exclusive title, it is disturbing? For once, in fact, it is not about caring for a shetland or save a princess in nice flower but to confront our fears of the most stubborn child diving head first into an universe populated by snakes, spiders and other forms of repulsive life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dead Rising: Chop Till you Drop - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dead-rising-chop-till-you-drop-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dead-rising-chop-till-you-drop-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than two years after investing the screens of Xbox 360 owners, the zombies of Dead Rising take the nice little Wii. If the game keeps the fun of his style, why ignore this new version?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dead Rising.3&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dead-rising-chop-till-you-drop-wii-preview/images/Dead-Rising.3-300x225.jpg&#34;&gt;Before diving further into the stinking bowels of the beast, take a few seconds to remember the context of the adventure, an identical course than the version 360 of course. The player embody Frank West, a nosy reporter, which aspires to get the scoop of the century. The shape of a boxer, a trucker Belarusian faces, replicas of the dead and a furious motivation, this is what you can expect when you see the guy. After a short trip by helicopter over a curiously American town in quarantine by the U.S. Army, Frank will finally end up trapped in a mall, a sort of giant shopping center particularly appreciated in this country. Unfortunately, this consumption temple, once so peaceful, is now infested with corpses and survivors traveling more or less helpless. Because, if the majority of them do ask to be rescued, the others seem almost more dangerous than zombies because of their fear, their folly, their unconscious motivations or their secrets. But on this particular subject, we will voluntarily silent because we don’t want to spoil the surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Judgement - Wii Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/castlevania-judgement-wii-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/castlevania-judgement-wii-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Konami let itself be drawn into the tendency to cross-over with Castlevania Judgment which marks the encounter of the most charismatic characters in the series. A radically different way from what Koji Igarashi used us since it is neither more nor less than a 100 % fighting game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Castlevania.3&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/castlevania-judgement-wii-preview/images/Castlevania.3-300x171.jpg&#34;&gt;Within two decades, the Konami gothic saga took the time to make a name with players in a sprawling building on a large number of different media. Today, the series extends primarily on consoles, waiting to know what will happen in the next major opus announced on PS3 and Xbox 360. As with SoulCalibur Legends, the Wii will finally be entitled to an episode of this prestigious marginal saga, the one this is the subject of this overview. Designed for the most unconditional fans, Castlevania Judgment certainly does not have the aura that characterizes the other parts of the series, but it is still a good opportunity to unwind alongside the cult figures of the saga&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Legend of Zelda Twilight Princess - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-legend-of-zelda-twilight-princess-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-legend-of-zelda-twilight-princess-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This unparalleled quest, you will be able to live in two different ways, depending on whether you opt for the Wii or the GameCube version. If their content is identical, the gaming experiences they provide vary widely, given the considerable changes made to gameplay by the Wii version, and it goes without saying that it necessarily benefits of an additional attraction in terms of discovery. Nevertheless it was legitimate to have some reservations and doubts about the effectiveness of its grip bold and unprecedented for a title of this magnitude. But to be among the first to have questioned the relevance of the outcome, let me dispel any fears you may have about this. Not only is the unique gameplay on the Wii version significantly renews the feeling of the game, but it is also intuitive enough to be forgotten in a few hours, the difficulties of taking control that inevitably occur when the familiar first time with a console of a new kind. Thus, cross swords through the Wiimote is going to become second nature, like each of the actions you&amp;rsquo;ll be asked to and you will see how fun that can be feel when engaged in a video game depends on the immersion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Smash Bros Brawl - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/super-smash-bros-brawl-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/super-smash-bros-brawl-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was discovered in 1999 on N64, and nearly ten years, the series will count as three episodes, each on different mediums. But when we see how it has evolved in that time, we see that Nintendo has made the right choice by focusing on quality over quantity. Super Smash Bros. Brawl succeeds an episode GameCube already very convincing and dethrones without difficulty. Just start the software, the player is literally bombarded by an avalanche of game modes, new to most, and can only kneel before the proper amazing range of characters available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Paper Mario - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/super-paper-mario-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/super-paper-mario-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super Paper Mario retains a focus on running the adventure, but separated from its background on the role play, starting with the fighting in turn-based. A change that should delight all those for whom the name of Mario is totally separated from the platforms type, which at least has the merit of renewing a few things. It is hoped however that Nintendo has not drawn a line on the concept of the Mario RPG, but it is likely that the next title will be rather light on DS. Nevertheless, Super Paper Mario is not just a platform game, it is above all a constant source of amazement as it demonstrated creativity in both its playful design and design graph. The result is very refreshing and proves that the field of video game is full of hidden concepts waiting to finally be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Mario Galaxy - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/super-mario-galaxy-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/super-mario-galaxy-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since its announcement, Super Mario Galaxy generates almost more confusion than curiosity in the hearts of players. The system evolution at the heart of this might he not have to change, or worse, distorting the very spirit of the series and the formula for Super Mario 64? Legitimate concerns, but in vain, since the idea to move Mario in a galaxy appears to be the key that opens the very doors of renewal and that allows him to leave behind him all his previous adventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resident Evil 4 - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resident-evil-4-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resident-evil-4-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Begin by the end if you want: a direct reply to the question of terminating the preamble to this test. So if Resident Evil 4 is still an excellent title on Wii, there is nothing new to his colleagues if not at the game console to own. Out of this, so it will still be entitled to the entire positive that this adjustment has the additions of the PS2 and PC versions starting with a game mode missing from the GameCube version: Separate Ways. The latter, like the assignment mode, you will lead the beautiful Ada throughout five missions. From the pure value added, especially the way that we proposed to visit a new decor and new looking kinematics. But before discussing this in detail, let us look at the original script.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince of Persia Rival Swords - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/prince-of-persia-rival-swords-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/prince-of-persia-rival-swords-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Too often adored and envied for their destiny out of the men elevated to hero often lead a life similar to that of the martyrs. Exhausted by years of wandering and fighting, he could push past his fight against the Dahaka and the curse of the sands of time, the Prince of Persia was an illusion to believe that he would finally know peace. But fate hounds brave men, and most recently, the tired hero takes up arms to face his worst enemy: himself. The scenario of evil Prince of Persia: Rival Swords is one of those who make you want to make a novel. All players who have overcome the hardships of the first two components together with the Prince know that we cannot forever endure such tortures without paying the price. Returned to Babylon with Kaileena, the Empress troubling time, the prince, nobody knows the name, discovers a city ravaged by war, a kingdom invaded by rivals more cruel than those which it has dealt so far. Therefore, the story starts quickly, leaving not even the soul time to break under the harsh fate that has befallen him. Victim of a conspiracy organized by a manipulative and tyrannical Vizier, Kaileena is killed in front of his eyes. Prince powerless to release the sands of time, even letting himself be contaminated by those who make the chew from the inside, corrupting his soul to bring out the evil that is in him and materialize in the form of sadistic entity: the Dark Prince. From a quality equivalent to the Two Kingdoms on GameCube, the achievement is as compelling and captivating. The opposition between the high and low quoted cities renews perfectly sets and the atmosphere that emanates from, and the animations are still among the very best at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Okami - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/okami-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/okami-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the pointer of my blog editor flashes before my eyes, I suddenly feel some anxiety, some fear. The latter told me that I could not find the right words to describe what I was invaded by discovering Okami. Thus, paradoxical as it may seem, the doubt comes knocking at my door just as many blank pages await my impressions I sleep to tell you my journey, the same one that made me assume the role a Japanese divinity which has been a difficult task to restore color to a world fallen into a torpor monochromatic. The exercise is all the more difficult it is a kind of homage to a still-born point that deserved its deadly fate. But this is not the time for tears, if not joy, because constrained and forced, I am ready to really start this test and tell you about one of my best gaming events since I looked on my very first Game &amp;amp; Watch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guitar Hero III Legends of Rock - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guitar-hero-iii-legends-of-rock-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guitar-hero-iii-legends-of-rock-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, the best part of Guitar Hero has been developed by Harmonix. Because it ends the suspense, Guitar Hero 3 supplants its elders, admittedly few, but still. It must be said that the formula has not changed, not to say that it remains unchanged with the exception of a few discrete improvements and additions not necessarily essential. The first change in size provided by this third edition is obviously the partial abandonment of lumpish from the previous flap. Activision puts his hand to the portfolio as well to recall how the popularity of Guitar Hero actually an advertising and therefore unavoidable, we are left with almost half of the tracklist that consists of original songs, singer without risking a dangerous original interpreter imitation of the solo and without deviating a bit from our memories. The disadvantage is that by contrast, these times always seem to do most unfortunate that, inevitably. Composed, therefore, with security whose integrity has been little affected, the new playlist of the game is a pure marvel, perfectly balanced between musical styles and technical approaches. Rock, Alternative, Metal, Blues-Rock, the sounds of electric fan is not only spoiled by the variety of styles but also by the worthy representatives selected by and paid by Neversoft Activision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boom Blox - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/boom-blox-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/boom-blox-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We don’t have to introduce you Steven Spielberg, the great director who marked his entire generation of cult films such as Jaws, ET, Close Encounters of the Third Kind, Jurassik Park, Indiana Jones or The Saving Private Ryan. In the last 25 years, this genius of the cinema has become one of the greatest filmmakers of all time and has amassed a colossal fortune that he invested to produce new films and support educational organizations. Not happy enough with having conquered Hollywood, Spielberg is tackling now the gaming arena with the prestigious publisher Electronic Arts. So that logically could be expected in a project supported by a more than great realization, the concept of Boom Blox is very basic. And the most surprising is that it works wonderfully!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metroid Prime 3 Corruption - Wii Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/metroid-prime-3-corruption-wii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/metroid-prime-3-corruption-wii-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the achievements it has accomplished to defend against the star system and against all attempts at domination perpetrated by the most dangerous creatures in the galaxy, the premiums hunter Samus Aran knows she is about to face a threat more terrible than all those she had already annihilate. Emergency contacted by members of the Galactic Federation, she learned that the Aurora 242 supercomputer has been infected by a virus of unknown origin, due to sabotage. Open from the beginning to save his own life at stake in this latest mission, Samus also knows that she will execute the directives of the Federation without asking any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
