<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelance on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freelance on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FreshWebJobs: A Unique Job Board for Web Designers &amp;amp; Developers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/freshwebjobs-a-unique-job-board-for-web-designers-amp-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back a few years ago I used to work full-time freelance web design. It&amp;rsquo;s a tiring job, and many people who can do it today earn a lot of money working for themselves in the trade. Web professionals are always in demand, but it&amp;rsquo;s difficult at times to find good web projects. Freshwebjobs.com changes all that with professional listings to pair up webmasters and developers to those looking into projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional Freelance Web Designer Shay Howe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the fastest growing professions is website design and web developers, especially with the attraction of working freelance. Many people hate the 9-5 grind induced through corporate America, and having the option to work from home on your own time seems like a much more viable and interesting option to many. Although in the end it may require a bit more work on your end, the ultimate freedom of your time seems to pay for itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Chris Spooner of Line25 Web Design Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-chris-spooner-of-line25-web-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-chris-spooner-of-line25-web-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: web design is hot. With the internet&amp;rsquo;s popularity skyrocketing, younger and younger kids are getting into design and web projects, even freelancing! Not to say this is bad at all, it&amp;rsquo;s actually started a large spread of web design and development tips and inspiration, mostly posted onto blogs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Successful Design Blog: Lessons from Web Designer Depot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs are the new in, everybody who is interested in making money online and knows any amount about web design is starting their own blog. Granted only a few have made it and gained star-status in the blogosphere, but there are thousands of others who struggle to build their way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
