<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social-Networking on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/social-networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social-Networking on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/social-networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MySpace More Layoffs and Reflecting on What Went Wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myspace-more-layoffs-and-reflecting-on-what-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last July, Inside the Webb reported on new changes coming to MySpace in an effort to streamline the overall design of the social networking giant. As reported at the time, the changes were long overdue, however overhauling such a large organization was no easy task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Discussion Boards and Dynamic Chatrooms with Donut Chat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/social-discussion-boards-and-dynamic-chatrooms-with-donut-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/social-discussion-boards-and-dynamic-chatrooms-with-donut-chat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new chatroom client has been released on the market, and it runs so smooth I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s not being used elsewhere. Donut Chat is my latest find in the ways of community and boards, and the software runs perfectly. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of chat rooms, they&amp;rsquo;re useful as support forums, sharing ideas with friends and business partners&amp;hellip; really anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craze.cc - New and Innovative Social News/Discussion Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/craze.cc-new-and-innovative-social-news/discussion-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/craze.cc-new-and-innovative-social-news/discussion-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love social media, I&amp;rsquo;ll get that off my chest right now. There are so many new and innovative websites popping up each and every day which take the idea of social networking and spin it around with some new features and a new look, then present it to you in a clean and elegant way. Well Craze.cc is certainly one of those sites, and the idea is spreading fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Google Buzz is Gaining Many Early Followers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-google-buzz-is-gaining-many-early-followers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-google-buzz-is-gaining-many-early-followers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Google Buzz launched a few months ago, it has had some very impressive early adopters. Mashable and TechCrunch have been the first of many larger blogs to jump on board, with many smaller blogs following suit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Profitable are Niche Video Game Forums and Communities?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of the web 2.0 boom is communication. People are communicating now more than ever, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise. With the vast size of apps these days, along with almost every website running some type of forum or blog, users are more connected than ever! Many marketers can see ways to utilizing this new &amp;ldquo;social networking fever&amp;rdquo; as a turning point to make some serious money online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Virtual Online Gaming Community FactPile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-virtual-online-gaming-community-factpile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many great online gaming communities. Video games have taken a huge rise in popularity over the years, and what a better way to celebrate your favorite games than hanging out with like-minded people on a fun and active community? FactPile does just that, collecting all gamers and tech-lovers from around the globe to interact and enjoy the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Your Username Availability on Tons of Websites with Namechk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/check-your-username-availability-on-tons-of-websites-with-namechk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/check-your-username-availability-on-tons-of-websites-with-namechk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us enjoy sticking with our usernames. We sign up with the same username on multiple websites, and this is especially true with social networking/bookmarking sites as it allows your name to become a presence in the community. Only thing is, there&amp;rsquo;s so many people online that the chances of our username being take is, well, pretty decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Digg-Themed Social News and Media Website Thuhm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-digg-themed-social-news-and-media-website-thuhm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has become the popular site for internet marketers and bloggers to aspire to. Digg used to be a popular tech website, where tech enthusiasts and internet lovers could gather to share links. Whichever links got the most &amp;ldquo;diggs&amp;rdquo; would hit the front page, generally to recieve a surge of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
