<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adobe&#39;s Secrets Revealed for New Creative Suite 5</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been quite a few videos in regards to the new Adobe Creative Suite 5, most specifically Photoshop and design software. There have been a lot of updates from the not-so-old CS4 set of Web and Graphic design software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Float Launches their Inspiration Blog with New Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design Float is one of the top social news sites for web design and graphics articles. Having been online for almost 2 years now, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk and hype about the site which has contributed to its popularity. However over the past few weeks, the owner of DF has begun to post again on the Design Float Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infamous Design Blog DesignM.ag Being Auctioned on Flippa</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs have become the de-facto of the internet revolution over the past 2-3 years. As web design has shot off and every 16 year old and their mother has started to learn XHTML/CSS, blogging about it has just become another step in the process. DesignM.ag is one of the most popular, sharing free tutorials and graphics frequently in their posts. As of April 5 the site has been put up for auction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Page /r/circlejerk Clones 4Chan&#39;s Website Design</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After visiting Reddit today, it was pretty obvious my favorite SubReddit circlejerk was up to no good. After toying around all week with a funny upvote arrow which looked similar to male genitalia, we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen an invasion of 4chan into Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Rolls out new User Interface for Flash Video Player</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/youtube-rolls-out-new-user-interface-for-flash-video-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/youtube-rolls-out-new-user-interface-for-flash-video-player/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having seen YouTube roll out new video and profile pages over the past few months, it&amp;rsquo;s been obvious there&amp;rsquo;s been a new Flash User Interface in the works for the common video player. Well as of today, YouTube has finally released the newest UI to most video pages, and are slowly trickling down throughout all videos over the next couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digzign - New Social News for Designers that Dig</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/digzign-new-social-news-for-designers-that-dig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social news has sprung along the web, and with the popularity of web design and graphics blogs sharing links has become commonplace. With popular sites such as DesignFloat and DesignBump, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine much else. However I have recently found a great-looking Digg clone website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://digzign.com/&#34;&gt;http://digzign.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Jacob Gube of Six Revisions Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the freelance and web design/development community for years now, starting back when I was attending high school. I always keep up with the latest blogs, tutorials, tips, and design tricks from the community, and no blog has shown greater content with a higher rate of growth than Six Revisions. Jacob Gube is the founder and main writer at the blog, and I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to share with you some great Q&amp;amp;A&amp;rsquo;s between us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Template Monster&#39;s Design Blog Kicks Off!</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/template-monsters-design-blog-kicks-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/template-monsters-design-blog-kicks-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out of all the website and Wordpress template sellers out there, Template Monster is clearly the king. Reigning in the business for the past couple of years, the company has grown substantially to offer tens of thousands of templates to it&amp;rsquo;s many customer&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Latest Free Icon Search Engine FindIcons.com</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-latest-free-icon-search-engine-findicons.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-latest-free-icon-search-engine-findicons.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a few weeks ago I got a great interview with the creator of IconFinder.net, one of the only free icon search engines online. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve come across another one which has just as many great icons shared, plus the ability to log in and save your favorite sets!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Webb v3.0 Launches Live!</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-the-webb-v3.0-launches-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-the-webb-v3.0-launches-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 3.0 of Inside the Webb has finally launched live. Since our last design update in December I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy at work contemplating how I could take Inside the Webb to the next level. Well it hit me about a week ago, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been tweaking the latest and greatest design launch!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Releases Sleek, Clean Homepage Redesign</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/twitter-releases-sleek-clean-homepage-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/twitter-releases-sleek-clean-homepage-redesign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this has been covered by many media blogs, Twitter has indeed released a new home page! I have to say, I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the new design and it definitely allows for a better user experience when first arriving at the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Point Forums Re-Design for the New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the internet marketing and blogging forums out there, Digital Point was the first community I ever joined. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there for years, learned so much from the members and even contributed to helping others along their path. There are many other choices, but DP will always hold a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of running the same design, DP has finally upgraded to a fresh web 2.0 look and feel to the entire site! Now running what is clearly the latest version of vBulletin 4.0 Forum Software, the latest design really kicks new life into such an expansive and helpful community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing DesignMoo for Social Media Traffic to your Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all of you running a design blog out there, DesignMoo is a site you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to bookmark. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all know of Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity, this has caused many smaller sites to spawn offspring and grow into micro-niche Digg sites. DesignMoo is one of these style of sites for graphic and web design, and can bring in a lot of traffic to your blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;amp;A with Premium Wordpress Theme Developer WPMonk</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many premium Wordpress themes roam the internet these days, all of varying quality and development. I recently found a really neat Premium Wordpress design company WP Monk. They run a very impressive website design, plus their premium themes are impeccable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Information and Photo now Displayed After each Post</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep, I finally decided to add some of those updates I had planned on rolling out so long ago! I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to add author info to the posts on Inside the Webb for a while, just haven&amp;rsquo;t had time. Well I finally found some time, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Interview with LogoMoose Creator Dirk Leys</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/exclusive-interview-with-logomoose-creator-dirk-leys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/exclusive-interview-with-logomoose-creator-dirk-leys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many inspirational sites have sprung up recently. The web is crawling with CSS galleries and logo galleries, but only a few really break the mold and stand out as the most creative, inspiring, and useful collections. LogoMoose makes it to the top of my list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Introduces a Brand New, Sleek Home Design</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Facebook released their newest design. Nothing has changed on personal profile pages, but when you log into your account you should see some major changes to how everything is layed out. This came as a shock to me when I logged in to check my status for the first time earlier today - a brand new look!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Vibrant and Inspiring Design Blog ilovecolors</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most graphic design blogs today can serve as a source of inspiration and creativity. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a fantastic design blog covering everything from Photoshop to Typography. ilovecolors is a fantastic blog run by Elio Rivero, and I was lucky enough to get a behind-the-scenes interview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging and Design Tips from Pro Blog Design Creator Michael Martin</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-and-design-tips-from-pro-blog-design-creator-michael-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-and-design-tips-from-pro-blog-design-creator-michael-martin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly one of the most important aspects of running a blog is keeping up with design trends. You can write amazing articles and share the best tips on the web, but if your blog looks like a run-down 1990&amp;rsquo;s ripoff or some generic Wordpress template, chances are you won&amp;rsquo;t be attracting many visitors to your site. The most famous and successful bloggers realize how important a custom design really is, and no expenses are cut when it comes to design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional Freelance Web Designer Shay Howe</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-freelance-web-designer-shay-howe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the fastest growing professions is website design and web developers, especially with the attraction of working freelance. Many people hate the 9-5 grind induced through corporate America, and having the option to work from home on your own time seems like a much more viable and interesting option to many. Although in the end it may require a bit more work on your end, the ultimate freedom of your time seems to pay for itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Little Box of Ideas Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much alike many designers out there, I&amp;rsquo;m constantly craving new graphic design inspiration, web design galleries, and everything the life of a designer should be filled to the brim with. This leads me on my quest of finding the best design blogs out on the internetz, and my interview today is no shortage. Little Box of Ideas is a great design and creativity blog, focusing on great topics such as graphics tutorials and typography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
