<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Images on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/images/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Images on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/images/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>InstaShow Instagram feed plugin review (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/instashow-instagram-feed-plugin-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/instashow-instagram-feed-plugin-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InstaShow is a premium WordPress plugin that allows you to integrate the Instagram feed on your website. It has registered 6000+ sales on the ThemeForest marketplace. It is a highly customizable plugin that has a rating of 4.87/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;InstaShow is cheap and it provides amazing features. If you own a photography, product review website or a food blog, you can get more Instagram followers by installing this plugin. The Instagram widget provided by InstaShow is a great alternative to a gallery or featured image widget because it saves server resources. Instead of uploading pictures on your server, you can share your images on Instagram and configure InstaShow to display the pictures in a nice interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Best CDN 2018: Fastest content delivery networks</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-cdn-2018-fastest-content-delivery-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-5-best-cdn-2018-fastest-content-delivery-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CDN aka content delivery networks improves the performance of your site. They reduce the latency by serving JavaScript and CSS files from the location closest to the visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CDN provider may have several data centers spread across the world. When you signup for the CDN service, the service will cache static resources of your site on a server nearby the location you specify. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to install a CDN plugin so as to change the website resource URL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image SEO tips and tools to make photos search engine friendly</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/image-seo-tips-and-tools-to-make-photos-search-engine-friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/image-seo-tips-and-tools-to-make-photos-search-engine-friendly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know? Images can bring tons of high-quality organic traffic to your blog or website. A website without pictures looks strange. Visitors may not find such sites attractive. If the blog post doesn&amp;rsquo;t have related pictures, visitors may not read the full content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve shared 7 useful tips for image optimization. If your site has many pictures, but if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get a good amount of traffic from Google image search, follow the below tips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best featured image plugin for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-featured-image-plugin-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-featured-image-plugin-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Featured image is a picture that appears in the post excerpt. When the visitor sees the image, he will find the topic interesting, relevant, and will not hesitate in exploring your website further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the premium and free WordPress themes launched these days support FI. If your website has 100s of posts, it is difficult to set featured images manually unless you are ready to edit posts one by one. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do so because the below free plugins will automate this task for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Image Sharing Plugin for WordPress (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-image-sharing-plugin-for-wordpress-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-image-sharing-plugin-for-wordpress-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A blog post is incomplete without images. Imagine if a site has no photos, will you spend your time going through the content?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A visitor to your website might be impressed with the picture you&amp;rsquo;ve embedded in the blog post. He may want to share the image on social networks. Some users may not waste their time in copying the photo URL by right clicking on the page. They may exit your website and use Google image search to get a link to the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete unused images in WordPress with Media Cleaner plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/delete-unused-images-in-wordpress-with-media-cleaner-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/delete-unused-images-in-wordpress-with-media-cleaner-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is one of the most important elements of a blog post. It not only makes the post attractive but also helps in improving the website&amp;rsquo;s search engine visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when you update a blog post, you may replace the image/pictures in it with some other pictures. Many users don&amp;rsquo;t bother to delete the old images from the uploads directory of wp-content WordPress installation folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a site grows larger, the uploads folder may have tons of unused images. These files waste storage memory, and they impact system&amp;rsquo;s performance. To delete or remove these files, download the Media Cleaner plugin and install it on your WordPress website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Pingdom alternatives to check website speed</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A website which opens quickly in the browser ensures the best user experience and higher rankings in Google search engine. Thus, the first thing that you should do after launching a new website is to check the page loading speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pingdom is one of the most widely used website speed checking tools, but it offers limited features due to which many people will use its below 2 top alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gtmetrix&#34;&gt;GTmetrix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;gtmetrix pingdom alternatives check website speed&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/images/gtmetrix.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Image Size in Post Content WordPress?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-change-image-size-in-post-content-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-change-image-size-in-post-content-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may not like your current WordPress theme, and you may think of replacing it with some other template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes allow you to export settings. But the settings you back up will be compatible only with the theme i.e. You can&amp;rsquo;t move settings of a Mythemshop template to TagDiv NewsPaper or Elegant Themes Divi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you change your template, you may have to tweak the design for the best experience of the user. You may also have to change image sizes so that the blog posts don&amp;rsquo;t look horrible or broken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
