<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Email-Marketing on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/email-marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Email-Marketing on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/email-marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Job Board Themes for WordPress (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-job-board-themes-for-wordpress-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-job-board-themes-for-wordpress-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recruiting a right person is crucial to the success of a business firm. Creating a website that allows you to publish job listings and managing them is not a huge task for a website developer. The developer can take anything between 20 to 50 days to create a job board site and he&amp;rsquo;ll charge you over $500 as a fee. If you&amp;rsquo;re are looking for a cheaper option, consider using WordPress content management system and buy one of the best Job Board Themes for WordPress we have shared in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OptinMonster vs SumoMe plugin comparison (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-vs-sumome-plugin-comparison-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-vs-sumome-plugin-comparison-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of the best plugins for email marketing and having regular visitors are OptinMonster and SumeMe. SumoMe is an ideal tool for the users looking for an all-in-one plugin for improving traffic, adding new subscribers, etc. OptinMonster is a great plugin for creating Opt-ins of various types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two plugins are great for users who don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste time in customization. They provide predefined templates which you can use right away on your website. In case you&amp;rsquo;re finding it confusing to choose between OptinMonster and SumoMe, go through the below paragraphs where we have explained the similarities and differences between the 2 most popular plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OptinMonster Review 2018: Powerful lead generation plugin for WP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-review-2018-powerful-lead-generation-plugin-for-wp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/optinmonster-review-2018-powerful-lead-generation-plugin-for-wp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Email marketing is probably incomplete without a good newsletter plugins that add subscription forms in our WordPress sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of free plugins to add newsletter forums to a website, but the features they offer are limited. For example, the MailChimp plugin doesn&amp;rsquo;t support popups, and it lacks an Ajax based form which makes the sign-up process fast. You can only change the background and button color with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloom plugin review : Create and add stylish Newsletter optin forms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloom-plugin-review-create-and-add-stylish-newsletter-optin-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloom-plugin-review-create-and-add-stylish-newsletter-optin-forms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Email Optin forms are useful because they attract visitor&amp;rsquo;s attention. When a visitor signs up with the form, the website will have a new loyal reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters will bring referral traffic to your blog. If your site is not ranked in search engines, you can still get free traffic provided that you send a newsletter to an email address or share blog posts on social media networks or the best bookmarking websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mailchimp latest Pricing, Review and Features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mailchimp-latest-pricing-review-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mailchimp-latest-pricing-review-and-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many bloggers believe that email marketing is the best strategy to have a loyal and regular audience. Thus, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an email opt-in widget on all popular blogs. There are a lot of email subscription service for blogs and in my perspective, Mailchimp tops the list. Mailchimp pricing is attractive, cheap and its features are powerful. The free version of MailChimp service allows you to change newsletter template, design, title. It can generate newsletter automatically from your blogs RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
