<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Duplicate-Content on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/duplicate-content/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Duplicate-Content on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/duplicate-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Best WordPress SEO plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-7-best-wordpress-seo-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-7-best-wordpress-seo-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re running a website, you must optimize it for search engines to succeed as a blogger, business owner etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers can have nightmares while making their site or client&amp;rsquo;s website SEO friendly. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a content management system, this task is a piece of cake, thanks to the best SEO plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to WordPress CMS or if you&amp;rsquo;re site is not performing well in search engines, you should use the following WordPress SEO plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Online Plagiarism Checkers that are Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-online-plagiarism-checkers-that-are-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-online-plagiarism-checkers-that-are-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plagiarism in the online world is the art of stealing others content without the copyright holder&amp;rsquo;s permission. It is bad for bloggers because duplicate content can affect their blog&amp;rsquo;s search engine visibility. Bloggers are not the only professionals worried about Plagiarism. Teachers always fear that their students might copy the homework from any one of the billions of sites available in Google&amp;rsquo;s search index. If you think that your hard work has been copied or if you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher who wants to check the genuineness of student&amp;rsquo;s homework, use the below tools to find all websites that have duplicate content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
