<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ux-Design on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/ux-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ux-Design on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/ux-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Perform Heuristics Evaluation On A Website?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-perform-heuristics-evaluation-on-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-perform-heuristics-evaluation-on-a-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every User Experience Researcher in the world gets the request of performing a &lt;strong&gt;Heuristic Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt; at least once in their lifetime. But it is not always clear if the requester knows precisely about this process of evaluation. What happens is, they hear a word in trend, and they request it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before you dive right into the heuristics evaluation of the website, you need to be aware of what it is and how you can conduct it with precision. Take some time and learn about all the ins and outs of the technique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Design Approaches, Frameworks and Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/modern-design-approaches-frameworks-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/modern-design-approaches-frameworks-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, several web design trends have exploded in popularity and different frameworks and libraries have emerged to support them. It&amp;rsquo;s been close to a decade since the term &amp;lsquo;responsive&amp;rsquo; became mainstream and changed our way of thinking about the structure of our applications across devices. Since that time other design philosophies have followed as we sought ways to improve the user experience across a diverse range of platforms. At the same time tools and techniques have continued to improve to arm designers with the right frameworks, libraries and approaches to deliver the best user experiences possible. In this article I will cover some of the more popular design approaches and libraries that can be used to implement them. I&amp;rsquo;ll conclude with a quick list of several wireframing tools that can also be used in design. I recommend checking out each of these resources via the links provided below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketching out your Perfect Website</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/sketching-out-your-perfect-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/sketching-out-your-perfect-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to start solidifying ideas for your ideal website. You have no doubt spent countless hours in the planning phase identifying your target audience, design considerations, and of course you have a solid idea of your overall content strategy. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, then do yourself a favor and take a look at The Complete Guide to Building Your Personal Brand, What Makes an Effective Website? and How to Design a Website for a Specific Target Audience? before reading on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Doctor of Science Degree?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/what-is-a-doctor-of-science-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/what-is-a-doctor-of-science-degree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I finally graduated after several years of intensive work from the University of Baltimore with a Doctor of Science degree in Information and Interaction Design. At the time I graduated people started asking me about my credential and whether or not it was the same as a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-doctor-of-science&#34;&gt;What is a Doctor of Science?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many articles online regarding this very topic. In some countries a Doctor of Science (often abbreviated as either Sc.D. or D.Sc.), is considered a different type of credential than what is considered in the United States. In the U.K. for example, an Sc.D. is considered a higher degree than the traditional Ph.D. This type of qualification there is only obtained by senior scholars in their field of study. In some cases it is bestowed as an honorary title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heather Remote Usability Session 10</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/heather-remote-usability-session-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/heather-remote-usability-session-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heather also experienced some workflow issues with the application where she was unable to locate various areas of the system.  She commented that the excessive scrolling contributed to her confusion with this.  In addition to this she noted concern with the various grid updates and format of the STA grid for editing and updating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meg Remote Usability Session 9</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/meg-remote-usability-session-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/meg-remote-usability-session-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meg had some difficulty working with the various grids, however once she learned the process, she was able to easily complete the remaining tasks.  She also had some initial trouble with the &amp;lsquo;Big Ideas&amp;rsquo; drop-down selection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Remote Usability Session 8</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/michael-remote-usability-session-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/michael-remote-usability-session-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael was able to complete all tasks without many concerns.  He observer and pointed out a few potential enhancements with the system, however the only issue he ran into was the recurring problem with the &amp;lsquo;Final Product&amp;rsquo; text area box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romey Remote Usability Session 7</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/romey-remote-usability-session-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/romey-remote-usability-session-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Romey completed most tasks with ease, however on a few occasions she came across recurring issues.  She had trouble working with the &amp;lsquo;Big Ideas&amp;rsquo; control, updating the various expedition and case study grids, and not correctly saving each form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Mapping for Expeditionary Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/curriculum-mapping-for-expeditionary-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/curriculum-mapping-for-expeditionary-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Curriculum Mapping is the process of documenting lessons, activities and assessment methods used within different grade levels and classes in an educational institution.  Expeditionary Learning (EL) is a style of teaching that involves the students in experiences and problem-solving activities.  This paper explores the intersection of these two educational theories and addresses how pedagogical goals are met/not met by designing for both. It also addresses how the research of Heidi Hayes Jacobs (2004) affect efforts to design for and support this intersection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backwards Design</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/backwards-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/backwards-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Backwards design is a methodology used to develop curriculum, which promotes the identification of learning results at the start of the design process.  Wiggins and McTighe defined this term as part of their Understanding by Design (UbD) framework.  Backwards design is not a new concept, it has been around for a long time and this paper explores some of the underlying research behind Wiggins and McTighe’s work.  Backwards design promotes a focus on teaching for understanding and learning, as well as designing the curriculum in way that meets learning goals while aligning results with state requirements.  (McTighe &amp;amp; Wiggins, 2012).  Often within education, learning goals are set first, before considering the assessment strategies that will be used to measure students’ understanding.  Without considering the results that are expected of a student, the chances of goals and assessment aligning with required results, or outputs are greatly diminished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Remote Usability Session 6</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/jeff-remote-usability-session-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/jeff-remote-usability-session-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeff ran into some problems when he did not save the form page he was on and lost changes.  He had trouble remembering to press the update button on the various grids.  In addition to this, he also came across problems with the &amp;lsquo;Big Ideas&amp;rsquo; control and text area bug for &amp;lsquo;Final Product&amp;rsquo; that others faced.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lorie Remote Usability Session 4</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/lorie-remote-usability-session-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/lorie-remote-usability-session-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This usability testing session revealed some issues with the using the Big Ideas drop-down selectors for adding new records.  In addition to this, the process for adding standards, targets and assessments appeared confusing to the user.  There were some issues with workflow where the user was confused about which screen she was on.  Recommendations were made for allowing file uploads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megan Remote Usability Session 5</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/megan-remote-usability-session-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/megan-remote-usability-session-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Megan was able to complete most tasks with ease.  The only issue she seemed to have was related to workflow and finding specific sections or areas of the application.  The confusion stemmed from differentiating between the case study and expedition screens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate - Remote Usability Session 3</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/kate-remote-usability-session-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/kate-remote-usability-session-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This remote usability test also revealed some problems with workflow as well as keyboard accessibility problems not previously discovered.  In addition to this, Kate noted several problems with form controls including the &amp;lsquo;Big Ideas&amp;rsquo; dropdown selection and &amp;lsquo;Common Core&amp;rsquo; search picker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rob - Remote Usability Session 2</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/rob-remote-usability-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/rob-remote-usability-session-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second remote usability test revealed some recurring issues as well as new observations.  Rob noted some issues in remembering to click update on the various grids.  He also ran into some problems with workflow and general navigation in terms of locating various parts of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application Demo and Reporting</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/application-demo-and-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/application-demo-and-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the last sprint, the first iteration of the actual application was developed using ASP.NET MVC 5 and SQL Server backend database.  This application is being used for the upcoming remote usability testing sessions. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beth - Remote Usability Session 1</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/beth-remote-usability-session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/beth-remote-usability-session-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first remote usability test revealed some issues regarding various interactions within the application.  For the most part the various tasks were completed with ease, however on one occasion a system bug caused problems.  Later in the session, Beth ran into problems using the text area box for final product description.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Mapping PD Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/curriculum-mapping-pd-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/curriculum-mapping-pd-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 17th, a Professional Development (PD) meeting was held at Monarch and 18 teachers and staff members attended.  At the even the researcher presented the Axure prototype and discussed the current development of Expedition Mapper.  Field surveys were distributed and completed by teachers, who were then divided into three groups afterwards to elaborate on their answers and to discuss other related concerns and questions regarding the proposed system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helen - Pilot Usability Session</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/helen-pilot-usability-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/helen-pilot-usability-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pilot usability testing was held at the University of Baltimore&amp;rsquo;s usability lab.  The pilot involved the new ASP.NET application, which enabled for more realistic interactions when compared to the earlier Axure wireframes.  Several problems were discovered with the application in terms of bugs identified with browser inconsistencies, not previously anticipated. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 6</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the final Axure prototype that will be developed for this project.  It build on the design of prototype 5 and increased consistency between screens.  Additional data elements were added and the interface for creating and managing case studies was redesigned.  Axure has been a useful tool for developing these initial prototypes, however limitations of static web pages and producing complex interactions has proven to be time consuming and difficult. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Elements Review and Reporting</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/data-elements-review-and-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/data-elements-review-and-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today a short meeting was held to discuss the overall progress of the prototype to date and demonstrate the key functionality to the EL representative for the school.  Comments were made on how further improvements could be made to the data collection part of the system.  The group is going to review the prototype over the next week further and share feedback at our next meeting.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 5</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prototype 5 integrated both expedition and non-expedition subject areas.  The concept of &amp;lsquo;strands&amp;rsquo; being units within the system has been further defined in this design.  The interactions for strands and sub-sections as well as optional elements has been further developed in this prototype.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Expedition Subject Areas</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/non-expedition-subject-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/non-expedition-subject-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This sprint continued discussion of non-expeditions.  This week we focused primarily on restructuring the prototype to correctly integrate subject areas that do not fall under the typical expedition.  The home page was refined further and several changes were made to the math non-expedition subject area created for prototype 4.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 4</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prototype 4 includes a lot of design changes stemming from our FSW and Winter Terms sprint.  These changes include improvements to the homepage and accomodation for non-expedition placeholders for FSW, winter and subject areas.  Other enhancements were made in the expedition forms and sub sections as well as proper differentiation between them and their non-expedition counterparts.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FSW and Winter Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/fsw-and-winter-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/fsw-and-winter-terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this meeting was to finalize the data-entry sections of the system by further describing functionality specifically on non-expedition semesters.  Non-expeditions were discussed both as FSW / Winter term as well as other subject areas or strands of the curriculum delivered in parallel to expeditions.  The majority of this meeting focused on refining prototype 3 further by improving the placement of FSW and winter semesters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 3</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After presenting the second prototype at the last requirements meeting, it was apparent that more work needed to be done with defining what an expedition is and where its sub-sections correctly belong.  Much of the discussion of the meeting concentrated on Standards, Learning Targets, Assessment (STAs) and their correct placement in the map.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining Expeditions</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/defining-expeditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/defining-expeditions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This meeting focused on prototype 3 and refining the structural breakdown of expeditions and their sub-components.  New terminology was introduced to describe the various elements of semester based expeditions and non-expeditions and certain elements were re-positioned within the data-entry screens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Level Requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/high-level-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/high-level-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the first requirements meeting since the initial kickoff back in April.  Prototype 2 served as the main discussion for this meeting as we dove deeper into the expected functionality and nuances of an EL curriculum map.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 2</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This prototype was developed after several discussions via email regarding the initial requirements of the project.  The kickoff meeting was helpful in framing the basics of the system in the first prototype, however it was lacking detail and missing some of the crucial elements of an EL map.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grade level Curriculum Planning Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/grade-level-curriculum-planning-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/grade-level-curriculum-planning-meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several grade level planning sessions will be observed in November / December 2013.  More details on the results of these observations will be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axure Prototype 1</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/axure-prototype-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This prototype was developed after the initial April 10th requirements meeting.  It includes a basic design with an incomplete &amp;lsquo;dashboard&amp;rsquo; page providing user interactions for various parts of the system.  Upon learning more about the unique needs of EL, it was determined the main expedition form / interactions was fundamentally flawed.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field Survey Structure</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/field-survey-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/field-survey-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;exploratory-requirements-survey&#34;&gt;Exploratory Requirements Survey&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to complete this short survey.  Your answers will contribute to building an effective Curriculum Mapping solution for Monarch Academy. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Assumptions for Qualitative Research</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/philosophical-assumptions-for-qualitative-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/philosophical-assumptions-for-qualitative-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In any kind of work or study, we always bring a certain set of beliefs as well as philosophical assumptions.  Qualitative researchers understand the importance of beliefs and theories that inform their work and also actively write about them in their research. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Teaching and Learning Experiences in Higher Education</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/online-teaching-and-learning-experiences-in-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/online-teaching-and-learning-experiences-in-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007 I graduated from the University of Ulster&amp;rsquo;s new E-Learning masters program.  For my thesis, I developed a research study on collaborative learning and more specifically the adoption of Adobe Connect at the University of Maryland University College.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health Services and Challenges facing the Low-Literacy Population</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/health-services-and-challenges-facing-the-low-literacy-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/health-services-and-challenges-facing-the-low-literacy-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the United States, a large proportion of the population falls into the category of having low literacy skills.  “A long-awaited federal study finds that an estimated 32 million adults in the USA — about one in seven — are saddled with such low literacy skills that it would be tough for them to read anything more challenging than a children&amp;rsquo;s picture book or to understand a medication&amp;rsquo;s side effects listed on a pill bottle.” Toppo (2009).  This poses challenges for these individuals seeking services and assistance online using websites that have traditionally not catered for this segment of the population.  Services including health information for vaccinations, information on the availability of free clinics in the area, and advice and support from organizations such as Planned Parenthood, simply aren’t as easily accessible to this group of the general population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illuminate</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/illuminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/illuminate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Illuminate is the code name for a curriculum mapping project I am currently developing as part of my Doctoral thesis.  I will be using this part of the blog to document my progress as development progresses.  My plan is to have a version 1 of Illuminate completed by the spring of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altas Rubicon Exploratory Eye Tracking Research</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/altas-rubicon-exploratory-eye-tracking-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/altas-rubicon-exploratory-eye-tracking-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2012, an eye tracking study was conducted with six participants in order to test the overall usability of a commercially available curriculum mapping application called Atlas Rubicon.  The results of this research helped determine some areas of interest that have helped shape the ExpeditionMapper project in terms of search, browse and general information retrieval.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An eBook for an Undergraduate Web Design Course</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/an-ebook-for-an-undergraduate-web-design-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/an-ebook-for-an-undergraduate-web-design-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CMST 385 Principles of Web Design and Technology is an undergraduate web design course taught at the University of Maryland University College. The online version of the class involves the use of WebTycho and weekly conferencing. For a long time, supplemental learning resources have been used in this class including videos, presentations and external reading materials to assist with student learning, all of which have been made available through the WebTycho Learning Management System (LMS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Cognition Factors in Online Messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/human-cognition-factors-in-online-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/human-cognition-factors-in-online-messaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a hypothetical study, the Interaction Design and Information Architecture (IDIA) department at the University of Baltimore decided to promote their Humans Computers and Cognition (IDIA 640) course to prospective students already enrolled in the program and to those interested in the field.  In order to foster interest in the program, it was decided that a banner or ticker should be deployed within the department website, providing news updates and information about the program to interest visitors.  This paper documents the development of a ticker prototype intended to serve this purpose.  Discussion of the chosen content, rationale for design from a human centered computing and cognitive standpoint follows in the paper.  The prototype has been designed with an emphasis on addressing memory, forgetting, learning and mood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“We Choose the Moon” From a Human Attention Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/we-choose-the-moon-from-a-human-attention-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/we-choose-the-moon-from-a-human-attention-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web based games and interactive applications have become a common means of teaching a wide range of concepts throughout K-12 schools in the United States.  With the declining costs of hardware and software coupled with the increase of available bandwidth and transfer speeds, the development of educational applications has advanced significantly in the last five years. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a Major News Website From a Human Cognitive Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/evaluation-of-a-major-news-website-from-a-human-cognitive-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/evaluation-of-a-major-news-website-from-a-human-cognitive-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, a shift has occurred in the way many people access, read and watch current events and news.  From the traditional newspapers and scheduled television news programs, we have moved to a more dynamic interactive medium, which dispenses information in a real-time format.  News websites are a fairly young media; however they have evolved exponentially since the late 1990s to the current time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article examines a popular news organization’s web presence and evaluates this resource in terms of human centered design and cognition.  It explores the website’s effectiveness of compiling and distributing news information in a way that is easy for humans to comprehend and process.  Much of the focus has been on the main homepage of the website; however other site pages have been taken into consideration adding context to some of the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Inside The Webb Layout with Genesis</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-inside-the-webb-layout-with-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-inside-the-webb-layout-with-genesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since the last major update to Inside The Webb, so I am pleased to post that today I completed customization of the new site layout using Studiopress Genesis Wordpress theme framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe&#39;s Secrets Revealed for New Creative Suite 5</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adobes-secrets-revealed-for-new-creative-suite-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been quite a few videos in regards to the new Adobe Creative Suite 5, most specifically Photoshop and design software. There have been a lot of updates from the not-so-old CS4 set of Web and Graphic design software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Float Launches their Inspiration Blog with New Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/design-float-launches-their-inspiration-blog-with-new-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design Float is one of the top social news sites for web design and graphics articles. Having been online for almost 2 years now, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk and hype about the site which has contributed to its popularity. However over the past few weeks, the owner of DF has begun to post again on the Design Float Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infamous Design Blog DesignM.ag Being Auctioned on Flippa</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs have become the de-facto of the internet revolution over the past 2-3 years. As web design has shot off and every 16 year old and their mother has started to learn XHTML/CSS, blogging about it has just become another step in the process. DesignM.ag is one of the most popular, sharing free tutorials and graphics frequently in their posts. As of April 5 the site has been put up for auction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Page /r/circlejerk Clones 4Chan&#39;s Website Design</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/reddit-page-/r/circlejerk-clones-4chans-website-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After visiting Reddit today, it was pretty obvious my favorite SubReddit circlejerk was up to no good. After toying around all week with a funny upvote arrow which looked similar to male genitalia, we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen an invasion of 4chan into Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Jacob Gube of Six Revisions Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the freelance and web design/development community for years now, starting back when I was attending high school. I always keep up with the latest blogs, tutorials, tips, and design tricks from the community, and no blog has shown greater content with a higher rate of growth than Six Revisions. Jacob Gube is the founder and main writer at the blog, and I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to share with you some great Q&amp;amp;A&amp;rsquo;s between us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Martin Leblanc Eigtved, Founder of IconFinder.net</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-martin-leblanc-eigtved-founder-of-iconfinder.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-martin-leblanc-eigtved-founder-of-iconfinder.net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many design blogs and showcases today are giving away icons for free. Even in large sets, social media icons and small graphics are making their way into the big time. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of collecting icons, and all of these free sites are extremely useful and always in my bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Point Forums Re-Design for the New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the internet marketing and blogging forums out there, Digital Point was the first community I ever joined. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there for years, learned so much from the members and even contributed to helping others along their path. There are many other choices, but DP will always hold a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of running the same design, DP has finally upgraded to a fresh web 2.0 look and feel to the entire site! Now running what is clearly the latest version of vBulletin 4.0 Forum Software, the latest design really kicks new life into such an expansive and helpful community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Professional XHTML/CSS Slicing Company Slicejack</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-professional-xhtml/css-slicing-company-slicejack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSD Conversion is a very high-paying business. Many amazing designers know how to work through Photoshop but just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or haven&amp;rsquo;t learned how to code their designs into XHTML and CSS code. This is where many popular companies come in to help, the most popular being psd2html.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing DesignMoo for Social Media Traffic to your Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/utilizing-designmoo-for-social-media-traffic-to-your-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all of you running a design blog out there, DesignMoo is a site you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to bookmark. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all know of Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity, this has caused many smaller sites to spawn offspring and grow into micro-niche Digg sites. DesignMoo is one of these style of sites for graphic and web design, and can bring in a lot of traffic to your blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;amp;A with Premium Wordpress Theme Developer WPMonk</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/qampa-with-premium-wordpress-theme-developer-wpmonk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many premium Wordpress themes roam the internet these days, all of varying quality and development. I recently found a really neat Premium Wordpress design company WP Monk. They run a very impressive website design, plus their premium themes are impeccable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Information and Photo now Displayed After each Post</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/author-information-and-photo-now-displayed-after-each-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep, I finally decided to add some of those updates I had planned on rolling out so long ago! I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to add author info to the posts on Inside the Webb for a while, just haven&amp;rsquo;t had time. Well I finally found some time, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Interview with LogoMoose Creator Dirk Leys</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/exclusive-interview-with-logomoose-creator-dirk-leys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/exclusive-interview-with-logomoose-creator-dirk-leys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So many inspirational sites have sprung up recently. The web is crawling with CSS galleries and logo galleries, but only a few really break the mold and stand out as the most creative, inspiring, and useful collections. LogoMoose makes it to the top of my list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Introduces a Brand New, Sleek Home Design</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-introduces-a-brand-new-sleek-home-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago Facebook released their newest design. Nothing has changed on personal profile pages, but when you log into your account you should see some major changes to how everything is layed out. This came as a shock to me when I logged in to check my status for the first time earlier today - a brand new look!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Vibrant and Inspiring Design Blog ilovecolors</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-vibrant-and-inspiring-design-blog-ilovecolors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most graphic design blogs today can serve as a source of inspiration and creativity. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a fantastic design blog covering everything from Photoshop to Typography. ilovecolors is a fantastic blog run by Elio Rivero, and I was lucky enough to get a behind-the-scenes interview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging and Design Tips from Pro Blog Design Creator Michael Martin</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-and-design-tips-from-pro-blog-design-creator-michael-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-and-design-tips-from-pro-blog-design-creator-michael-martin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly one of the most important aspects of running a blog is keeping up with design trends. You can write amazing articles and share the best tips on the web, but if your blog looks like a run-down 1990&amp;rsquo;s ripoff or some generic Wordpress template, chances are you won&amp;rsquo;t be attracting many visitors to your site. The most famous and successful bloggers realize how important a custom design really is, and no expenses are cut when it comes to design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Little Box of Ideas Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-little-box-of-ideas-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much alike many designers out there, I&amp;rsquo;m constantly craving new graphic design inspiration, web design galleries, and everything the life of a designer should be filled to the brim with. This leads me on my quest of finding the best design blogs out on the internetz, and my interview today is no shortage. Little Box of Ideas is a great design and creativity blog, focusing on great topics such as graphics tutorials and typography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Creativity Den: New Inspiration Blog for Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-creativity-den-new-inspiration-blog-for-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-creativity-den-new-inspiration-blog-for-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web designers have no shortage of inspiration these days. It seems as though there are new design and inspiration blogs popping up every hour, and there&amp;rsquo;s never a shortage of posts to go around. With new social media sites such as Design Moo and DesignBump, articles for graphic artists and web designers are able to spread like wildfire. It&amp;rsquo;s rare when you run across a unique and helpful blog, and this is the case with CreativityDen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Chris Spooner of Line25 Web Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-chris-spooner-of-line25-web-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-chris-spooner-of-line25-web-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: web design is hot. With the internet&amp;rsquo;s popularity skyrocketing, younger and younger kids are getting into design and web projects, even freelancing! Not to say this is bad at all, it&amp;rsquo;s actually started a large spread of web design and development tips and inspiration, mostly posted onto blogs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Successful Design Blog: Lessons from Web Designer Depot</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/developing-a-successful-design-blog-lessons-from-web-designer-depot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs are the new in, everybody who is interested in making money online and knows any amount about web design is starting their own blog. Granted only a few have made it and gained star-status in the blogosphere, but there are thousands of others who struggle to build their way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Device Applications from a Development Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-device-applications-from-a-development-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mobile-device-applications-from-a-development-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations-and-opportunities-explored&#34;&gt;Limitations and opportunities explored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile devices have many positive aspects including opening up networking channels and increasing the accessibility of information, but as with any new technology, potential pitfalls must be researched, remedied and cautiously provided for.  This literature review discusses several potential pitfalls of mobile technologies as well as potential opportunities faced by developers of software as well as mobile device manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, several themes are highlighted through existing literature on areas concerned with the development of mobile applications.  These themes include context awareness, mobile security, usability and accessibility.  By focusing on these themes and researching the literature available, the developer will be better equipped to face the challenges and opportunities ahead in order to create practical and usable applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with PSDFan&#39;s Designer and Blogger Tom Ross</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-psdfans-designer-and-blogger-tom-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-psdfans-designer-and-blogger-tom-ross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding good tutorials on web design and development can be tough these days. Although so many people have and use Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and all of the creative suite, there are very few that know how to utilize the tools properly and create astounding designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CollegeHumor&#39;s Designer Anna Hiort</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-collegehumors-designer-anna-hiort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten my fair share of laughs from all of the hilarious content on the internet today. Photoshopped photos and amazing/retarded videos are spread like wildfire through forums and social networking sites. However, one of the best sites I&amp;rsquo;ve ever run across for generally hilarious content has to be Collegehumor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrazyLeaf Design Blog - Inspiration and Resources for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/crazyleaf-design-blog-inspiration-and-resources-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/crazyleaf-design-blog-inspiration-and-resources-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Web designers can spend hours looking for inspiration. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, up at 1 in the morning trying to work out a project you&amp;rsquo;ve got lined up but nothing seems to be hitting you. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m at a design roadblock I usually turn to typical web design blogs to get the juices flowing again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside FudgeGraphics: Web Design Freebies and Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-fudgegraphics-web-design-freebies-and-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-fudgegraphics-web-design-freebies-and-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: we all love free stuff. As web designers, graphic designers, PHP programmers, or AJAX gurus we all love finding free code snippits or templates to work with. I have recently found a great new web design and development-focused blog Fudgegraphics which is full of all the freebies any web designer could want!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Blog.SpoonGraphics with Creator Chris Spooner</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/inside-blog.spoongraphics-with-creator-chris-spooner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personally one of my favorite graphic design blogs on the web, Blog.Spoongraphics provides amazing resources, tutorials, and tips for graphic and web designers everywhere. The creator and designer of the blog Chris Spooner is also a freelance web designer himself, and I landed a great interview with him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Designer and Blogger Andrew Houle of MyInkBlog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/graphic-designer-and-blogger-andrew-houle-of-myinkblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/graphic-designer-and-blogger-andrew-houle-of-myinkblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Graphic and web designers, lend me your ears! We have another great graphic design blog to add to our list today, MyInkBlog. Featuring all sorts of free goodies to download, amazing tutorials, inspiring articles, and a whole lot more! MyInkBlog is one of the premiere graphic and web design blogs on the web, with over 3,000 Twitter followers and almost 4,000 RSS followers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Colorburned with Designer Grant Friedman</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-colorburned-with-designer-grant-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-colorburned-with-designer-grant-friedman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a large collection of design blogs leaves your options open to so much. You can find original content very quickly, learn a lot more through tutorials and freebies, and also get to know a lot of people in the design community. Colorburned is another very popular and well-respected graphic design blog which features some of the best design news, resources, and tutorials from around the web. This can include free textures, patterns, Photoshop brushes, tutorials, and a whole lot more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inside Web Design Dev with Creator Michael Dunlop</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-web-design-dev-with-creator-michael-dunlop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/getting-inside-web-design-dev-with-creator-michael-dunlop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Dunlop is what you could call an &amp;ldquo;internet marketer&amp;rdquo;, making enough money online to provide a livable income since he was in college. Since he has started in internet marketing, Michael has created a slew of websites, one of which is a very popular website design blog. Web Design Dev posts up large collections of lists, tools, tricks, and tutorials to help beginning and professional web designers alike to find the best resources on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Digg-Clone for Designers DesignBump</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-digg-clone-for-designers-designbump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg was the first social news site to really skyrocket into popularity, gaining millions of pageviews a day to the site. No doubt, there would be similar sites in separate niches on the web. The first of these niche sites in the web design category was Design Float, which has had many issues with databases and keeping the site up and running properly. Therefore, a new competitor has stepped up to the plate: DesignBump.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Steven Snell of DesignM.ag</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-steven-snell-of-designm.ag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Website Design has become one of the most popular career paths, especially with many teenagers taking entry-level classes in high school, and with so many available resources to learn from. There are tons of web design blogs, galleries, news sites, and much more. However, there are only a select few that actually post up quality content, update frequently, and are run my professional web designers who can teach us all a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Behavior Leadership and Teamwork</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-behavior-leadership-and-teamwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/organizational-behavior-leadership-and-teamwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the summer of 1997 I worked for a period of four months on a contract for a company called the Environment and Heritage Service (EHS) Northern Ireland.  During this time I worked primarily within the Computing Department of the organization and our team was involved with all the Information Technology issues across the various offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper will look at the two main areas of leadership and team working as I learned a great deal while working there.  The main Information Technology department comprised of a Systems Manager with three main Network Managers working for him and staff working under the database managers for various computing related jobs. To give an idea of the responsibilities of the staff within the computing department I will list briefly what each position has entailed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of having one large government over individual governments</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/advantages-of-having-one-large-government-over-individual-governments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/advantages-of-having-one-large-government-over-individual-governments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The information gathered for this essay on social space and the European Social Chapter was obtained from various sources.  These included Internet sites listed in the Bibliography and numerous books and material from the University of Ulster Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will attempt to show how the benefits for and the objectives against the European Social Chapter affect social space within various countries in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;european-social-space&#34;&gt;EUROPEAN SOCIAL SPACE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind social space within the European Union has highlighted certain areas of concern within countries of the European Union.  Employment, industrial health, social costs of industry, labour mobility and social spending within these countries are all elements dealt within European Social Space.  Social space also involves education, training, housing and health.  Over recent years the issues of social welfare have become extremely important as the EU has grown.  One of the main reasons for this is that public expectations have increased rapidly that their governments will play a major role in improving overall quality of life, bringing social affairs firmly into the public domain.  It is only over recent years that the idea of Social Space within the European Union has become a vital factor to the expansion of the EC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manpower Planning Versus Human Resource Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/manpower-planning-versus-human-resource-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/manpower-planning-versus-human-resource-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The differences between manpower planning and human resource planning will be outlined within this essay along with how human resource planning has built on and developed traditional manpower planning. The main sources of information to compile this assignment have come mostly from Coleraine and Jordanstown University of Ulster Libraries and the books used and referred to have been listed in the references and bibliography section of this essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;manpower-planning&#34;&gt;MANPOWER PLANNING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason the process of manpower planning came about was to help the management of employees within a business organization.  Manpower planning looks at the organizations current and future need of labour within the business.  The current and future employment needs are a great concern and the examination of supply within the local area for possible new employees if required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
