<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Microblogging on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/microblogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microblogging on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/microblogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Craze.cc - New and Innovative Social News/Discussion Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/craze.cc-new-and-innovative-social-news/discussion-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/craze.cc-new-and-innovative-social-news/discussion-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love social media, I&amp;rsquo;ll get that off my chest right now. There are so many new and innovative websites popping up each and every day which take the idea of social networking and spin it around with some new features and a new look, then present it to you in a clean and elegant way. Well Craze.cc is certainly one of those sites, and the idea is spreading fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Releases Sleek, Clean Homepage Redesign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/twitter-releases-sleek-clean-homepage-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/twitter-releases-sleek-clean-homepage-redesign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this has been covered by many media blogs, Twitter has indeed released a new home page! I have to say, I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the new design and it definitely allows for a better user experience when first arriving at the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plurk Rivals Twitter as the Next Popular Microblogging Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter - you either love it or hate it. The application has exploded onto the web, where not only everybody seems to need one, but even larger corporations have set up Twitter accounts. Tweeting is the next big thing! tons of people are getting into this new trend, while naysayers stand behind and wave their fingers in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with New Twitter app Taweet: The Future of Twitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-new-twitter-app-taweet-the-future-of-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-new-twitter-app-taweet-the-future-of-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Twitter has blown through other social media sites, it&amp;rsquo;s become one of the most trafficked websites of the present day. Everybody and their grandma is using Twitter, and there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of helpful applications and Twitter resources for them all! Ranging from Twitter wallpaper creators to free icons or avatars, the internet hosts them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Rose&#39;s Failed Microblogging Platform: Where Pownce went Wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/kevin-roses-failed-microblogging-platform-where-pownce-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/kevin-roses-failed-microblogging-platform-where-pownce-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Pownce first launched in the summer of 2007, I thought it would revolutionize how I communicated and shared stuff with my friends! By the way Kevin Rose had hyped it, you could share any type of file (music, video, .zip archive), share notes, share photos, really anything you wanted to with your friends! This was an application that was desperately needed on the web, and to this day I still claim there needs to be something to fill the void.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
