<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyberspace-and-Cybersecurity on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cyberspace-and-cybersecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyberspace-and-Cybersecurity on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cyberspace-and-cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security Concerns with Outsourcing IT Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/security-concerns-with-outsourcing-it-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/security-concerns-with-outsourcing-it-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing has become very common in recent years, especially in the field of Information Technology. So that companies can focus more on their core business, it makes sense to outsource many of their IT services and work to external organizations. In addition to this, quite often outsourcing can provide a cheaper means of labor if sent off shore, which enables the company to reduce costs and remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What exactly is Cyberspace and Cybersecurity?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-exactly-is-cyberspace-and-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-exactly-is-cyberspace-and-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of buzz around the web in recent years regarding information assurance and cybersecurity especially with an increasing trend in cyber attacks and intrusions.  UMUC just recently started several cybersecurity degree and certificate programs in the fall of 2010.  Over the next few weeks articles will be posted here related to cybersecurity, starting with answering the basic question of what the terms cyberspace and cybersecurity mean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Cybersecurity Programs begin Second Semester at UMUC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-cybersecurity-programs-begin-second-semester-at-umuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-cybersecurity-programs-begin-second-semester-at-umuc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Maryland University College (UMUC) is getting ready to begin its second semester of offering their new Cybersecurity programs, which opened to students in the fall of 2010. Two masters programs as well as an additional specialization in one of their existing information technology degrees were introduced last semester, along with an undergraduate program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government Cybersecurity Initiative for a Universal Internet ID</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-cybersecurity-initiative-for-a-universal-internet-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-cybersecurity-initiative-for-a-universal-internet-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Commerce Department has been handed the authority from the Whitehouse to create an Internet ID for Americans as one of the latest efforts in Cybersecurity policy.  The idea is that everyone would have one secure login to access many services online to increase security and privacy and reduce the need to remember numerous passwords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
