<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Apps on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apps on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aptana acquired by Appcelerator</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aptana, the company behind the popular programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Aptana Studio, announced today that they have been acquired by Appcelerator. Aptana has been the choice for many web development professionals for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Joomla 1.6 Pushes Enterprise Level Features</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/new-joomla-1.6-pushes-enterprise-level-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new version of the popular Joomla Content Management System (CMS) was released early last week and has already reached over 115k in downloads. 1.6 has been in the making for some time and earlier beta versions have been tested over the last few month. The first release candidate (RC1) was made available for download on December 14th, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MailBrowser - Simple Gmail Plugin for Managing your Contacts</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailbrowser-simple-gmail-plugin-for-managing-your-contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailbrowser-simple-gmail-plugin-for-managing-your-contacts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long, long time have I been looking for a great Plugin for Gmail to help manage my contacts. I send a lot of e-mails to a lot of different people, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to sort through all of my mail and attachments without getting lost in the thousands upon thousands of messages. However with the new browser plug-in MailBrowser, it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Releases Official Buzz Share Widget with Live Counter</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-releases-official-buzz-share-widget-with-live-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-releases-official-buzz-share-widget-with-live-counter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has recently released the beginning of a small API working with Google Buzz. There have been plenty of issues with Google Buzz&amp;rsquo;s widget, and many other sites made their own to fill the gap. However with this newest release even Mashable has updated their Buzz widgets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find Popular and Useful Websites Easily with TopSite</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/find-popular-and-useful-websites-easily-with-topsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/find-popular-and-useful-websites-easily-with-topsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever find yourself wondering &amp;ldquo;how can I find the best blogs on the web, or the best social media apps for rating food or movies&amp;rdquo;? Well look no further, your web search engine is here! When your trust pal Google has failed you, I recommend giving TopSite a shot. It&amp;rsquo;s a social search engine which tracks down the top 10 most popular websites based on a keyword.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Young Blogger and Founder of Blogussion Alex Fraiser</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-young-blogger-and-founder-of-blogussion-alex-fraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-young-blogger-and-founder-of-blogussion-alex-fraiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of blogs, namely up and coming stars. Blogussion caught my eye a few months ago, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been following their articles ever since. Jam-packed with blogging and internet traffic-related SEO articles, Blogussion is one of the top blogging resources on the web today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chill to your Music Library anywhere with Grooveshark</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/chill-to-your-music-library-anywhere-with-grooveshark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/chill-to-your-music-library-anywhere-with-grooveshark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I found out about Grooveshark a few months ago, it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionized the way I listen to music. No longer am I stuck with my iTunes playlists and limitions on songs - nor do I even need to store the songs on my computer!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Yahoo! Answers Q&amp;amp;A Competitor Blurtit</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Answers has to be the most well-known and popular Question &amp;amp; Community on the web. However there is always room for improvement on apps like these, and Blurtit takes the cake. Building more of a community around the idea of the &amp;ldquo;Ask Any Question&amp;rdquo; niche, Blurtit allows users to connect like never before, searching for the most popular questions and sharing knowledge between everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Your Username Availability on Tons of Websites with Namechk</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/check-your-username-availability-on-tons-of-websites-with-namechk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/check-your-username-availability-on-tons-of-websites-with-namechk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us enjoy sticking with our usernames. We sign up with the same username on multiple websites, and this is especially true with social networking/bookmarking sites as it allows your name to become a presence in the community. Only thing is, there&amp;rsquo;s so many people online that the chances of our username being take is, well, pretty decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plurk Rivals Twitter as the Next Popular Microblogging Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter - you either love it or hate it. The application has exploded onto the web, where not only everybody seems to need one, but even larger corporations have set up Twitter accounts. Tweeting is the next big thing! tons of people are getting into this new trend, while naysayers stand behind and wave their fingers in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Web&#39;s Cutest URL Shortening Service Moourl.com</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I know, I&amp;rsquo;m a guy and the word &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in my vocabulary. Well if I ever needed to use the word cute to describe anything, it would have to be moourl.com. It&amp;rsquo;s a URL shortening service with an actually &lt;em&gt;bearable&lt;/em&gt; design to it. Beautiful vectors and color scheme, I love the site!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes at Posterous.com:  Filesharing Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/behind-the-scenes-at-posterous.com-filesharing-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing files over the internet used to be a devilish task. Finding the right application, storage space, or transporation method for files used to be very difficult only 5 years ago. Now with file upload sites and forums/bulletin boards to share files, sending your friend a song or posting up a funny picture has never been easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Express your 3D Avatars with Frenzoo</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/express-your-3d-avatars-with-frenzoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating your own avatar online has become a popular trend. Everybody wants to have their own personal expression to make them stand out from the crowd. There is a different type of communication over the internet, and you need something to make yourself stand out next to everyone else. Most people have unique username&amp;rsquo;s on websites, but avatars are a great way to stand out with style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Adobe&#39;s Primary Developer of Rich Internet Applications Mark Anders</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-adobes-primary-developer-of-rich-internet-applications-mark-anders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-adobes-primary-developer-of-rich-internet-applications-mark-anders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Anders is a senior principal scientist at Adobe Systems, and one of his core responsibilities is to make Flash the platform for building the next generation of rich internet applications. Prior to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of Macromedia, Anders started and led the Flex Builder Team, but he is probably best known for his work at Microsoft, where during a decade-long career he led the creation of ASP.NET.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link Your Social Networking Profiles Together with SocialFollow</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/link-your-social-networking-profiles-together-with-socialfollow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social Follow is a cool new web application that combines all of your other social networking and social bookmarking profiles. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all have accounts on Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Digg, and many other profiles around the net. With SocialFollow, you are able to combine all of these profiles into one handy button. These are great for posting to your blog, sharing in your forum sigs, or posting it anywhere around the web!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with New Web 2.0 Web Conferencing Tool Fuze Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-new-web-2.0-web-conferencing-tool-fuze-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-new-web-2.0-web-conferencing-tool-fuze-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We can all agree that connecting with each other is important. This is especially the case in the world of business, where communications can be as important as arranging a business meeting promptly at 9:30AM. I spoke with Patrick Moran of Fuze Meeting&amp;rsquo;s Marketing division, and got the inside scoop on the new web conferencing tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage Your Businesses Internet Marketing with twtapps</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/manage-your-businesses-internet-marketing-with-twtapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/manage-your-businesses-internet-marketing-with-twtapps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has skyrocketed into mainstream with seemingly no meaning behind it. The simple application allowing everyone in the world to share what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, thinking, or feeling in 140 characters has grown into one of the most popular web 2.0 applications on the web, and it&amp;rsquo;s no doubt there are many apps on the web to accompany it. Although not affiliate with Twitter in any way, twtapps is a neat website that features some of the coolest web 2.0 applications that help businesses market on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Display Your High-Resolution Photos Online with ClosR.it</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/display-your-high-resolution-photos-online-with-closr.it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/display-your-high-resolution-photos-online-with-closr.it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ClosR.it is another great web 2.0 application I stumbled upon while browsing the net. It allows photo enthusiasts, designers, professional photographers, and really anyone who takes pictures to upload their photos in high-resolution. The problem with many other image hosting services is that they cap limits on the site of the photos, or just re-size them. ClosR.it allows full HD image views, perfect to share with all of your photo-enthusiastic friends and family!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Zemanta: Improving the Way We Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-zemanta-improving-the-way-we-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-zemanta-improving-the-way-we-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more people are discovering the wonders of web 2.0 technology, working with things such as wikis and social networks. However, nothing has been rising faster than the amount of people learning about blogging. Blogging is a great way to post your ideas, research, thoughts, or random ramblings online and share it with the mass of internet users who stumble upon it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with the Psychedelic New App Yooouuutuuube</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-the-psychedelic-new-app-yooouuutuuube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-the-psychedelic-new-app-yooouuutuuube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a big fan of Digg.com, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you remember seeing an article hit the front page about 2-3 weeks ago titled The Most Trippy and Hypnotic Thing You Will See Today. It linked to a video of many split-screen Alice in Wonderland clips playing over some neat background music, and really was the most trippy thing I&amp;rsquo;d seen! After this first discovery, tons of videos from Yooouuutuuube.com started popping up everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with GigTide - The Online Resume Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-gigtide-the-online-resume-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-gigtide-the-online-resume-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many online applications to help with business-type things: You&amp;rsquo;ve got your invoice applications, e-mail marketing, time management, project management&amp;hellip; the list could go on and on. And although there are so many sites out there for businesses to utilize, GigTide is definitely one of the greatest all-around useful sites for anybody looking to create, manage, or perfect their resume&amp;rsquo;s online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flick.to.Twitt - Easily share your Flickr Photos on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/flick.to.twitt-easily-share-your-flickr-photos-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/flick.to.twitt-easily-share-your-flickr-photos-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has become one of the largest web 2.0 applications on the web today, in comparison with Facebook, MySpace, and Digg. Along with this, Flickr has become a giant web app where users can share their photos. However, with the use of Flick.to.Twitt you are now able to post your Flickr photos right to your Twitter account! I have an interview with the site&amp;rsquo;s founder Marco Almeida, in which we discussed the site&amp;rsquo;s creation and also future goals for the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
