<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Money on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/money/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Money on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency: Future Money or Unicorn of Century?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/cryptocurrency-future-money-or-unicorn-of-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/cryptocurrency-future-money-or-unicorn-of-century/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency is virtual currency or digital currency that is designed to be used as a medium of exchange to make secure transactions. It does not have any centralized control and there isn’t any regulatory authority as opposite of banks and electronic money. Its control works as a blockchain that is a distributed ledger. The technical system that is base of cryptocurrency was created by an unknown person or a group named Satoshi Nakamoto. In 2017 thousands of cryptocurrencies were created, most of them were like Bitcoin. Is the system of cryptocurrencies the balance and safety of ledgers are managed by miners which are a community of distrustful parties. Miners get a financial benefit for maintaining the security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social News Website for Financial Articles and Tips at Tip&#39;d</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/social-news-website-for-financial-articles-and-tips-at-tipd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/social-news-website-for-financial-articles-and-tips-at-tipd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t find many great social news websites these days. You know, the kind that let you vote on stories and the most popular hit the front page? Digg and Reddit are still pretty good, and there are a few nice Pligg sites out there but overall not too many.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Young Blogger and Founder of Blogussion Alex Fraiser</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-young-blogger-and-founder-of-blogussion-alex-fraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-young-blogger-and-founder-of-blogussion-alex-fraiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of blogs, namely up and coming stars. Blogussion caught my eye a few months ago, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been following their articles ever since. Jam-packed with blogging and internet traffic-related SEO articles, Blogussion is one of the top blogging resources on the web today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Money with Short URL Service adf.ly</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With web URL shortening services in high demand these days, it&amp;rsquo;s no wonder adf.ly hadn&amp;rsquo;t come around sooner. Allowing you the same benefits of other free short URL services, adf.ly allows one big benefit - each pageview you get counts towards a small percentage of CPM costs for advertisers! Long story short, you get paid to use adf.ly&amp;rsquo;s services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Jacob Gube of Six Revisions Design Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-jacob-gube-of-six-revisions-design-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the freelance and web design/development community for years now, starting back when I was attending high school. I always keep up with the latest blogs, tutorials, tips, and design tricks from the community, and no blog has shown greater content with a higher rate of growth than Six Revisions. Jacob Gube is the founder and main writer at the blog, and I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to share with you some great Q&amp;amp;A&amp;rsquo;s between us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Digg&#39;s New Ad System is Gaining Popularity</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has always been an extremely innovative company. Launching into the social news bit in 2004, the site has grown immensely popular with monthly pageviews in the tens of millions. Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity has allowed for a counter-culture of internet users to become Diggers, voting on the best stories to hit the front page and sent traffic spikes to interesting and useful blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Point Forums Re-Design for the New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/digital-point-forums-re-design-for-the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the internet marketing and blogging forums out there, Digital Point was the first community I ever joined. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there for years, learned so much from the members and even contributed to helping others along their path. There are many other choices, but DP will always hold a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of running the same design, DP has finally upgraded to a fresh web 2.0 look and feel to the entire site! Now running what is clearly the latest version of vBulletin 4.0 Forum Software, the latest design really kicks new life into such an expansive and helpful community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Profitable are Niche Video Game Forums and Communities?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of the web 2.0 boom is communication. People are communicating now more than ever, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise. With the vast size of apps these days, along with almost every website running some type of forum or blog, users are more connected than ever! Many marketers can see ways to utilizing this new &amp;ldquo;social networking fever&amp;rdquo; as a turning point to make some serious money online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pro Blogger Daniel Scocco Shares his Internet Marketing Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/pro-blogger-daniel-scocco-shares-his-internet-marketing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/pro-blogger-daniel-scocco-shares-his-internet-marketing-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are millions, maybe even billions of different blogs on the internet, with new blogs being created every minute. Blogging is still a relatively new realm to the internet, and people are just started to discover it&amp;rsquo;s power-first hand. Daniel Scocco, the creator and main blogger on the site Daily Blog Tips runs a few very popular blogs on the web. Some could call him a professional blogger, an internet marketer, or even a social media guru.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with ManageME7: Learn to Save Your Money the Easy Way!</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-manageme7-learn-to-save-your-money-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-manageme7-learn-to-save-your-money-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for some stability with your income? I think we all do, since we all can&amp;rsquo;t make 100k every month. Especially in times like these, managing money properly is a great skill to have and utilize, and knowing when to spend money and on what can be a challenge. With manageME7, you can manage your money 7 days a week, 24 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
