<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet-Marketing on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/internet-marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet-Marketing on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/categories/internet-marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways to Improve Your Site&#39;s Crawlability (And Why You Should)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/7-ways-to-improve-your-sites-crawlability-and-why-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/7-ways-to-improve-your-sites-crawlability-and-why-you-should/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While keyword research, link-building, content optimization, and other on-page strategies can improve your domain&amp;rsquo;s search ranking, search engine optimization (SEO) starts with getting your pages indexed and to do that you need to ensure they&amp;rsquo;re crawler-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawler bots, like human users, appreciate sites which have clear, structured, readable data. However, since crawlers can only spend a limited amount of time and resources per site, domains with incoherent site maps, broken links, or 404 errors might not get indexed at all, effectively invisibilizing it for all potential users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Marketplace vs Craigslist: Which site is better?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-marketplace-vs-craigslist-which-site-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/facebook-marketplace-vs-craigslist-which-site-is-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After destroying MySpace, Orkut, Flickr and several other internet companies. FB is now after Craigslist, Olx, Kijiji, and 100s of other classified listing sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social networking giant opened its marketplace for everyone using FB. The new feature has not gone well with people using this site just for fun. But it has been received well by business owners using Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is FB&amp;rsquo;s new tool a great alternative to OLX, CL, and other similar websites? Go through the below comparison of the two sites to get the answer!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 8 Best Business Listing Sites (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-8-best-business-listing-sites-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-8-best-business-listing-sites-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of internet users has grown from 100 to 3+ billion. Although a lot of firms have benefited from the internet revolution, many businesses have become bankrupt. eCommerce platforms have destroyed the business of 1000s of brick and mortar stores. The only way to survive the wrath of these sites is to make people aware of your shop/service and the products you sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listing a business online is the best way to promote it. Although there are 100s of sites where you can list your office, shop, or service, not all sites are trustworthy or complete. Businesses won&amp;rsquo;t benefit from such sites. Hence, they should not be listed on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Payoneer with Amazon and ShareASale affiliate programs</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/using-payoneer-with-amazon-and-shareasale-affiliate-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/using-payoneer-with-amazon-and-shareasale-affiliate-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In you&amp;rsquo;re not in the US, sending and receiving payment from an affiliate marketing service operating in the US can be a headache. PayPal is the first choice of many freelancers, bloggers, etc. But in the last 2 to 3 years, Payoneer has emerged as a great alternative to PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Payoneer is a reliable service and many leading marketing services support it. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve received about $200 without any hassles. I&amp;rsquo;m using this payment service to receive commissions from Amazon Associates US, ThemeForest, and ShareASale affiliate programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Best WordPress SEO plugins (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-7-best-wordpress-seo-plugins-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/top-7-best-wordpress-seo-plugins-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re running a website, you must optimize it for search engines to succeed as a blogger, business owner etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers can have nightmares while making their site or client&amp;rsquo;s website SEO friendly. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a content management system, this task is a piece of cake, thanks to the best SEO plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to WordPress CMS or if you&amp;rsquo;re site is not performing well in search engines, you should use the following WordPress SEO plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging vs YouTube (Vlogging): Which is better?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-vs-youtube-vlogging-which-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-vs-youtube-vlogging-which-is-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging and Vlogging are two sides of the same coin. Many people employ these two methods to earn money online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In blogging, you start a new website and publish reviews and details of your favorite products, tips, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vlogging, you ask someone to record your video or if you&amp;rsquo;re publishing a video tutorial, you use a screen recorder tool to capture the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, I have shared a detailed comparison of Blogging and Vlogging. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to pursuing a career in Vlogging or Blogging, my comparison will clear your doubts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdSense vs Affiliate Marketing : The best monetization technique is...</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adsense-vs-affiliate-marketing-the-best-monetization-technique-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adsense-vs-affiliate-marketing-the-best-monetization-technique-is.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People join affiliate programs or signup for AdSense to earn money online. In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering which monetization technique you should implement on your blog, go through the following 6 to 7 paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adsense-or-affiliate-marketing--which-is-better&#34;&gt;AdSense or Affiliate Marketing : Which is better?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AdSense is the world&amp;rsquo;s best CPC network. It has the highest CPC rates. AdWords is the backbone of AdSense. It has a large number of advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you become a part of AdSense program, you have to place an ad code on your website in accordance with the AdSense terms and conditions. You can get the ad code from your AdSense dashboard. AdSense provides various types of ad formats&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best tools to check Google keyword rankings for a website</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-tools-to-check-google-keyword-rankings-for-a-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once your website starts ranking in search engines, you should check its Google keyword rankings often. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, competitors may steal your keywords and use them on their portals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website with high domain authority won&amp;rsquo;t be affected by this. But if a site is new, competitor stealing your major keywords may have a negative impact on your website traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some of the best free tools to check website ranking in Google search engine. Most of the tools covered in this blog post won&amp;rsquo;t ask you to create an account. Nor they&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to enter credit or debit card details. Apart from free tools, we&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned a powerful premium SEO tool that provides plenty of useful SEO tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to increase Amazon Affiliate sales?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-increase-amazon-affiliate-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-increase-amazon-affiliate-sales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Associates affiliate program is one of the most important sources of revenue for many bloggers. If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to earn money from Amazon, follow the below tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;effective-tips-to-increase-amazon-affiliatesales&#34;&gt;Effective tips to increase Amazon affiliate sales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;send-more-traffic&#34;&gt;Send more traffic:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is counted among the most trusted brands in the world. It has listings of more than a million products. The products include household items, accessories for mobile devices, cameras, etc. They have a competitive price tag due to which people don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate in buying expensive or inexpensive stuff from Amazon. Hence, the more traffic you send to Amazon, the higher will be the conversions. I can say this from my personal experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Google Penalty Checker tool for sites whose traffic is down</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-google-penalty-checker-tool-for-sites-whose-traffic-is-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-google-penalty-checker-tool-for-sites-whose-traffic-is-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1000s of changes have been made to Google Search Engine since it was launched in 1998. Engineers working at Google don&amp;rsquo;t reveal what changes were made, but they do warn or alert webmasters that their website traffic may be impacted by an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case your blog or website is not performing well suddenly in Google, you must know that your site has suffered a Google Penalty. To know which Google Algorithm has affected your site, you can either post help message in the webmaster central forum or use the Baracuda Panguin tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Writing vs Blogging : Which is better?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/freelance-writing-vs-blogging-which-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/freelance-writing-vs-blogging-which-is-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelance writing and blogging are two of the most preferred options for making money online by working from home. If you are planning to begin your career as an FW or a blogger, go through the below pros/cons of these two career options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros-of-freelance-writing&#34;&gt;Pros of Freelance Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better reputation&lt;/strong&gt;: If authority sites like Huffington post, BGR, TechCrunch are publishing your articles, 1000s of people might know you. You are likely to have a good fan following.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best AdSense alternatives to earn dollars not cents (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-adsense-alternatives-to-earn-dollars-not-cents-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-adsense-alternatives-to-earn-dollars-not-cents-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AdSense is a great platform for making money online. But getting approved for it or having a five or six figure AdSense revenue is a difficult task. People have a misunderstanding that GA is the only advertiser with which they can make them rich. They are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is predictable in the world of internet. Hence, you should always try out different strategies for maximizing revenue from the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many methods of monetizing a website. This is what I have learned from my 3 years of experience as a blogger. People make a mistake by depending only on AdSense aka a single source for their earnings. They don&amp;rsquo;t experiment with other monetization programs aka AdSense alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Visual Traceroute is a free WhoIs lookup, Packet sniffer tool for PC</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/open-visual-traceroute-is-a-free-whois-lookup-packet-sniffer-tool-for-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/open-visual-traceroute-is-a-free-whois-lookup-packet-sniffer-tool-for-pc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traceroute is an important and one of the most widely used commands. It is recognized in all the operating systems. In case you&amp;rsquo;re searching for standalone Windows program that simulates the traceroute command, try out Open Visual Traceroute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OVT is an open source program that can be used on Windows as well as Linux OS. It has been built with Java and available for download on sourceforge.com. Users must install the Java Runtime Environment to use this program. OVT has the below three essential utilities that webmasters often use:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MailMunch Review: Killer plugin to build opt-in forms and get new leads</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailmunch-review-killer-plugin-to-build-opt-in-forms-and-get-new-leads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailmunch-review-killer-plugin-to-build-opt-in-forms-and-get-new-leads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Opt-in forms and Newsletter subscription services are the best tools to get loyal and regular audiences. Once your blog or website has a couple of thousand regular readers, money will keep flowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress, without any doubt, is the top CMS. Millions of bloggers use WP to fulfill their dream of running a website or making money from the web. If you use WP and want to add a killer opt-in form to your site for free, then download and install the MailMunch plugin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Website Traffic Free Online with these awesome tools</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/check-website-traffic-free-online-with-these-awesome-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every website visit you visit uses an analytics tool to track visitors and their activity. Only the organization that own its will have access to the tracking data. The company doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to make their data public unless they&amp;rsquo;re generating advertising revenue from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people using the internet are always curious to know how much traffic does their favorite website get. But as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned earlier, the real data is with the site&amp;rsquo;s owner. Thus, no matter what tool you use, you cannot get the exact statistics of a website traffic unless the company decides to share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsense Placement Tips and Strategy to increase earnings</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adsense-placement-tips-and-strategy-to-increase-earnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adsense-placement-tips-and-strategy-to-increase-earnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pay per click advertisement platforms is the best way to monetize a blog. When it comes to the best PPC networks, nothing beats Google Adsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GA is the most widely used PPC platform. It has 10 to 100 times better CPC rates than Chitika, InFolinks, Bidvertiser, etc. Thus, your first monetization option should always be Adsense. If your AdSense application gets disapproved, you should make your website better before resubmitting the application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OptinMonster Review 2018: Powerful lead generation plugin for WP</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/optinmonster-review-2018-powerful-lead-generation-plugin-for-wp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/optinmonster-review-2018-powerful-lead-generation-plugin-for-wp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Email marketing is probably incomplete without a good newsletter plugins that add subscription forms in our WordPress sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of free plugins to add newsletter forums to a website, but the features they offer are limited. For example, the MailChimp plugin doesn&amp;rsquo;t support popups, and it lacks an Ajax based form which makes the sign-up process fast. You can only change the background and button color with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improve Alexa Rank of your Website to attract advertisers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/improve-alexa-rank-of-your-website-to-attract-advertisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/improve-alexa-rank-of-your-website-to-attract-advertisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google PR is dead, and it will never be updated in the future. Advertisers have started using Moz rank and domain authority to know whether a website is ranking high in search engines or not. One more important factor they consider for checking the popularity of a website is the Alexa rank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain authority and MR is generated by inbound link data of a website. Thus, a site with a good number of backlinks will have a good DA/MR. In one of our articles, we have mentioned that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t create inbound links manually. Make sure that you go through the article to know what happens when backlinks are created artificially.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Pingdom alternatives to check website speed</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A website which opens quickly in the browser ensures the best user experience and higher rankings in Google search engine. Thus, the first thing that you should do after launching a new website is to check the page loading speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pingdom is one of the most widely used website speed checking tools, but it offers limited features due to which many people will use its below 2 top alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gtmetrix&#34;&gt;GTmetrix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;gtmetrix pingdom alternatives check website speed&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.carnaghan.com/best-pingdom-alternatives-to-check-website-speed/images/gtmetrix.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon vs Flipkart affiliate program : High paying and best in India</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/amazon-vs-flipkart-affiliate-program-high-paying-and-best-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/amazon-vs-flipkart-affiliate-program-high-paying-and-best-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Affiliate programs from e-commerce portals are the best way to earn money online in India. If you have a website with decent traffic and a bank account, you can quickly join them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of the 1000s of affiliate marketers who are earning decent money with e-commerce based affiliate programs. I&amp;rsquo;ve signed up with Amazon, Snapdeal, and Flipkart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is the biggest online retailer, and its affiliate program is active in every country it operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SEO Framework plugin review : Free Yoast alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-seo-framework-plugin-review-free-yoast-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/the-seo-framework-plugin-review-free-yoast-alternative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yoast is no doubt the best SEO plugin, but its version 3.0.x has disappointed a lot of WordPress users. The plugin is useful, but you cannot get support from Joost De Valk and his team unless you&amp;rsquo;re a premium user. Because of these two reasons, many people have switched from Yoast to its alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new plugin called the SEO framework is getting a good response from the WordPress community and it is emerging as an excellent alternative to Yoast. Is this plugin right for you? Check out the below review to know this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloom plugin review : Create and add stylish Newsletter optin forms</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/bloom-plugin-review-create-and-add-stylish-newsletter-optin-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/bloom-plugin-review-create-and-add-stylish-newsletter-optin-forms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Email Optin forms are useful because they attract visitor&amp;rsquo;s attention. When a visitor signs up with the form, the website will have a new loyal reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters will bring referral traffic to your blog. If your site is not ranked in search engines, you can still get free traffic provided that you send a newsletter to an email address or share blog posts on social media networks or the best bookmarking websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biggest Google algorithm update for 2016 is underway</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/biggest-google-algorithm-update-for-2016-is-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/biggest-google-algorithm-update-for-2016-is-underway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Penguin and Panda are two of the most talked about and important algorithm updates in the world of SEO. They are refreshed once or twice a year. Every webmaster keeps an eye on these two updates. Panda algorithm focuses on promoting high-quality content high in the Google search engine. Google Penguin can hit blogs and websites that are not following the webmaster guidelines. Both these algorithms affect&amp;rsquo;s rankings of large as well as new sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoast vs All in One SEO pack : The best WordPress plugin is...</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/yoast-vs-all-in-one-seo-pack-the-best-wordpress-plugin-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/yoast-vs-all-in-one-seo-pack-the-best-wordpress-plugin-is.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress is an excellent content management system, but it has a lot of modules that may cause duplicate content problems and many other SEO related issues. Thus anyone using WordPress to power their websites should install an SEO plugin. An excellent plugin will have options to disable unnecessary WordPress features which in turn improves SEO score of your blog. It will take care of meta description, titles, redirects, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of free and premium SEO plugins available for download in the WordPress directory, but people trust just 2 of them - Yoast and All in One SEO. If you&amp;rsquo;re confused in choosing between these two plugins, go through the below paragraphs where we&amp;rsquo;ve covered a detailed comparison of Yoast vs. ALL in One SEO pack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best way to manage affiliate links in WordPress without headaches</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-way-to-manage-affiliate-links-in-wordpress-without-headaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-way-to-manage-affiliate-links-in-wordpress-without-headaches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a blogger, I&amp;rsquo;ve to use various strategies to earn money online. I use Google Adsense and many affiliate programs for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about ads delivered by Google. The entire process is automated and handled to perfection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing affiliate links can be a headache because you&amp;rsquo;ve to be careful while using them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you link them in your WordPress posts in such a way that Google can crawl them, your blog will be penalized. Matt Cutts (former webspam head at Google) had revealed that Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t like affiliate links. Thus you should make them nofollow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and Best SEO tools that every webmaster should use</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/free-and-best-seo-tools-that-every-webmaster-should-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization aka SEO is one of the most important topics of discussion in the online world. Without following the right guidelines and SEO tips, it will be tough to survive as a blogger or a webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use search engines and Facebook more than any other website. Promoting a product on Facebook is not free. If you want to do this without any costs, you will have to build a large community and huge fan following. Search engines like Google are powerful and every major or minor website is indexed by them. It indexes your site without any costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increase AdSense earnings without any special plugin or testing</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/increase-adsense-earnings-without-any-special-plugin-or-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/increase-adsense-earnings-without-any-special-plugin-or-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adsense is one of the best platforms to earn money online, but not everyone is successful with it. Some bloggers make 500+ dollars per month just with AdSense and others have to satisfy themselves with just 50 or 100 USD. If people use black hat methods and cheat Google, their accounts are banned immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to cheat, nor you have to waste time in using websites that claim to increase your ad revenue. If you work smartly and hard, your Adsense income will increase. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some effective tips and strategies that will help you to earn more cash with Google&amp;rsquo;s publisher program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grammarly review: Best grammar checker (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/grammarly-review-best-grammar-checker-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/grammarly-review-best-grammar-checker-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;English is one of the most widely accepted and spoken language around the globe. Whether its a TV or any other electronic device, English is used everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English has more than 2 billion speakers. Due to its importance, it has become an official language in many countries. Although it is used everywhere, let us face a truth that many people do not speak and write good English. There might be many reasons behind this problem, but one of the most common is the grammar. Grammar is vast and many people fail to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular 9 to 5 job vs Working from Home Online</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/regular-9-to-5-job-vs-working-from-home-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/regular-9-to-5-job-vs-working-from-home-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many people think that working from 9 to 5 is a nightmare. Some believe that working from home is a great experience. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been in both the situations and thus I can give a better explanation on this topic. I have spent a  year in an IT company. My working time was 9 to 6 or 7. After working for a year, I resigned from the job to be a self-dependent person. I can say that my decision was right as I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved my goal. I am earning decent money, and I am confident that my earnings will increase as the time passes by. Although I work from home and have a source of income, sometimes I feel frustrated because of disturbances from the surrounding. Here are the pros and cons of working from home online and working in a 9 to 5 job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Online Plagiarism Checkers that are Free</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-online-plagiarism-checkers-that-are-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-online-plagiarism-checkers-that-are-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plagiarism in the online world is the art of stealing others content without the copyright holder&amp;rsquo;s permission. It is bad for bloggers because duplicate content can affect their blog&amp;rsquo;s search engine visibility. Bloggers are not the only professionals worried about Plagiarism. Teachers always fear that their students might copy the homework from any one of the billions of sites available in Google&amp;rsquo;s search index. If you think that your hard work has been copied or if you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher who wants to check the genuineness of student&amp;rsquo;s homework, use the below tools to find all websites that have duplicate content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killer ways to make money without AdSense (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/killer-ways-to-make-money-without-adsense-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/killer-ways-to-make-money-without-adsense-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adsense program accepts websites that have quality content or very high organic search traffic. If your site doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any of these 2, instead of wasting your time in applying for Adsense account, use any of the below techniques to monetize your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve not recommended ad networks like Infolinks, Chitika, Vigilink, media.net as they pay you just one or 2 pennies for traffic from non-English speaking countries. These advertising networks demotivate bloggers due to their low payouts. Hence many bloggers quit their online careers within 5 or 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Tail Pro 3.0 Discount and Review (Aug 2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/long-tail-pro-3.0-discount-and-review-aug-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/long-tail-pro-3.0-discount-and-review-aug-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the user opens a search engine like google or bing? What is the 1st thing he sees? A large text box accompanied with a search button. To find information, the user must enter some data in the textbox. This data in SEO world is known as the keyword. Many bloggers, webmasters, and SEO professionals use keywords to rank their websites in search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right keywords is not an easy task. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to spend plenty of hours using online tools like Google AdWords, sem rush, etc. Adwords is owned by Google. It is used by online marketing professionals and agencies to advertise products or websites in Google. The advertisers use AdWords to find keywords that a user enters in the search field of the Google. You can use this free tool only if you have a Google account.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 best methods to monetize a blog and make good money online</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/4-best-methods-to-monetize-a-blog-and-make-good-money-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/4-best-methods-to-monetize-a-blog-and-make-good-money-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have a blog and want to start making money online with it? We&amp;rsquo;ve shortlisted the most widely used website monetization strategies through this article. Many bloggers around the world use these monetization methods and they have been successful so far. To execute these strategies successfully, make sure that your website gets minimum unique 200 visitors every day through search engines or social networks. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a blog, go through this article Blogger vs WordPress and read our review of Hostgator and A small orange. You&amp;rsquo;ll get an idea of what online career and blogging is all about. Here are the 4 &lt;strong&gt;most widely used methods to monetize a blog&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEMRush Free Trial account : Find Competitor Keywords and more</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/semrush-free-trial-account-find-competitor-keywords-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professional bloggers are successful because they make wise use of SEO tools. For example, Pat Flynn, the owner of smart passive income has launched a few niche blogs that earn him over 5000 dollars every month. Patt is one of the most intelligent bloggers in the world. He makes more than 50000 dollars every month by promoting various products. He makes use of different keyword research tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amit Agarwal, the top Indian blogger, initially used Google Keyword Planner to find relevant and high traffic keywords, as a result, his blog labnol generates more 2.5 million INR revenue through AdSense. Most of the articles on his site labnol.org rank on 1st page of Google.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mailchimp latest Pricing, Review and Features</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailchimp-latest-pricing-review-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailchimp-latest-pricing-review-and-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many bloggers believe that email marketing is the best strategy to have a loyal and regular audience. Thus, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an email opt-in widget on all popular blogs. There are a lot of email subscription service for blogs and in my perspective, Mailchimp tops the list. Mailchimp pricing is attractive, cheap and its features are powerful. The free version of MailChimp service allows you to change newsletter template, design, title. It can generate newsletter automatically from your blogs RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key reasons why Google adsense application gets disapproved</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/key-reasons-why-google-adsense-application-gets-disapproved/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/key-reasons-why-google-adsense-application-gets-disapproved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google AdSense program can make you rich. But getting your blog or website approved for it is a challenging task. Newbie bloggers have to wait for several months before their sites get approved for Adsense ads. I had applied for 20 times. Each time I applied for Adsense, I got the rejection message stating that my blog is not eligible to participate in the program. The news was disheartening, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from submitting the application again. My site got approved on the 21st attempt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon associates affiliate program tips for 100% success</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/amazon-associates-affiliate-program-tips-for-100-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/amazon-associates-affiliate-program-tips-for-100-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warren buffet says that you should not depend on a single source of income. This statement from the US-based Billionaire and one of the richest man in the world is brilliant and it makes sense in many ways. If you’re a blogger, go through the below article to know why the statement from Warren Buffet is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many online sources that can generate revenue from a blog. Google AdSense is at the top. If you own a technology blog, you can start earning money by registering an affiliate account with eCommerce sites. Most of these sites will accept you into their affiliate program in a couple of days. But to achieve success with them, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow some genuine tips. This article will reveal tips that I follow. I&amp;rsquo;m using amazon, Flipkart and SnapDeal affiliate links on one of my site along with Adsense. Thus, I make a fair income working from the comfort of my home. Amazon is the best affiliate network for technology niche blogs. It has the highest commission rates. It was initially difficult for me to make money with the affiliate networks as I was a newbie or a beginner. But now, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my earnings. Anyways, here are the tips that you should follow. Please note that you use the below tips for any affiliate network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best backlink checker tools to check link profile of any website</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-backlink-checker-tools-to-check-link-profile-of-any-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/best-backlink-checker-tools-to-check-link-profile-of-any-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most discussed topics in SEO is backlink. Backlinks help a blog to get higher ranking in search engines. But they can be a reason for the death of your blog too. Backlinks can be created manually by the user or artificially via software. If you write a high-quality article which has unique content, your article will be referred to another website via a backlink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural links are useful, and you should avoid creating links using any other method. Google has explicitly mentioned in its webmaster guidelines that it will show no mercy on sites that participate in link exchanges, link trades, 5etc. Google&amp;rsquo;s Penguin algorithm has proven to be a sworn enemy of websites with bad link profiles. The Penguin algorithm is refreshed every 3 or 4 months. Tools such as Mozcast and algoroo can make you aware of any Google update. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing the best five most powerful tools to check backlinks. These tools can generate a report on the daily, monthly or yearly basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Anthony Feint&#39;s E-book Flipped - Guide to Flipping Websites for Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/review-of-anthony-feints-e-book-flipped-guide-to-flipping-websites-for-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/review-of-anthony-feints-e-book-flipped-guide-to-flipping-websites-for-profit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reading Anthony Feint&amp;rsquo;s blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://feint.me/&#34;&gt;http://feint.me/&lt;/a&gt; for a long time now. He shares some amazing motivational posts about getting into the real world of internet marketing, and also provides tips and tricks about how to substantially grow your website and keep motivated.. really it&amp;rsquo;s more of an inspirational blog than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infamous Design Blog DesignM.ag Being Auctioned on Flippa</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/infamous-design-blog-designm.ag-being-auctioned-on-flippa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design blogs have become the de-facto of the internet revolution over the past 2-3 years. As web design has shot off and every 16 year old and their mother has started to learn XHTML/CSS, blogging about it has just become another step in the process. DesignM.ag is one of the most popular, sharing free tutorials and graphics frequently in their posts. As of April 5 the site has been put up for auction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Money with Short URL Service adf.ly</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/make-money-with-short-url-service-adf.ly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With web URL shortening services in high demand these days, it&amp;rsquo;s no wonder adf.ly hadn&amp;rsquo;t come around sooner. Allowing you the same benefits of other free short URL services, adf.ly allows one big benefit - each pageview you get counts towards a small percentage of CPM costs for advertisers! Long story short, you get paid to use adf.ly&amp;rsquo;s services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Blogging and Writings Tips from Blogussion</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/useful-blogging-and-writings-tips-from-blogussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/useful-blogging-and-writings-tips-from-blogussion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a huge fan of Blogussion for a long time now. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, they&amp;rsquo;re a quality blog in regards to blogging tips, writing techniques, time management and focusing on goals of making money online through blogging. There are many others in this niche (ProBlogger comes to mind), but nobody really delves deeply into details and provides as much useful information as Blogussion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Digg&#39;s New Ad System is Gaining Popularity</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-diggs-new-ad-system-is-gaining-popularity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digg has always been an extremely innovative company. Launching into the social news bit in 2004, the site has grown immensely popular with monthly pageviews in the tens of millions. Digg&amp;rsquo;s popularity has allowed for a counter-culture of internet users to become Diggers, voting on the best stories to hit the front page and sent traffic spikes to interesting and useful blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How StumbleUpon Advertising has Increased Traffic</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-stumbleupon-advertising-has-increased-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-stumbleupon-advertising-has-increased-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those who use StumbleUpon for both casual web surfing and internet marketing know how powerful the site is. It&amp;rsquo;s grown substantially over the last year or 2, increasing not only it&amp;rsquo;s userbase but also the amount of submitted articles and stumbled posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Profitable are Niche Video Game Forums and Communities?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-profitable-are-niche-video-game-forums-and-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of the web 2.0 boom is communication. People are communicating now more than ever, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise. With the vast size of apps these days, along with almost every website running some type of forum or blog, users are more connected than ever! Many marketers can see ways to utilizing this new &amp;ldquo;social networking fever&amp;rdquo; as a turning point to make some serious money online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with is.gd URL Shortener</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-is.gd-url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/interview-with-is.gd-url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New URL Shortening services hit the web every week it seems. I can remember not too long ago when TinyURL was just starting up, and that hit with a huge bang. Ever since then, there have been countless creations of URL shorteners (where some even provided stats). However, only a select few have really succeeded to hit mainstream popularity and be of any use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founder of Omegle.com Answers Questions From Redditors</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/founder-of-omegle.com-answers-questions-from-redditors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omegle.com has spread across many social networking hubs, forums, and internet chatrooms rapidly over the past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s a new site with a very simple concept: you log in anonymously and talk to someone else. Someone random, someone you&amp;rsquo;ve *probably* never even met before, just talking about whatever. It seems like a breeding ground for spam and pranks, but it ultimately seen very positive results in traffic and user response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pro Blogger Daniel Scocco Shares his Internet Marketing Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/pro-blogger-daniel-scocco-shares-his-internet-marketing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/pro-blogger-daniel-scocco-shares-his-internet-marketing-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are millions, maybe even billions of different blogs on the internet, with new blogs being created every minute. Blogging is still a relatively new realm to the internet, and people are just started to discover it&amp;rsquo;s power-first hand. Daniel Scocco, the creator and main blogger on the site Daily Blog Tips runs a few very popular blogs on the web. Some could call him a professional blogger, an internet marketer, or even a social media guru.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
