<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Web2-0 on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web2-0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web2-0 on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web2-0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aptana acquired by Appcelerator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/aptana-acquired-by-appcelerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aptana, the company behind the popular programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Aptana Studio, announced today that they have been acquired by Appcelerator. Aptana has been the choice for many web development professionals for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social News Website for Financial Articles and Tips at Tip&#39;d</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/social-news-website-for-financial-articles-and-tips-at-tipd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/social-news-website-for-financial-articles-and-tips-at-tipd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t find many great social news websites these days. You know, the kind that let you vote on stories and the most popular hit the front page? Digg and Reddit are still pretty good, and there are a few nice Pligg sites out there but overall not too many.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Newest Trending Social News Sharing Community Humsurfer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-newest-trending-social-news-sharing-community-humsurfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult these days to track down the best social news sharing communities. There are the classics such as Digg and Reddit, and also smaller niche communities containing topics like design and programming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CypherBox.net - Great Pligg-based PR4 Social Bookmarking Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cypherbox.net-great-pligg-based-pr4-social-bookmarking-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cypherbox.net-great-pligg-based-pr4-social-bookmarking-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just want to say, I absolutely love Pligg. It&amp;rsquo;s an amazing PHP script, free to download which allows you to set up your own social news site similar to Digg. Many micro-niche sites have popped up running on Pligg&amp;rsquo;s backend, and CypherBox is my latest find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rumors of Yahoo! Taking Down MyBlogLog could be False</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rumors-of-yahoo-taking-down-mybloglog-could-be-false/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rumors-of-yahoo-taking-down-mybloglog-could-be-false/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting around December I had seen a lot of blogs posting about Yahoo! considering closing the doors on MyBlogLog. I was sad to hear this news, as I have been a huge fan of MyBlogLog since it first launched in 2005. It was a simple community of bloggers with a simple goal of uniting the best writers and bloggers on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Digg.com is heading for a Major Pitfall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-digg.com-is-heading-for-a-major-pitfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-digg.com-is-heading-for-a-major-pitfall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember a time when Digg used to roam wild in the Social News kingdom. It was the force to be reckoned with when it came to internet marketing - everybody needed to hit the front page to gain some traffic to their site. I&amp;rsquo;m sure tons of blogs have built their popularity off of Digg&amp;rsquo;s massive traffic influx, but there are many signs pointing towards this site closing the lid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Yahoo! Answers Q&amp;amp;A Competitor Blurtit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-yahoo-answers-qampa-competitor-blurtit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Answers has to be the most well-known and popular Question &amp;amp; Community on the web. However there is always room for improvement on apps like these, and Blurtit takes the cake. Building more of a community around the idea of the &amp;ldquo;Ask Any Question&amp;rdquo; niche, Blurtit allows users to connect like never before, searching for the most popular questions and sharing knowledge between everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plurk Rivals Twitter as the Next Popular Microblogging Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plurk-rivals-twitter-as-the-next-popular-microblogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter - you either love it or hate it. The application has exploded onto the web, where not only everybody seems to need one, but even larger corporations have set up Twitter accounts. Tweeting is the next big thing! tons of people are getting into this new trend, while naysayers stand behind and wave their fingers in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with New Twitter app Taweet: The Future of Twitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-new-twitter-app-taweet-the-future-of-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview-with-new-twitter-app-taweet-the-future-of-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Twitter has blown through other social media sites, it&amp;rsquo;s become one of the most trafficked websites of the present day. Everybody and their grandma is using Twitter, and there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of helpful applications and Twitter resources for them all! Ranging from Twitter wallpaper creators to free icons or avatars, the internet hosts them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organize your Schedule Online with Plan.fm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/organize-your-schedule-online-with-plan.fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/organize-your-schedule-online-with-plan.fm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I found another cool app the other day. plan.fm, simple name with a simple purpose of uniting all of your plans in one place. You can draw in feeds from social networking sites such as Facebook and Twitter and merge your plans all into one calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Webb is back with a New Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-the-webb-is-back-with-a-new-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-the-webb-is-back-with-a-new-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So yes, there haven&amp;rsquo;t been many updates here at Inside the Webb in the past few months. However, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a whole new batch of great interviews, reviews, and demos of the latest and greatest web 2.0 apps across the internet! We&amp;rsquo;ve launched with a brand new design and look, and we&amp;rsquo;re back to claim all web 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Web&#39;s Cutest URL Shortening Service Moourl.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-webs-cutest-url-shortening-service-moourl.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I know, I&amp;rsquo;m a guy and the word &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in my vocabulary. Well if I ever needed to use the word cute to describe anything, it would have to be moourl.com. It&amp;rsquo;s a URL shortening service with an actually &lt;em&gt;bearable&lt;/em&gt; design to it. Beautiful vectors and color scheme, I love the site!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Rose&#39;s Failed Microblogging Platform: Where Pownce went Wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/kevin-roses-failed-microblogging-platform-where-pownce-went-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/kevin-roses-failed-microblogging-platform-where-pownce-went-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Pownce first launched in the summer of 2007, I thought it would revolutionize how I communicated and shared stuff with my friends! By the way Kevin Rose had hyped it, you could share any type of file (music, video, .zip archive), share notes, share photos, really anything you wanted to with your friends! This was an application that was desperately needed on the web, and to this day I still claim there needs to be something to fill the void.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
