<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Domain-Names on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/domain-names/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Domain-Names on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/domain-names/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GoDaddy review: A web hosting and domain registration company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/godaddy-review-a-web-hosting-and-domain-registration-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/godaddy-review-a-web-hosting-and-domain-registration-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Godaddy is one of the top domain registrars and hosting companies of the world. It has over 500K customers. I&amp;rsquo;m one of the customers of Godaddy. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using its email hosting and domain registration service for 5 years. Here&amp;rsquo;s my review of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;list-of-godaddy-services-that-i-use&#34;&gt;List of GoDaddy services that I use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premium email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;domain-names&#34;&gt;Domain names&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godaddy website is user-friendly. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced or a novice user, registering a new DN is easy with GD. The home page of GoDaddy&amp;rsquo;s official website features a text box through which you can find domain names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where to buy AI domain for the best price?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/where-to-buy-ai-domain-for-the-best-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/where-to-buy-ai-domain-for-the-best-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The AI domain extension was launched in 1994/1995 for the use of companies and individuals based in a Carribean country Anguilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, the world&amp;rsquo;s largest search engine doesn&amp;rsquo;t display the information of Anguilla when you enter the search phrase as &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo;. Even Bing displays Artificial Intelligence search results for the search phrase &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, AI is an abbreviation for Artificial Intelligence. AI programs are self-learning applications that can be used for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EMD SEO and Google : 3 Important things that you should know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/emd-seo-and-google-3-important-things-that-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/emd-seo-and-google-3-important-things-that-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google penalizes spammy EMD sites, but do you know that Exact match domain names can outrank an authority site for a specific keyword? If you don&amp;rsquo;t know this, you are probably a newbie or an immature SEO professional. Here are the three important things that you should know as a Sear Engine Optimization professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;emd-domains-rank&#34;&gt;EMD domains rank&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can give 10 good examples that exact match domain names rank high for the keywords. Google starts ranking EMD sites only after a certain time period. The sites using EMD have 100s of polished articles with an average content length of 500 words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Namecheap Review 2018: Cheap SSL certificates and domains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/namecheap-review-2018-cheap-ssl-certificates-and-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/namecheap-review-2018-cheap-ssl-certificates-and-domains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was thinking about registering a new domain name for my new project. My first choice was GoDaddy. I had shortlisted a few TLDs from GoDaddy, but I was not able to buy a domain name for less than 10$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoDaddy runs a promotion wherein new customers can register a TLD for USD 0.99. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using GoDaddy for three years. Hence, I was not eligible for this offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips to register a new profitable top level domain name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tips-to-register-a-new-profitable-top-level-domain-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tips-to-register-a-new-profitable-top-level-domain-name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Registering a domain name is one of the most important activities of a person who wants to make an online career. But managing it and setting up a hosting service can be tricky. Name of a domain should be chosen wisely on the basis of below criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: A DN should have one or 2 keywords that will kelp users understand what your blog/site is all about. The keywords should not contain the names of large enterprises (and their products). For example Microsoft, Google, Amazon, Windows, etc. If you ignore this, you&amp;rsquo;ll face legal action in the future. The company might register a DMCA complaint against your site which will force search engines to remove your blog from their index.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
