<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bluehost on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bluehost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bluehost on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bluehost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bluehost vs Hostmonster vs JustHost (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-vs-hostmonster-vs-justhost-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-vs-hostmonster-vs-justhost-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People are often confused in choosing a hosting service for their sites. On the internet, you will find details on 100s of web hosting companies. Yesterday, one of our readers dropped me an email to know which is the best hosting among Bluehost, Justhost, and HostMonster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reader was confused because the plans and features offered by the companies are almost the same. I have shared a comparison of JH, HM, and BH in this article to help our readers in buying the best hosting plan for their site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluehost vs GoDaddy hosting Comparison and Plans (2018)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-vs-godaddy-hosting-comparison-and-plans-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-vs-godaddy-hosting-comparison-and-plans-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are planning to launch a new WordPress blog or a website, you may have shortlisted BlueHost and GoDaddy to host your site. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it? The reason why you may have chosen the two companies is their immense popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoDaddy uses TV channels as a promotion medium. BlueHost, being a decade old company is very popular among bloggers. Today, we have shared a detailed comparison of these two hosting providers so that it becomes easier for you to buy a hosting plan for your WordPress project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluehost hosting review 2018: Should you use it or not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-hosting-review-2018-should-you-use-it-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bluehost-hosting-review-2018-should-you-use-it-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many website hosting providers offer better features and more free add-ons but if budget is not a problem for you, choose a product on the basis of its quality, not quantity. Frankly speaking, the best hosting companies in the world are Hostgator and Bluehost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hostgator is a superb platform for hosting websites, but if your site has been banned for high resource utilization or some other reasons, you should consider signing up with Bluehost as it offers similar features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
