<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Ian Carnaghan</title>
    <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Ian Carnaghan</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ian Carnaghan</title>
      <url>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.carnaghan.com/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google AMP pros and cons: Should you implement AMP on your website?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-amp-pros-and-cons-should-you-implement-amp-on-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-amp-pros-and-cons-should-you-implement-amp-on-your-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Googleweblight, AMP aka Accelerated Mobile Pages is the new initiative from the search engine giant Google to make the web fast. As of today, over 900K sites are powered by AMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used AMP on my site for a month. Below, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared the Pros and Cons of Google AMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pros-of-google-amp-advantages&#34;&gt;Pros of Google AMP (Advantages)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;easy-to-implement&#34;&gt;Easy to implement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has published a detailed documentation which covers the HTML markup/CSS code you should use while implementing AMP. It also covers tutorials, news, case studies and demos of AMP. If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, go through the documentation before writing the code of your website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A2 Hosting review: Is it the fastest shared hosting service?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;A2 Hosting&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.carnaghan.com/a2-hosting-review-is-it-the-fastest-shared-hosting-service/images/A2-Hosting.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2 is one of the top 10 hosting companies in the world. The company has been operating since 2001/2002 and it has launched several hosting plans for every budget. As of today, over 10K sites are hosted on A2 servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2 offers cloud, VPS, dedicated and shared hosting service. Is it a reliable hosting firm? Are its plans affordable? Is its support staff customer friendly? Let&amp;rsquo;s find it out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging vs YouTube (Vlogging): Which is better?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-vs-youtube-vlogging-which-is-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/blogging-vs-youtube-vlogging-which-is-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging and Vlogging are two sides of the same coin. Many people employ these two methods to earn money online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In blogging, you start a new website and publish reviews and details of your favorite products, tips, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vlogging, you ask someone to record your video or if you&amp;rsquo;re publishing a video tutorial, you use a screen recorder tool to capture the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, I have shared a detailed comparison of Blogging and Vlogging. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to pursuing a career in Vlogging or Blogging, my comparison will clear your doubts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Fred Update: Hybrid of Google Phantom and Penguin algorithms?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-fred-update-hybrid-of-google-phantom-and-penguin-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-fred-update-hybrid-of-google-phantom-and-penguin-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has rolled out a new algorithm update on 7th of March. The head of web spam team, Garry Illyes has named the new algorithm as Fred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Fred update has killed the rankings of many websites overnight. It has brought people who were earning good amount of money online to their knees. Since 8th of March, many webmasters have reported that their sites have lost 80 to 90% traffic and some folks have reported a significant increase in organic traffic after March 8.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site deindexed by Google: Possible reasons why your website is removed</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/site-deindexed-by-google-possible-reasons-why-your-website-is-removed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/site-deindexed-by-google-possible-reasons-why-your-website-is-removed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Site deindexed from Google is the worst nightmare for any blogger or business owner. When Google removes your site from its index, your AdSense earnings are down by 70 to 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If traffic from social networks to your site is high, you can recover the earnings by becoming an affiliate marketer. If your site doesn&amp;rsquo;t get good traffic from Facebook, Twitter or any other social site, your website will be of no use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTP to HTTPS migration: Important thing you should know</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/http-to-https-migration-important-thing-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/http-to-https-migration-important-thing-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to Google, HTTPS is a ranking signal. If you make your website secure by configuring the web server to deliver HTTPS pages, your site may rank higher than an HTTP only portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, web browsers have begun to warn their users of non-secure web pages. The Google Chrome browser (version 56) marks non-https website pages as insecure when they have an HTML field for entering passwords, credit or debit card details, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set preferred domain correctly in Google Search Console</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-set-preferred-domain-correctly-in-google-search-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-set-preferred-domain-correctly-in-google-search-console/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting a preferred domain is one of the most important things to do after launching a new site. It takes few seconds to set a PD. Before setting a preferred domain, you should make sure that Google indexes only the URLS which you want to appear in search results. To do so, you must set up a 301 redirect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 301 redirect will prevent duplicate content issues. It will tell search engines that they should index the correct web pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to find and fix thin Content that leads to Google Panda penalty?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-find-and-fix-thin-content-that-leads-to-google-panda-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-to-find-and-fix-thin-content-that-leads-to-google-panda-penalty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your website is not performing well in the search engines, it is either hit by Google Penguin algorithm or has loads of thin content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have built backlinks manually or used a software to do so, it is likely that your website is affected by the real-time Penguin update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go through the following articles to learn why Penguin algorithm has struck your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Penguin 4.0 Update Rolled Out : Biggest Seo Update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Google Penalty Checker Tool For Sites Whose Traffic Is Down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Blog Commenting Is The Worst Link Building Strategy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guest Blogging Is Injurious To Your Blog And Online Career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your website has plenty of thin pages, the Google Panda or Phantom algorithm may have killed the traffic of your website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Penguin 4.0 update rolled out : Biggest SEO update (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-penguin-4.0-update-rolled-out-biggest-seo-update-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-penguin-4.0-update-rolled-out-biggest-seo-update-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has indexed over a billion web pages. It is the largest search engine in the world. Millions of sites depend on traffic from Google to earn revenue. Hence, when engineers working at Google roll out a new update, the SEO experts are excited and equally worried hoping that their or client sites don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; lose traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days back, the head of webspam at Google revealed that the much awaited Penguin 4.0 algorithm update is now in action. The Algoroo graph indicated massive fluctuations in search engine results starting from September 1. It seems like Google began testing the Penguin 4.0 update from 1st September onward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoast vs SEO framework vs AIO SEO plugins comparision</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/yoast-vs-seo-framework-vs-aio-seo-plugins-comparision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/yoast-vs-seo-framework-vs-aio-seo-plugins-comparision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEO is not a child&amp;rsquo;s play. One wrong setting can impact search engine rankings dramatically. Although WordPress is a decade old CMS and powers millions of sites, it is still suffering from various SEO issues. To fix the problem, the must install one of the 100s of SEO plugins available in the WordPress repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not install plugins which have poor ratings and promise plenty of features. I did the same mistake in the past and I still regret it. In the year 2013, my site lost 90 to 95% organic traffic because of a bad WordPress SEO plugin. Today, the best SEO plugins provide plenty of useful features. They let users optimize their site for higher local search rankings, add breadcrumbs to the website, add XML sitemaps, etc. Moreover, they work great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proof : HTTP 500 Internal Server Errors Impact Google Rankings</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/proof-http-500-internal-server-errors-impact-google-rankings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a regular reader of this blog, you may have noticed that this site was throwing error establishing database connection or internal server errors last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue which was caused by the Linux out of memory manager has now been fixed, and the site is now live 24 x 7. I&amp;rsquo;m using this server to host some other WordPress websites as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing the error was a very confusing task for me. To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about OOM process killer in Linux. If I knew how this module worked, the error would have been fixed on the day the error message appeared the system log file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WP Statistics is a Google Analytics alternative for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/wp-statistics-is-a-google-analytics-alternative-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some webmasters are concerned about their online privacy, and they will never use a popular third party analytics tool like Google Search Console, webmaster tools, clicky, StatCounter, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To safeguard their website statistics, people use a plugin which will create a database to store data related to websites. One of the best plugin to do this job is WP statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin works 24 x 7 to update the DB with visitor data. You can use it to compare website traffic from the best search engines i.e. Google, Bing, Baidu, Yandex, DuckDuckGo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding analytics dashboard to WordPress site in a minute</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/adding-analytics-dashboard-to-wordpress-site-in-a-minute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is one of the most valuable free tools for webmasters. With it, you can easily track traffic to your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytics makes you aware of many details like visitor source, average visit time, page views, website loading speed, device, operating system, the browser of the visitor and much more. It is easy to understand the tool. Even new bloggers or website owners will find it intuitive and easy to use. To start tracking the visitor behavior and traffic, the user has to install a tracking code to the header or footer section of their website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biggest Google algorithm update for 2016 is underway</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/biggest-google-algorithm-update-for-2016-is-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/biggest-google-algorithm-update-for-2016-is-underway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Penguin and Panda are two of the most talked about and important algorithm updates in the world of SEO. They are refreshed once or twice a year. Every webmaster keeps an eye on these two updates. Panda algorithm focuses on promoting high-quality content high in the Google search engine. Google Penguin can hit blogs and websites that are not following the webmaster guidelines. Both these algorithms affect&amp;rsquo;s rankings of large as well as new sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MailBrowser - Simple Gmail Plugin for Managing your Contacts</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailbrowser-simple-gmail-plugin-for-managing-your-contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mailbrowser-simple-gmail-plugin-for-managing-your-contacts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long, long time have I been looking for a great Plugin for Gmail to help manage my contacts. I send a lot of e-mails to a lot of different people, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to sort through all of my mail and attachments without getting lost in the thousands upon thousands of messages. However with the new browser plug-in MailBrowser, it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Releases Official Buzz Share Widget with Live Counter</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-releases-official-buzz-share-widget-with-live-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-releases-official-buzz-share-widget-with-live-counter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has recently released the beginning of a small API working with Google Buzz. There have been plenty of issues with Google Buzz&amp;rsquo;s widget, and many other sites made their own to fill the gap. However with this newest release even Mashable has updated their Buzz widgets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Merges Startup Visual Search Engine Plink with Google Goggles</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-merges-startup-visual-search-engine-plink-with-google-goggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/google-merges-startup-visual-search-engine-plink-with-google-goggles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has taken another step forward in visual and image search after acquiring UK-based startup Plink. Having only launched 4 months ago, Plink is a visual search engine which you can download as an Android app and take a photo of a picture to find out more information about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mashable-Style Google Buzz Widget with Counter Available by Njuice</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/mashable-style-google-buzz-widget-with-counter-available-by-njuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/mashable-style-google-buzz-widget-with-counter-available-by-njuice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many fans of the popular social media blog Mashable know, over the past month or 2 they have been messing around with a new Google Buzz button. Allowing you to share stories over Google Reader which publish into Google Buzz, this small widget has grown in popularity and it seems like every blogger is looking for one!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darren Rowse&#39;s ProBlogger.net Bought and Acquired by Google</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/darren-rowses-problogger.net-bought-and-acquired-by-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/darren-rowses-problogger.net-bought-and-acquired-by-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much of a shock as this comes, Darren Rowse has actually sold ProBlogger. In an official press release held on the blog, Darren announces Google had offered to buy the blog and add it to their Blogger line of applications, to which Darren had rightfully accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Google Buzz is Gaining Many Early Followers</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-google-buzz-is-gaining-many-early-followers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/how-google-buzz-is-gaining-many-early-followers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Google Buzz launched a few months ago, it has had some very impressive early adopters. Mashable and TechCrunch have been the first of many larger blogs to jump on board, with many smaller blogs following suit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Mashable so Quick to Promote Google Buzz?</title>
      <link>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.carnaghan.com/why-is-mashable-so-quick-to-promote-google-buzz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mashable is one huge blog, a very large competitor to Inside the Webb and what I wish we could be someday! They run some amazing articles about social networking, social media, tech news, and everything internet related. They usually have articles hitting the front page of Digg and Delicious, gaining well into 1500+ ReTweets and tons of Stumbles: bottom line, their blog is huge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
